<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="file:///C|/Program%20Files/SoftQuad/XMetaL%202/display/ead.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead relatedencoding="MARC21"> 
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" audience="internal" id="a0" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" countryencoding="iso3166-1" repositoryencoding="iso15511"> 
	 <eadid encodinganalog="852$a" countrycode="US" mainagencycode="Tx">urn:taro:tslac.70002</eadid> 
	 <filedesc> 
		<titlestmt> 
		  <titleproper>Texas Inaugural Committee:</titleproper> 
		  <subtitle>An Inventory of Inaugural Committee Perry-Dewhurst Inaugural
			 Records at the Texas State Archives, 
			 <date type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</date>
			 </subtitle> 
		  <author>Finding aid by Rebecca Romanchuk</author> 
		  <sponsor>This EAD finding aid was created in cooperation with Texas
			 Archival Resources Online.</sponsor> 
		</titlestmt> 
		<publicationstmt> 
		  <publisher>Texas State Library and Archives Commission 
			 <extptr href="defaultstar.gif" show="embed" actuate="onload"/></publisher> 
		  <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian">June 2005</date>
		  
		</publicationstmt> 
	 </filedesc> 
	 <profiledesc> 
		<creation>Finding aid encoded by Rebecca Romanchuk in EAD Version 2002 as
		  part of the TARO project, 
		  <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian">April 2005.</date></creation> 
		<langusage>Finding aid written in <language
langcode="eng">English.</language></langusage> <descrules>Description based on 
		<emph render="italic">DACS</emph>.</descrules>
	 </profiledesc><!-- Add a new change for each major revision of the finding aid, include what was done, who did it, and when -->
	 <revisiondesc> 
		<change> 
		  <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian"><?xm-replace_text {date}?></date> 
		  <item><?xm-replace_text {item}?></item> 
		</change> 
	 </revisiondesc> 
  </eadheader> 
  <archdesc level="subgrp" type="inventory" audience="external"> <?xm-replace_text (be sure level attribute is correct)?>
	 <did id="a1"> 
		<head>Overview</head> 
		<repository> 
		  
<extref href="http://www.tsl.state.tx.us/arc/index.html" show="new"
 actuate="onrequest">Texas State Archives</extref></repository> 
		<origination label="Creator:"> 
		  <corpname encodinganalog="110" source="lcnaf">Texas Inaugural
			 Committee.</corpname></origination> 
		<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245">Inaugural Committee
		  Perry-Dewhurst inaugural records</unittitle> 
		
<unitdate label="Dates:" encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" era="ce"
 calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate> 
		<abstract label="Abstract:" encodinganalog="520$a">Records of the 2003
		  Texas Inaugural Committee document its organization and planning of the
		  inaugural ceremony for Governor Rick Perry and Lieutenant Governor David
		  Dewhurst on January 21, 2003 and other celebratory events occurring both
before
		  and after the swearing-in of the chief executive of the state and the
		  lieutenant governor, who also serves as Constitutional President of the
Texas
		  Senate. Types of records include minutes, agenda, meeting materials,
		  organizational charts, schedules, lists of duties and responsibilities,
		  invitations, tickets, badges, programs, oaths, plans, timelines, memoranda,
		  estimates, photographs, and press releases dating 2002-2003.</abstract> 
		<langmaterial label="Language:">These materials are written in 
		<language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
		<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300$a">0.67 cubic
		  ft.</physdesc> 
	 </did> 
	 <accessrestrict id="a14" encodinganalog="506"> 
		<head>Restrictions on Access</head> 
		<p>None.</p> 
	 </accessrestrict> 
	 <userestrict id="a15" encodinganalog="540"> 
		<head>Restrictions on Use</head> 
		<p>Most records created by Texas state agencies are not copyrighted and
		  may be freely used in any way. State records also include materials
received
		  by, not created by, state agencies. Copyright remains with the creator. The
		  researcher is responsible for complying with U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17
		  U.S.C.).</p> 
	 </userestrict> <phystech encodinganalog="340"> 
	 <head>Technical Requirements</head> 
	 <p>Researchers are required to wear gloves provided by the Archives when
		reviewing photographic materials. Researchers wishing to access digital
		versions of these records on CD-ROM must contact the Archives' Preservation
		Officer to obtain the necessary equipment.</p></phystech> 
	 <bioghist id="a2" encodinganalog="545"> 
		<head>Agency History</head> 
		<p>The functions and activities of the Texas Inaugural Committee are
		  governed by Section 401 of the Texas Government Code. No later than the
tenth
		  day after the date of each election for governor and lieutenant governor,
the
		  secretary of state issues a proclamation stating who, in the secretary's
		  opinion, based on the best information available, are the governor-elect
and
		  lieutenant governor-elect. The secretary of state then delivers certified
		  copies of the proclamation to the individuals named in the proclamation.
The
		  governor-elect and lieutenant governor-elect then each file with the
secretary
		  of state a signed instrument. In that instrument, the governor-elect
designates
		  one individual to serve as chair of the inaugural committee and one
individual
		  to serve as a cochair of the committee; the lieutenant governor-elect
		  designates one individual to serve as a cochair of the committee. The
		  governor-elect and lieutenant governor-elect may appoint other members to
the
		  inaugural committee as they consider necessary.</p>
		<p>After the committee members have been appointed, they convene at a
		  time and place designated by the chair, take the constitutional oath of
office,
		  and hold an organizational meeting to make arrangements necessary for
		  conducting ceremonies and events to observe the inauguration of the
governor
		  and lieutenant governor. The committee may hold subsequent meetings at
times it
		  determines or on the call of the chairman, who, when present, presides at
the
		  meetings. The committee may adopt rules to govern its proceedings.
Committee
		  members serve without compensation but may be reimbursed for actual and
		  necessary expenses incurred in the performance of committee duties as
provided
		  by legislative appropriation. The committee may employ staff or engage the
		  services of consultants to assist in its work, and may request the
cooperation
		  of an agency or official of state or local government.</p>
		<p>The inaugural fund is a special fund in the state treasury to be used
		  only for costs related to the inauguration. The comptroller credits to the
		  inaugural fund a pro-rata share of the interest received from the deposit
of
		  state funds as if the inaugural fund were a constitutional fund. A person
may
		  contribute funds, services, or other things of value to pay the expenses of
or
		  otherwise provide for an inauguration; such contributions may be made to
the
		  inaugural committee or secretary of state. The contribution is not a
political
		  contribution for purposes of state law regulating political contributions
or
		  prohibiting a contribution by a corporation or labor organization. If the
		  secretary of state receives a contribution while the inaugural committee
		  exists, the secretary of state delivers it to the committee. If the
secretary
		  of state receives a contribution at any other time, then s/he transmits it
to
		  the comptroller, who deposits it in the state treasury to the credit of the
		  inaugural fund. The secretary of state retains the receipt for the
contribution
		  in his/her office for at least four years and maintains an index of the
		  receipts, arranged alphabetically by contributor, showing the date of the
		  contribution, the name and mailing address of the contributor, and the
amount
		  of each contribution. The index and receipts are public information.</p>
		<p>Money appropriated from the inaugural fund may be used for: printing;
		  the employment of staff; the lease of office space and payment of utility
		  expenses; professional and consultant fees; postage, telephone, and
telegraph
		  expenses; payment of expenses incurred by committee members; and any other
		  public purpose reasonably related to conducting inaugural ceremonies and
		  related events, including expenses of raising funds. Contributions received
by
		  the committee and not deposited in the state treasury may be expended for
any
		  purpose the committee considers appropriate. A voucher for an expenditure
from
		  the inaugural fund must be approved in writing by the chairman. The
committee
		  maintains a record of each expenditure of nonappropriated funds containing
the
		  following information about each expenditure: the name and address of the
		  entity to whom the expenditure was paid, the amount, the date, and the
purpose
		  of the expenditure.</p>
		<p>No later than June 30 of the year in which the inauguration is held,
		  the committee files with the secretary of state a final report verified by
a
		  certified public accountant that shows: the total amount of contributions
		  received by the committee, including contributions paid to the secretary of
		  state during the committee's existence; the total amount of expenditures
made
		  by the committee from nonappropriated funds; and the total amount of
		  nonappropriated funds remaining in the committee's possession. This report
is
		  public information. On the day the committee files the final report, the
		  committee must deliver all unexpended nonappropriated funds it possesses to
the
		  comptroller. The comptroller deposits the funds in the state treasury to
the
		  credit of the inaugural fund. When the secretary of state determines that
the
		  committee has complied with these requirements, the secretary issues a
		  proclamation to that effect. The committee is dissolved on the day after
the
		  date the proclamation is issued.</p>
		<p>The 2003 inauguration was funded entirely through corporate and
		  private underwriters and ticket sales, using none of the $100,000 allowed
by
		  state statute to cover inaugural expenses.</p>
		<p>The 2003 Texas Inaugural Committee was chaired by Pamela Willeford,
		  with co-chairs James Huffines and Drayton McLane. Scott Caven and Colleen
		  McHugh were the finance co-chairs. The theme for the inaugural festivities
for
		  Governor Rick Perry and Lieutenant Governor David Dewhurst was 
		  <emph render="doublequote">One Star. One Future. One Texas.</emph></p> 
		<p>(Sources include: V.T.C.A., Government Code, Section 401.001-011;
		  press releases found within these records.)</p>
	 </bioghist> 
	 <scopecontent id="a3" encodinganalog="520"> 
		<head>Scope and Contents of the Records</head> 
		<p>Records of the 2003 Texas Inaugural Committee document its
		  organization and planning of the inaugural ceremony for Governor Rick Perry
and
		  Lieutenant Governor David Dewhurst on January 21, 2003 and other
celebratory
		  events occurring both before and after the swearing-in of the chief
executive
		  of the state and the lieutenant governor, who also serves as Constitutional
		  President of the Texas Senate. Types of records include minutes, agenda,
		  meeting materials, organizational charts, schedules, lists of duties and
		  responsibilities, invitations, tickets, badges, programs, oaths, plans,
		  timelines, memoranda, estimates, photographs, and press releases, dating
		  2002-2003.</p> 
		<p>The first series, <emph render="italic">Planning documents</emph>,
		  comprises records created by the Committee in organizing the inauguration,
with
		  the exception of photographs. Appointments to the Committee by the
		  governor-elect and lieutenant governor-elect are included in the records,
as is
		  a printed version of the Committee's website which offered event
information to
		  the press and public. Planning contributions from the Texas Legislative
Council
		  are found in the swearing-in material. In addition to the inauguration
itself,
		  events for inaugural sponsors, participants' guests, and the public
included a
		  Texas Celebration at the Bob Bullock Texas State History Museum, a morning
		  prayer service on the day of the inauguration, a barbecue on the Capitol
south
		  lawn, an inaugural parade on Congress Avenue, and the inaugural ball at the
		  Austin Convention Center. Follow-up materials contain the only Committee
		  meeting minutes in these records and look ahead to reserving accommodations
for
		  the 2007 inauguration.</p>
		<p>The second series, <emph render="italic">Photographs</emph>, consists
		  of 354 digital photographs on CD-ROM, the majority of which show only
set-up
		  and arrangements prior to the inaugural events taking place; and color
4"x6"
		  prints made of 78 of those digital photographs which were taken during the
		  events and which show key participants, including Governor Perry and his
family
		  and Lieutenant Governor Dewhurst. Selection of digital photographs to be
		  printed was made by State Archives staff.</p>
	 </scopecontent> 
	 <arrangement id="a5" encodinganalog="351"> 
		<head>Organization of the Records</head> 
		<p>The records have been organized by State Archives staff into two
		  series:</p> 
		<list> 
		  <item>Planning documents, 2002-2003, 0.47 cubic ft.</item>
		  <item>Photographs, 2003, 0.2 cubic ft. (78 color prints and 1
			 CD-ROM)</item> 
		</list> 
	 </arrangement> 
	 <controlaccess id="a12"> 
		<head>Index Terms</head> 
		<p><emph render="italic">The terms listed here were used to catalog the
		  records. The terms can be used to find similar or related
records.</emph></p> 
		<controlaccess> 
		  <head>Personal Names:</head> 
		  <persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="600">Dewhurst, David, 1945-
			 --Inauguration--2003.</persname> 
		  <persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="600">Perry, Rick, 1950-
			 --Inauguration--2003.</persname>
		</controlaccess> 
		<controlaccess> 
		  <head>Subjects:</head> 
		  <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Governors--Texas.</subject>
		  
		</controlaccess> 
		<controlaccess> 
		  <head>Document Types:</head> 
		  <genreform source="aat"
 encodinganalog="655">Minutes--Texas--Governors--Inaugurations--2003.</genreform>
		  
		  <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Organizational
			 charts--Texas--Governors--Inaugurations--2002-2003</genreform>
		  <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Schedules (time
			 plans)--Texas--Governors--Inaugurations--2002-2003</genreform>
		  <genreform source="aat"
 encodinganalog="655">Lists--Texas--Governors--Inaugurations--2002-2003</genreform>
		  <genreform source="aat"
 encodinganalog="655">Invitations--Texas--Governors--Inaugurations--2002-2003</genreform>
		  <genreform source="aat"
 encodinganalog="655">Tickets--Texas--Governors--Inaugurations--2002-2003</genreform>
		  <genreform source="aat"
 encodinganalog="655">Programs--Texas--Governors--Inaugurations--2002-2003</genreform>
		  <genreform source="aat"
 encodinganalog="655">Oaths--Texas--Governors--Inaugurations--2002-2003</genreform>
		  <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Press
			 releases--Texas--Governors--Inaugurations--2002-2003</genreform>
		  <genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Plans
			 (drawings)--Texas--Governors--Inaugurations--2002-2003</genreform>
		  <genreform source="aat"
 encodinganalog="655">Photographs--Texas--Governors--Inaugurations--2003</genreform>
		</controlaccess> 
		<controlaccess> 
		  <head>Functions:</head> 
		  <function source="aat" encodinganalog="657">Planning inaugural
			 activities.</function> 
		</controlaccess> 
	 </controlaccess> 
	 <relatedmaterial id="a6"> 
		<head>Related Material</head> 
		<p><emph render="italic">The following materials are offered as possible
		  sources of further information on the agencies and subjects covered by the
		  records. The listing is not exhaustive.</emph></p> 
		<relatedmaterial> 
		  <p> 
			 <repository><emph render="bold">Texas State
				Archives</emph></repository></p> 
		  
<archref href="http://www.lib.utexas.edu/taro/tslac/10135/tsl-10135.html"
 show="new" actuate="onrequest">Texas Inaugural Committee, Bush-Perry inaugural
records,
			 1934-1999 (bulk 1998-1999), 0.47 cubic ft.</archref>
		  
<archref href="http://www.lib.utexas.edu/taro/tslac/10192/tsl-10192.html"
 show="new" actuate="onrequest">Texas Inaugural Committee, Bush-Bullock
inaugural records,
			 1994-1995, 0.47 cubic ft.</archref>
		  
<archref href="http://www.lib.utexas.edu/taro/tslac/10191/tsl-10191.html"
 show="new" actuate="onrequest">Texas Inaugural Committee, Richards-Bullock
inauguration
			 records, 1932, 1963-1991, 3.24 cubic ft</archref>
		  
<archref href="http://www.lib.utexas.edu/taro/tslac/70003/tsl-70003.html"
 show="new" actuate="onrequest">Texas Legislative Council, Legislative Council
inaugural
			 planning documents and other material, 1955-2003, 0.24 cubic ft.</archref>
		  <archref>Viriginia Whitten Papers, 1973-1994, 0.94 cubic ft.</archref>
		  <archref>Texas Secretary of State, Inaugural fund filings, 1979-1983,
			 1986-1987, 1990-1991, 0.24 cubic ft.</archref> 
		</relatedmaterial> 
	 </relatedmaterial> <descgrp> 
	 <prefercite id="a18" encodinganalog="524"> 
		<head>Preferred Citation</head> 
		<p>(Identify the item and cite the series), Texas Inaugural Committee
		  Perry-Dewhurst inaugural records. Archives and Information Services
Division,
		  Texas State Library and Archives Commission.</p> 
	 </prefercite> 
	 <processinfo id="a20" encodinganalog="583"> 
		<head>Processing Information</head> 
		<p>Rebecca Romanchuk, March 2005</p> 
	 </processinfo> 
	 <acqinfo id="a19" encodinganalog="541"> 
		<head>Accession Information</head> 
		<p>Accession number: 2003/177</p> 
		<p>These records were transferred to the Archives and Information
		  Services Division of the Texas State Library and Archives Commission by the
		  Texas Inaugural Committee on July 2, 2003.</p> 
	 </acqinfo> 
	 <altformavail id="a17" encodinganalog="530"> 
		<head>Other Formats for the Records</head> 
		<p>All of the documents in the first series, <emph render="italic">Planning
documents</emph>, also exist as digital files on
		  CD-ROM, in Windows 2000 Microsoft Word, Excel, or PowerPoint formats; or in
		  Adobe Acrobat 6.0. All 354 photographs in the second series, 
		  <emph render="italic">Photographs</emph>, exist as JPEG digital image files
on
		  CD-ROM.</p> 
	 </altformavail> </descgrp> 
	 <dsc type="combined" id="a23"> 
		<head>Detailed Description of the Records</head> 
		<c01 level="series" id="ser1"> 
		  <did> 
			 <unittitle>Planning documents, 
				<unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian" type="inclusive">2002-2003,
				  </unitdate> </unittitle> 
			 <physdesc>0.47 cubic ft.</physdesc> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent encodinganalog="520"> 
			 <p>In planning the 2003 inaugural events, the Texas Inaugural
				Committee conducted research into past Texas inaugurals and kept records to
				document the committee members' decisions on each aspect of the events,
				including the printing of invitations and credentials, selection of vendors,
				detailed timelines, transportation arrangements, and financial expenditures.
				Types of records include minutes, agenda, meeting materials, organizational
				charts, schedules, lists of duties and responsibilities, invitations, tickets,
				badges, programs, oaths, plans, timelines, memoranda, estimates, photographs,
				and press releases, dating 2002-2003. The committee's publicity efforts are
				shown through its press releases and its public website, which was printed in
				its entirety. Planning contributions from the Texas Legislative Council are
				found in the swearing-in material. Plans made by the committee for the 2007
				inaugural include contracts for hotel and convention center space and
				services.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		  <arrangement encodinganalog="351"> 
			 <head>Arrangement</head> 
			 <p>These records are listed in their original order as received from
				the agency.</p> 
		  </arrangement>
		  <prefercite encodinganalog="524"> 
			 <head>Preferred Citation</head> 
			 <p>(Identify the item), Planning documents, Texas Inaugural Committee
				Perry-Dewhurst inaugural records. Archives and Information Services Division,
				Texas State Library and Archives Commission.</p> 
		  </prefercite> 
		  <accessrestrict>
			 <head>Restrictions on Access</head> 
			 <p>None.</p> 
		  </accessrestrict>
		  <userestrict>
			 <head>Restrictions on Use</head> 
			 <p>Most records created by Texas state agencies are not copyrighted
				and may be freely used in any way. State records also include materials
				received by, not created by, state agencies. Copyright remains with the
				creator. The researcher is responsible for complying with U.S. Copyright Law
				(Title 17 U.S.C.).</p> 
		  </userestrict><phystech encodinganalog="340"> 
		  <head>Technical Requirements</head> 
		  <p>Researchers wishing to access digital versions of these records on
			 CD-ROM must contact the Archives' Preservation Officer to obtain the necessary
			 equipment.</p></phystech> 
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Introduction, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Background research, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02> 
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Memos and agreements, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02> 
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Committee appointments and meetings, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02> 
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Printing, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02> 
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Staff, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Credentialing, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Timelines, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02> 
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Governor's Mansion, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Texas Celebration, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Prayer Service, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02> 
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Swearing-in, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Barbecue, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Luncheon, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Program, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Parade, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Ball, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Elected officials, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Friends and family, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Finance, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Communications (including press releases and Committee
				  website), 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02> 
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Commemoratives, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Transportation, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Baskets, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Invitations and ticketing, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-1</container> 
				<unittitle>Follow-up, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">CD/DVD Box 1</container> 
				<unittitle>Inaugural committee planning documents, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2002-2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
			 </did> 
		  </c02> 
		</c01> 
		<c01 level="series" id="ser2"> 
		  <did> 
			 <unittitle>Photographs, 
				<unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian" type="inclusive">2003,
				  </unitdate> </unittitle> 
			 <physdesc><extent>0.2 cubic ft. </extent><extent>(78 </extent>
				<physfacet> color prints </physfacet>and <extent>1 </extent>CD-ROM)</physdesc> 
		  </did> 
		  <scopecontent encodinganalog="520"> 
			 <p>The Texas Inaugural Committee documented the 2003 inaugural events
				through 354 digital photographs saved to a CD-ROM to record the appearance of
				their arrangements for this state occasion attended by thousands of people. The
				majority of these digital photographs, taken before and during the inaugural
				ceremony, barbecue, parade, and ball show only set-up and arrangements prior to
				the events taking place. About one-fourth of the photographs were taken during
				the events as they occurred and show key participants, including Governor Perry
				and his family and Lieutenant Governor Dewhurst; color 4"x6" prints were made
				of 78 of these photographs, selected by State Archives staff. If known, names
				of individuals and organizations appearing in the photograph are noted on the
				reverse of the print.</p> 
		  </scopecontent> 
		  <arrangement encodinganalog="351"> 
			 <head>Arrangement</head> 
			 <p>The digital image files on the CD-ROM are in their original order
				as received from the agency. The selected prints made from the digital images
				are listed in order according to the chronology of the inaugural events.</p> 
		  </arrangement> 
		  <prefercite encodinganalog="524"> 
			 <head>Preferred Citation</head> 
			 <p>(Identify the item), Photographs, Texas Inaugural Committee
				Perry-Dewhurst inaugural records. Archives and Information Services Division,
				Texas State Library and Archives Commission.</p> 
		  </prefercite> 
		  <accessrestrict>
			 <head>Restrictions on Access</head> 
			 <p>None.</p> 
		  </accessrestrict>
		  <userestrict>
			 <head>Restrictions on Use</head> 
			 <p>Most records created by Texas state agencies are not copyrighted
				and may be freely used in any way. State records also include materials
				received by, not created by, state agencies. Copyright remains with the
				creator. The researcher is responsible for complying with U.S. Copyright Law
				(Title 17 U.S.C.).</p> 
		  </userestrict><phystech encodinganalog="340"> 
		  <head>Technical Requirements</head> 
		  <p>Researchers are required to wear gloves provided by the Archives
			 when reviewing photographic materials. Researchers wishing to access digital
			 versions of these records on CD-ROM must contact the Archives' Preservation
			 Officer to obtain the necessary equipment.</p></phystech> 
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">CD/DVD Box 1</container> 
				<unittitle>Inaugural swearing-in ceremony, barbecue, parade, and
				  ball photographs, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
				<physdesc><extent>[354 </extent><physfacet>digital image files on
				  CD-ROM]</physfacet></physdesc>
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-2</container> 
				<unittitle>Inaugural swearing-in ceremony photographs, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
				<physdesc><extent>[17 </extent><physfacet> color prints
				  </physfacet><dimensions>4"x6"]</dimensions></physdesc>
			 </did>
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-2</container> 
				<unittitle>Inaugural parade photographs, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
				<physdesc><extent>[44 </extent><physfacet> color prints
				  </physfacet><dimensions>4"x6"]</dimensions></physdesc>
			 </did> 
		  </c02>
		  <c02> 
			 <did> 
				<container type="Box">2003/177-2</container> 
				<unittitle>Inaugural ball photographs, 
				  <unitdate era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</unitdate></unittitle> 
				<physdesc><extent>[17 </extent><physfacet> color prints
				  </physfacet><dimensions>4"x6"]</dimensions></physdesc>
			 </did> 
		  </c02> 
		</c01></dsc> 
  </archdesc>
</ead>
