<!DOCTYPE ead SYSTEM "http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/bus/EAD/2002/dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
<eadheader audience="internal">
<eadid>ICU.SPCL.LINCOLNBROADSIDES</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Guide to the Lincoln Collection, Broadsides<date>1854-1922</date></titleproper>
<author>Finding aid prepared by SC, 2008</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher></publicationstmt>
<notestmt>
<note><p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p></note>
     <note><p><subject>Abraham Lincoln, Stephen Douglas and the Civil War</subject></p></note>
</notestmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2009</creation>
<langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>

<frontmatter audience="external">
<titlepage>
<publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
<titleproper>Guide to the Lincoln Collection, Broadsides<date>1854-1922</date></titleproper>
<author>Finding aid prepared by SC, 2008</author>
<p>© 2009 University of Chicago Library</p>
</titlepage>

</frontmatter>

<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Descriptive Summary</head>
<unittitle label="Title">Lincoln Collection. Broadsides</unittitle>
<unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1854-1922</unitdate>


<langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
<physdesc label="Size">6 linear feet (2 boxes)</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><address>
<addressline>Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
<addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
<addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
<addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
</address></repository>
<abstract label="Abstract">This collection is made up of broadsides compiled by William E. Barton. A pastor in Oak Park, Illinois, Baron published and lectured on Lincoln extensively. He also maintained connections with fellow Lincoln experts and carried out multiple research projects that delved into the many different facets of Lincoln’s life, times and family history. The Broadsides section of the William E. Barton Collection of Lincolniana contains materials relating to the social and political atmosphere of the Civil War period.</abstract>
</did>

<descgrp><head>Information on Use</head>
<accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>The collection is open for research.</p></accessrestrict>

<prefercite><head>Citation</head><p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Lincoln Collection. Broadsides, [Box #, Folder #], Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p></prefercite>
<bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Rev. William Eleazar Barton (1861-1930) The Rev. William Eleazar Barton (1861-1930) was one of the early twentieth century's most prominent writers and lecturers on the life of Abraham Lincoln. Born in Sublette, Illinois, in the same year Lincoln assumed the presidency, Barton grew up in an environment heavily influenced by reverence for Lincoln. After pursuing undergraduate studies at Berea College in Kentucky, Barton earned his divinity degree from the Oberlin Theological Seminary in 1890. He served parishes in Tennessee, Ohio, and Massachusetts before becoming the pastor of the First Congregational Church of Oak Park, Illinois, a position he held until his retirement in 1924. Four years later, Barton accepted an appointment as lecturer at Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, where he also organized and served as pastor of the Collegeside Congregational Church.
</p><p>Barton's work as a writer produced a number of denominational manuals for church organization and a series of books presenting the wisdom and parables of a character he named Safed the Sage. For the last ten years of his life, however, Barton was best known to the public as a prolific author and lecturer on Abraham Lincoln. His publications about Lincoln included The Soul of Abraham Lincoln (1920), The Paternity of Abraham Lincoln (1920), The Life of Abraham Lincoln (1925), The Great and Good Man (1927), The Women Lincoln Loved (1927), and The Lincoln of the Biographers (1930).
</p><p>In the course of compiling material for his writings and talks, Barton visited Lincoln sites in Kentucky, Indiana, and Illinois; interviewed surviving Lincoln relatives and acquaintances; and traveled as far as California and England to collect information and conduct genealogical research on the ancestry of the Lincoln family. While acquiring a large collection of books, periodicals, pamphlets, manuscripts, and ephemera related to Lincoln and the Civil War era, Barton also purchased privately or at auction historical materials amassed by other Lincoln collectors such as John E. Burton and Osborn H. Oldroyd.
</p></bioghist>
<scopecontent><head>Scope Note</head><p>This collection is made up of broadsides compiled by William E. Barton. A pastor in Oak Park, Illinois, Baron published and lectured on Lincoln extensively. He also maintained connections with fellow Lincoln experts and carried out multiple research projects that delved into the many different facets of Lincoln’s life, times and family history. 
</p><p>
</p><p>The materials housed in this collection are political and propaganda broadsides from the mid nineteenth century. This collection is organized into two series: Series I: Broadsides and Series II: Oversized. This collection has been organized in consideration of the size of materials and aimed to make the collection readily accessible to researchers. The first five subseries of Series I are mirrored in Series II. 
</p><p>
</p><p>Series I is arranged into six subseries. Subseries 1, Election of 1860, consists of broadsides from this election year. The majority of these materials serve as propaganda for the respective parties. Subseries 2, Pre-Civil War, contains circulated broadsides alluding to the social and political atmosphere of the pre-war period. Subseries 3, Civil War, contains documentation and proclamations made by statesmen and army generals which were circulated throughout the states. Subseries 4, Election of 1864, contains broadsides of the ballots and platforms of the two parties in this election. Subseries 5, Post Civil War, contains memorial materials such as posters, ribbons, and speeches commemorating Lincoln’s life and his martyrdom. Also housed under this subseries are materials associated with Lincoln’s death, for example, the playbill and advertisement of the performance at the Ford Theatre at which he was assassinated. Subseries 6, General, contains advertisements and leaves from texts associated with Lincoln’s life which were published after his death.  
</p><p>
</p><p>Series II contains oversized materials and is organized into five subseries that mirror the organization of Series I. 
</p><p>
</p></scopecontent>
<relatedmaterial><head>Related Resources</head>
     <p>The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:</p><archref><unittitle>http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html</unittitle></archref>
     </relatedmaterial>
<controlaccess><head>Subject Headings</head>
<persname>Barton, William Eleazar, 1861-1930
</persname><persname>Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865
</persname><persname>
</persname>

<subject>Collectors and collecting -- United States
</subject><subject>
</subject>
<geogname>United States – History – Civil War, 1861-1865</geogname>



</controlaccess>
</descgrp>



<dsc type="combined">
<head>INVENTORY</head>

<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series I: Broadsides</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains political broadsides from the mid nineteenth century to the post Civil War period. </p>
</scopecontent>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 1: Election of 1860</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Print: A. Lincoln and H. Hamlin, "Free Territory for a Free People", and Democratic Ticket, For President: John C. Breckinridge of Kentucky, For Vice President: Joseph Lane of Oregon, 1860</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Miscellaneous fragments, "The Abraham Lincoln Log Cabin", Fragments of portrait with Mrs. Lincoln and Robert Todd Lincoln, three unknown fragmentary materials, undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Fragments from Chas. Magnus print, "Birds Eye View of Sixth St. 			Wharf, Washington, D.C.," undated</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 2: Pre-Civil War</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Call for a Northern Convention, 1857</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Broadsides: "The Campaign Acrostic of the Alphabet" and "Estate Sale: 101 Prime Negroes, by Alonzo White", 1854</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 3: Civil War</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Broadside: Who is Responsible for the War? Who Accountable for its Horrors and Desolations?, 1861</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>Broadside: Is the War a Failure?, undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>The Polyrama of the Rebellion, undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>"Rebel Terms of Peace!", undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>The Two Roads to Peace, 1864</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle>By the President, Abraham Lincoln, A Proclamation closing certain ports, 1865</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">12</container>
<unittitle>Message from the President of the United States, Abraham Lincoln, recommending a vote of thanks from Congress for Captain Louis M. Goldsborough’s services and gallantry displayed in the attack of Roanoke Island; and excerpt from book on soldier voting laws in Rhode Island, Connecticut, New York, New Jersey, Pennsylvania, Delaware, and Ohio, 1862</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">13</container>
<unittitle>The President to Gen. McClellen, 1862</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">14</container>
<unittitle>Proclamation by Brig. Gen. W.H. Emory, 1863</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">15</container>
<unittitle>An Address to the People of the Free States by the President of the Southern Confederacy, Jefferson Davis, 1863</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">16</container>
<unittitle>Memorandum No. 57, Paymaster General's Office, concurrence of the Attorney General with Treasury office that African American soldiers are to be treated as freemen in all cases, 1865</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">17</container>
<unittitle>Circular. Headquarters, Department of the Gulf, Office of the Sequestrations Commission, 1863; Circulars from Headquarters by Maj. Gen. George B. McClellan: Army of the Potomac, Camp near Harrison's Landing, Va., 1862; Army of the Potomac, Fairfax Court House, Va., 1862; Circular from Headquarters by Maj. Gen. Comm. N.P. Banks, Department of the Gulf, New Orleans, 1863</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">18</container>
<unittitle>Army Relief Bazaar Buildings, Academy Park, Albany, N.Y., 1864</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 4: Election of 1864</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">19</container>
<unittitle>President Lincoln and General Grant on Peace and War, 1864</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">20</container>
<unittitle>The Platforms, Baltimore and Chicago, 1864; The Real Chicago Platform, As Expounded by the Democratic Orators at Chicago, 1864</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">21</container>
<unittitle>Ohio Union Presidential Ticket, (written in German), 1864; National Union Ticket for President, undated</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 5: Post Civil War</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">22</container>
<unittitle>Died, near the south-side rail road, The Southern Confederacy, satire on South’s defeat, (two copies), undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">23</container>
<unittitle>Playbill and broadsides from the night Lincoln was assassinated: The Shuber-Garrick Playbill, "She Walked in Her Sleep"; broadside, President and Mrs. Lincoln attend Theatrical Performance -- for the last time; photograph of broadside, Ford’s Theatre, This evening the Performance will be Honored with the presence of President Lincoln, undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">24</container>
<unittitle>Nation Morning Lincoln death: General Orders No. 3, Headquarters District of Alexandria, and 9th Army Corp. and General Orders No. 14, Headquarters Northern Division of Louisiana, 1865</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">25</container>
<unittitle>Proclamation by the Governor, Algernon S. Paddock, (Mourning Lincoln’s death); Treasury Department Notification, 1865</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">26</container>
<unittitle>Funerary Memoranda: To the Memory of Abraham Lincoln; In Memory of Abraham Lincoln; The Home  Tomb of President Lincoln, undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">27</container>
<unittitle>Order of service bulletins: Funeral Service in the City Hall, Portland; Memorial Services, City of Boston; Burial of Abraham Lincoln, Town Hall, Foxboro, 1865</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">28</container>
<unittitle>Obsequies of President Lincoln, order of funeral procession, (two copies); Headquarters Department of the East: Funeral services of Abraham Lincoln, 1865</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">29</container>
<unittitle>Funeral commemoration ribbons of Abraham Lincoln: "We Mourn</unittitle>
<note><list>
<item>A Father Slain", "The Late Lamented President Lincoln", "The Martyr President", undated</item>
</list></note></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">30</container>
<unittitle>Emancipation Proclamation ribbon, post Lincoln assassination in support of the Emancipation Proclamation, undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">31</container>
<unittitle>Stamps, 1865</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">32</container>
<unittitle>Lincoln monument: Certification of Mary E. Sterner’s contribution and membership of The Lincoln Monument Association, 1865; "National Lincoln Monument, Springfield, Illinois", 1869; 67th Congress, 2nd Session: H.J. Res. 127, Joint Resolution to erect the statue of Abraham Lincoln upon its original site, and S. Res. 291, Resolution accepting the invitation to attend the ceremonies at the dedication of the Lincoln Memorial, 1922</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">33</container>
<unittitle>Fremont Ticket, (four copies), undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">34</container>
<unittitle>By the President of the United States of America, Andrew Johnson; A Proclamation removing all restrictions on trade, by admitting articles hitherto declared contraband of war, 1865</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">35</container>
<unittitle>Journal, Extra, The Atlantic Telegraph, 1858</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">36</container>
<unittitle>U.S. Senate, Impeachment of the President, ticket, (three copies), 1868</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 6: General</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">37</container>
<unittitle>Book description and press critique of "The Great National Work, Lincoln  Slavery". The History of Abraham Lincoln and the Overthrow of Slavery; Theatre Ticket, Madison Square Theatre: Walt Whitman on Abraham Lincoln, undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">38</container>
<unittitle>"The Original Lincoln Log Cabin" and "The Bibliographer", undated</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>

</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series II: Oversize</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains oversized political broadsides from the mid nineteenth century to the post Civil War period. </p>
</scopecontent>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 1: Election of 1860</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Kentucky Campaign -- Extra. Great Combined Circus and Menagerie, undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Roll of the Republican National Convention, May 16, 1860</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 2: Pre-Civil War </unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Broadside: "Some Account of some of the bloody deeds of 				General Jackson," undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Supplement to the Weekly Illinois State Journal, containing an 			address from President Buchanan, 1860</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Charles Magnus, "Narrative of Kilpatrick’s Cavalry Expedition," 			1864</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 3: Civil War</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>"True Democracy!: Eloquent Extracts," 1863; A Call to Arms, 1864</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>To Working Men, (two copies), 1864</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>"Epitaph. Here lie the mutilated and disjointed remains of the 			noblest form of government," undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>"Union Broadside No. 2: What the Copperheads and their Southern 		Friends Say," undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>"A Traitor’s Peace (The Degrading Compromise): That the Northern Copperhead 	Leaders would force upon the country" (multiple copies), undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle>Lyric sheet for Obadiah Wheelock's "Our Country Redeemed!" 			1865</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">12</container>
<unittitle>Playbill for "The Libby Prison Minstrels," 1863</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">13</container>
<unittitle>Battles during the Great American Rebellion, 1861-1862</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">14</container>
<unittitle>"Magnus’ Historical War Map: One Hundred and Fifty Miles Around Richmond," undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">15</container>
<unittitle>"What the Administration has done: Map Showing Progress of the</unittitle>
<note><list>
<item>      National Armies," undated</item>
</list></note></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">16</container>
<unittitle>Copies of the Emancipation Proclamation (negative photostats), 		1863; The Original Manuscript of President Lincoln's Proclamation,</unittitle>
<note><list>
<item>of July 25, 1862, undated; By the President, Abraham Lincoln: Emancipation Proclamation, undated</item>
</list></note></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">17</container>
<unittitle>"Governor John Andrew: Governor of Massachusetts, A Proclamation," 1863</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">18</container>
<unittitle>"The Great Union Speech of Hon. Alexander Stephens," undated</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 4: Election of 1864</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">19</container>
<unittitle>Broadside: "Elect Lincoln: Universal Anarchy, and Ultimate Ruin/Elect M’Clellan: In an Honorable, Permanent and Happy Peace", undated</unittitle>
<note><list>
<item>Subseries 5: Post-Civil War</item>
</list></note></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">20</container>
<unittitle>President Lincoln’s Farewell Address to His Neighbors: Springfield,</unittitle>
<note><list>
<item>      Illinois, undated</item>
</list></note></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">21</container>
<unittitle>Memorial announcement: To the Memory of Abraham Lincoln (reproduction), undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">22</container>
<unittitle>Memorial portraits of Lincoln: "Fallen, But Enshrined",  "Tho’ Dead, He Liveth", "He Still Lives", "We Mourn Our Loved and Martyred Guide", "We Mourn Our Nation’s Loss", undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">23</container>
<unittitle>Reward poster: $100,000 Reward! The Murderer of our late beloved President, Abraham Lincoln, 1865</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">24</container>
<unittitle>"The Cost of a Rebel Peace", undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">25</container>
<unittitle>"Democrats Rally!" undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">26</container>
<unittitle>Announcement Poster: "Fremont Meeting", 1856</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">27</container>
<unittitle>"The Great Impeachment Trial of President Johnson: The Only Full and Impartial Report," undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">28</container>
<unittitle>Announcement: Odd-Fellow Hall, J.H. Surratt lecture, undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">29</container>
<unittitle>Salt River News Extra, 1867</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">30</container>
<unittitle>"Headquarters Delegations from 1st, 2nd, 3rd. 4th, 5th, 6th and 7th Senatorial Districts," authored by Stephen A. Douglas, 1880</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc></ead>
