<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../EssentialFiles/ead.dtd">
<ead relatedencoding="marc21">
<eadheader audience="internal" langencoding="ISO639-2b">
<eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="TxArU" encodinganalog="852$a">urn:taro:utarl.02031</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Atchison, Topeka, and Santa Fe Railway Company Records:</titleproper>
<subtitle>A Guide</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Brenda S. McClurkin</author></titlestmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by Brenda S. McClurkin, <date normal="20110523">May 23, 2011</date>.</creation>
<langusage>Finding aid written in <language>English</language>.</langusage>
</profiledesc>
<revisiondesc><change><date normal="20110707">July 7, 2011</date><item>Encoding updated by Brenda S. McClurkin</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader>
<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Descriptive Summary</head>
<origination label="Creator:">
<corpname encodinganalog="110$a" source="lcnaf">Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company.</corpname>
</origination>
<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company Records</unittitle>
<unitdate label="Inclusive Dates:" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" normal="[1885/1985]">[1885-1985]</unitdate>
<abstract label="Abstract:">The Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company (ATSF) was founded by Cyrus K. Holiday in Kansas in 1859.  By 1888 the railroad stretched from Chicago to the West Coast and was seeking to tap Texas and Gulf Coast markets.  The ATSF expanded into these markets by purchasing the ten railroads: Beaumont Wharf and Terminal Company; Cane Belt Railroad; Concho, San Saba and Llano Valley Railroad; Gulf and Interstate Railway; Gulf, Beaumont and Great Northern Railroad; Gulf, Beaumont and Kansas City Railway; Jasper and Eastern Railroad; Port Bolivar Iron Ore Railroad; Texas and Gulf Railway; and the Gulf, Colorado and Santa Fe Railway.  This collection is comprised  of mixed deed records, oil and gas leases,  correspondence, standard plan books, manuals, and maps.</abstract><unitid label="Identification:">Unprocessed mss. 2011-47</unitid><physdesc label="Extent:" encodinganalog="300$a">9 boxes (11.25 linear ft.)</physdesc>
<langmaterial label="Language:" encodinganalog="546">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a"> <extref href="http://library.uta.edu/spco/" show="new" actuate="onrequest"> <corpname encodinganalog="852$a"> <subarea>Special Collections,</subarea> The University of Texas at Arlington Library </corpname> </extref> </repository>	
</did>
<bioghist encodinganalog="545$a"><head>Historical Note</head><p> The Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company (ATSF) was founded by Cyrus K. Holiday in Kansas in 1859.  By 1888 the railroad stretched from Chicago to the West Coast and was seeking to tap Texas and Gulf Coast markets.  The ATSF expanded into these markets by purchasing the ten railroads: Beaumont Wharf and Terminal Company; Cane Belt Railroad; Concho, San Saba and Llano Valley Railroad; Gulf and Interstate Railway; Gulf, Beaumont and Great Northern Railroad; Gulf, Beaumont and Kansas City Railway; Jasper and Eastern Railroad; Port Bolivar Iron Ore Railroad; Texas and Gulf Railway; and the Gulf, Colorado and Santa Fe Railway.</p></bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520$a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Real estate records, correspondence, printed materials, maps.  This collection is comprised  of mixed deed records, oil and gas leases,  correspondence, standard plan books, manuals, and maps.</p></scopecontent>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506$a"><head>Access</head><p>Open for research.</p></accessrestrict>

<custodhist encodinganalog="561$a"><head>Provenance</head><p>Gift of anonymous donor, <date type="acquisition" normal="2010" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2010</date>.</p></custodhist>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541$a"><head>Acquisition</head><p>Gift, <date type="acquisition" normal="2010" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2010</date>.  </p><p>Accessioned as number 2011-47.</p></acqinfo>










<prefercite encodinganalog="524$a"><head>Citation</head><p>Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company Records, [1885-1985], Unprocessed mss. 2011-47, Box Number, Folder Number, Special Collections, The University of Texas at Arlington Library.</p></prefercite><relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544$a"><head>Related Material</head><p><archref href="http://www.lib.utexas.edu/taro/utarl/00004/arl-00004.html" show="new" actuate="onrequest" linktype="simple">00004 </archref>  AR425: Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company Records.</p></relatedmaterial><controlaccess> 
<head>Index Terms</head> 
<p>These materials are indexed under the following headings in the catalog of The University of Texas at Arlington Library.  Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons or places should search the catalog using these headings.</p>

<controlaccess> 
<head>Organizations</head>
<corpname encodinganalog="610$ " source="lcnaf">Atchison, Topeka and Santa Fe Railway Company--Records and correspondence.</corpname></controlaccess>


<controlaccess><head>Alternate Titles</head><title encodinganalog="246$a">Historical Manuscripts Collection</title></controlaccess>
</controlaccess></archdesc>
</ead>
