<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead relatedencoding="marc21">
	<eadheader audience="internal">
		<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="TxU-TH" encodinganalog="852$a"
			>urn:taro:utexas.cah.01489</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>A Guide to the Woman's Commonwealth Archive, 1760-1991</titleproper>
			</titlestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Original EAD encoding by Megan Mummey according to TARO 2 EAD 2002 Editing
				Instructions. <date>April 2010</date></creation>
			<langusage>Finding aid written in <language>English.</language></langusage>

		</profiledesc>
		<revisiondesc>
			<change>
				<date>May 2010</date>
				<item>Revised by Megan Mummey.</item>
			</change>
		</revisiondesc>
	</eadheader>
	<archdesc type="inventory" level="collection">
		<did>
			<head>Descriptive Summary</head>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<corpname encodinganalog="110">Woman's Commonwealth</corpname>
			</origination>
			<unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Title:">Woman's Commonwealth Archive</unittitle>
			<unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245" label="Dates:">1760-1991</unitdate>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Materials are written in <language langcode="eng"
					>English.</language></langmaterial>
			<unitid label="Accession No.:">88-179; 92-204; 95-073; 97-038</unitid>
			<physdesc label="Extent:" encodinganalog="300$a">4 ft., 10 in.</physdesc>

			<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a">
				<extref href="http://www.cah.utexas.edu" show="new" actuate="onrequest">
					<corpname><subarea> Dolph Briscoe Center for American History, </subarea>The
						University of Texas at Austin</corpname></extref></repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:" encodinganalog="520$a">Correspondence, ledgers, photographs,
				journals, company records, newspaper clippings, membership lists, account books,
				legal documents, financial records, greeting cards, and miscellaneous printed
				material relating to the history, development, membership, and activities of the
				Woman’s Commonwealth and to Martha McWhirter, organization president, during its
				years in Belton, Texas, and Washington, D.C. (ca. 1860s-1920s). </abstract>

		</did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
			<head>Historical Note</head>
			<p>The Woman’s Commonwealth originated in Belton, Texas, in the 1860s, as the Belton
				Woman’s Commonwealth, a commune founded on the principles of religious
				perfectionism, celibacy, and Wesleyan sanctificationism. The Commonwealth was
				primarily composed of middle-class Protestant women. Martha McWhirter, who founded a
				Methodist woman’s study and prayer group, had a religious vision and proclaimed that
				she was sanctified and encouraged other women to seek divine revelations. Many of
				these women had to deal with controlling husbands prone to drinking and physical
				abuse. McWhirter counseled these women to complete their domestic duties, but to
				limit social and sexual interactions with their unsanctified husbands. Eventually an
				alternative communal life developed, which involved women living apart from their
				husbands and making a living by selling eggs and dairy products, doing laundry,
				working as domestic servants, and running a boarding house/hotel. The Commonwealth’s
				membership averaged around thirty people, mostly women and their children. </p>
			<p>The Belton Woman’s Commonwealth became administratively and financially independent
				by the early 1880s. Though initially the Belton community blamed Martha McWhirter
				for various separations and divorces, the Woman’s Commonwealth became more popular
				and accepted during the next two decades. In 1899 the women retired from their
				various business ventures in Belton, and purchased lands in Washington D. C. and
				Maryland. They incorporated in 1902 as the Woman’s Commonwealth of Washington. When
				Martha McWhirter died in 1904, Fannie Holtzclaw became the Commonwealth’s leader.
				The Woman’s Commonwealth endured until 1983 when their last member passed away. </p>
			<p><emph render="bold">Source: </emph>
				<emph render="italic">Handbook of Texas Online</emph>, s.v. Belton Woman’s
				Commonwealth, http://www.tshaonline.org/handbook/online/articles/BB/vib1.html
				(accessed May 19, 2010).</p>

		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
			<head>Scope and Contents</head>
			<p>Correspondence, ledgers, photographs, journals, company records, newspaper clippings,
				membership lists, account books, legal documents, financial records, greeting cards,
				and miscellaneous printed material compose the Woman’s Commonwealth Archive
				(1760-1991), which documents the history, development, membership, and activities of
				the Woman’s Commonwealth during its years in Belton, Texas, and Washington, D.C.
				(ca. 1860s-1920s). Furthermore, the archive pertains to the Commonwealth’s founder
				and first president Martha McWhirter. The collection primarily consists of
				correspondence and records, dealing with the Commonwealth’s economic situation and
				legal issues. Additionally, the collection contains Martha McWhirter’s
				correspondence and a small amount of unidentified tintypes and photographs.</p>

		</scopecontent>
		<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
			<head>Access Restrictions</head>
			<p>The collection is open for research use.</p>
		</accessrestrict>
		<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
			<head>Use Restrictions</head>
			<p>Copyright restrictions apply. Some literary rights are restricted. </p>
		</userestrict>
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Index Terms</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects (Persons)</head>
				<persname encodinganalog="600">McWhirter, Martha, 1827-1904--Archives.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="600">Holtzclaw, Fannie--Archives.</persname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects (Organizations)</head>
				<corpname encodinganalog="610">Woman's Commonwealth (Belton,
					Tex.)--Archives.</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="610">Woman's Commonwealth (Belton,
					Tex.)--History</corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects</head>
				<subject encodinganalog="650">Collective settlements--United
					States--History.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="650">Methodists--United States--History. </subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Places</head>
				<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf">Belton (Tex.)--History.</geogname>
				<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf">Washington (D.C.)</geogname>
				<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf">Mount Pleasant (Md.)</geogname>

			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
			<head>Preferred Citation</head>
			<p>Woman's Commonwealth Archive, 1760-1991, Dolph Briscoe Center for American History,
				The University of Texas at Austin.</p>
		</prefercite>
		<separatedmaterial>
			<head>Separated Material</head>
			<p>Some material has been separated to the Artifact Collection.</p>
		</separatedmaterial>
		<processinfo>
			<head>Processing Information</head>
			<p>Basic processing and cataloging of this collection was supported with funds from the National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC) for the Briscoe Center’s <emph render="doublequote">History Revealed: Bringing Collections to Light</emph> project, 2009-2011.</p>
		</processinfo>
		<dsc type="in-depth">
			<head>Detailed Description of the Papers</head>
			<c01 level="series" id="ser1">
				<did>
					<unittitle>Contact repository for inventory</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
