<?xml version="1.0" standalone="no"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead relatedencoding="marc21">
	<eadheader audience="internal">
		<eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="TxU-TH" encodinganalog="852$a"
			>urn:taro:utexas.cah.02297</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>A Guide to the Eliot Asinof Papers, [ca. 1930s-2000s]</titleproper>
			</titlestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Original EAD encoding by Laurel Rozema according to TARO 2 EAD 2002 Editing
				Instructions. <date>February 2011</date></creation>
			<langusage>Finding aid written in <language>English.</language></langusage>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<archdesc type="inventory" level="collection">
		<did>
			<head>Descriptive Summary</head>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<persname encodinganalog="100">Asinof, Eliot, 1919-2008.</persname>
			</origination>
			<unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Title:">Asinof, Eliot, papers</unittitle>
			<unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245" label="Dates:">[ca.
				1930s-2000s]</unitdate>
			<!--Modify the language of material if appropriate and update 3 letter langcode in the upper-right table. 
				Add multiple languages with most commonly used listed first, if necessary. 
				Example: <language langcode="eng">English</language> and <language langcode="spa">Spanish.</language> -->
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Materials are written in <language langcode="eng"
					>English.</language></langmaterial>
			<unitid label="Accession No.:">2009-171</unitid>
			<physdesc label="Extent:" encodinganalog="300$a">ca. 40 ft.</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:" encodinganalog="852$a">
				<extref href="http://www.cah.utexas.edu" show="new" actuate="onrequest">
					<corpname><subarea>Dolph Briscoe Center for American History, </subarea>The
						University of Texas at Austin</corpname></extref></repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:" encodinganalog="520$a">Documenting Asinof’s writing career,
				the Eliot Asinof Papers, [ca. 1930s-2000s], comprise research notes, manuscripts and
				galleys, correspondence, photographs, printed materials, publicity and promotional
				items, film treatments, interview audiotapes, and videotapes of his speeches.
			</abstract>
		</did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
			<head>Biographical Note</head>
			<p>Born in New York City to Russian-American tailor Max Asinof, writer Eliot Tager
				Asinof (1919-2008) played baseball for Lawrence High School in Cedarhurst on Long
				Island, before joining the Swarthmore College team. Following graduation, he signed
				a contract for the Philadelphia Phillies’ minor league team. During World War II,
				Asinof trained as a fighter pilot until going into the U.S. Army’s Officer
				Candidates School with the help of Detroit Tigers’ first baseman Hank Greenberg, a
				family friend. Upon graduation, Asinof was stationed for two years at the army and
				naval base on Adak Island, Alaska. Following the war, he returned to New York City,
				where he met and married actress Jocelyn Brando (1919-2005), the sister of actor
				Marlon Brando. The two eventually had a son, Martin, before divorcing in 1955.</p>
			<p>In the 1950s, Asinof began writing scripts for TV shows and fronting for writers
				blacklisted by the House Un-American Committee. Signing a petition to integrate the
				New York Yankees, Asinof soon found himself among the blacklisted screenwriters. In
				1955, he wrote Man on Spikes, a novel based on his former teammate Mickey Rutner’s
				difficulties making it into major league baseball. </p>
			<p>That same year, Asinof moved to California to write a screenplay adaptation of Man on
				Spikes, which appeared on the television show Goodyear Playhouse. A contract writer
				for Warner Brothers, Asinof began work on a movie for John Wayne, but studio head Jack
				Warner fired Asinof after he wrote a scene where Wayne’s character grieves the death
				of a friend by hitting a horse. </p>
			<p>Asinof then returned to New York City to write a TV screenplay for David Susskind
				about the Black Sox scandal, in which eight Chicago White Sox players in collusion
				with gamblers intentionally lost the 1919 World Series. When the screenplay was
				dropped, Asinof attained an advance from Putnam to turn the story into a book. He
				met with several people involved in the scandal, including White Sox outfielder
				Oscar “Happy” Felsch and boxer Abe Attell, who allegedly supplied money from
				gangster Arnold Rothstein to the players. The result, Eight Men Out, was published
				in 1963, receiving a place in Sports Illustrated’s top 50 best sports books of all
				time. John Sayles adapted the book into the 1987 film of the same name.</p>
			<p>Asinof published numerous other novels and non-fiction books, such as People v.
				Blutcher (1970); Craig and Joan (1971); The Fox is Crazy, Too (1976); Bleeding
				Between the Lines (1979); Strike Zone (1994); and Final Judgment (2008).</p>
			<p>Sources:</p>
			<p>Kisseloff, Jeff. “Bio.” Eliot Asinof. Accessed February 2, 2010.
				http://eliotasinof.com/page4/page4.html.</p>
			<p>Weber, Bruce. “Eliot Asinof, Eight Men Out Author, Is Dead at 88.” New York Times.
				June 11 and 12, 2008. </p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
			<!--This explains the collection. Include the title, dates, subjects, and material types in complete sentences.-->
			<head>Scope and Contents</head>
			<p>Documenting Asinof’s writing career, the Eliot Asinof Papers, [ca. 1930s-2000s],
				comprise research notes, manuscripts and galleys, correspondence, photographs,
				printed materials, publicity and promotional items, film treatments, interview
				audiotapes, and videotapes of his speeches. Divided by type, the collection contains
				ten series: I. Scripts; II. Galleys; III. Publicity and published material; IV.
				Treatments and Proposals; V. Correspondence; VI. Notes; VII. Manuscripts; VIII.
				Personal documents; IX. Scrapbooks; and X. Audiovisual material. Each series
				chronicles the development of Asinof’s books, screenplays, teleplays; and articles,
				including Eight Men Out; The Fox is Crazy, Too; Ten-Second Jailbreak; and
				contributions to Golf Illustrated, Newsweek, and New York Sunday Times. The
				collection also includes treatments and proposals for movies, teleplays, novels, and
				articles as well as manuscripts and notes for unpublished books, like Push Pull,
				Crash at Ndola, and Like Married. </p>
			<p>The correspondence, notes, scrapbooks, and publicity and published material series
				illustrate Asinof’s relationship with different publishers, producers, and others
				involved with the making of his works in Hollywood and New York City. Furthermore,
				the publicity and published material series and the scrapbook series shed light on
				the publication process and reviews of his books and articles as well as the release
				and reviews of his films and teleplays. The personal documents series concerns his
				financial records, royalties, a lawsuit with David Susskind, his experiences as a
				young man during the 1930s and 1940s, and his military career during World War II.
				The final series, audiovisual material, includes videotapes from Asinof’s speaking
				engagements as well as audio reels and audiocassettes of interviews with Rod Laver,
				Billy Casper, Garry Merrill, Joel Kaplan, John Sayles, and other individuals
				involved in the true-life events that formed the basis for his non-fiction books
				People v. Blutcher, Craig and Joan, and Ten-Second Jailbreak.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<arrangement>
			<head>Arrangement</head>
			<p>The papers are arranged by type into ten series:</p>
			<p><list>
					<item>I. Scripts</item>
					<item>II. Galleys</item>
					<item>III. Publicity and published material</item>
					<item>IV. Treatments and Proposals</item>
					<item>V. Correspondence</item>
					<item>VI. Notes</item>
					<item>VII. Manuscripts</item>
					<item>VIII. Personal documents</item>
					<item>IX. Scrapbooks</item>
					<item>X. Audiovisual material</item>
				</list></p>
		</arrangement>
		<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
			<!-- Select the appropriate tag(s) and delete others. You may need to modify an existing 
				description or create a new one. The SAA Glossary defines access restrictions as such:
				"Access restrictions may be defined by a period of time or by a class of individual 
				allowed or denied access. They may be designed to protect national security (classification), 
				personal privacy, or to preserve materials." -->
			<head>Access Restrictions</head>
			<p>This collection is open for research use.</p>
			<p>Use of some audio and video material by appointment only; please contact sound
				archivist for more information.</p>
			<p>The donor maintains copyright of the collection.</p>
		</accessrestrict>
		<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
			<!-- Delete field if there are no use restrictions. Select the appropriate tag(s) and delete others. 
				You may need to modify an existing description or create a new one. The SAA Glossary defines use 
				restrictions as such: "Use restrictions may limit what can be done with materials, or they may 
				place qualifications on use. For example, an individual may be allowed access to materials but 
				may not have permission or right to copy, quote, or publish those materials, or conditions may 
				be imposed on such use. In addition to legal use restrictions, such as privacy and copyright, 
				donor agreements often contain use restrictions." -->
			<head>Use Restrictions</head>
			<p>These papers are stored remotely. Advance notice required for retrieval. Contact
				repository for retrieval. </p>
		</userestrict>
		<controlaccess>
			<head>Index Terms</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects (Persons)</head>
				<persname encodinganalog="600">Asinof, Eliot, 1919-2008 -- Archives.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="600">Asinof, Eliot, 1919-2008. Eight men out.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="600">Blutcher, Laurence</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="600">Trapnell, Garrett Brok, 1938-</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="600">Kaplan, Joel David.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="600">Susskind, David, 1920-1987.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="600">Badiali, Craig, 1952-1969.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="600">Fox, Joan, 1951 or 2-1969.</persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="600">Sayles, John, 1950-</persname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects (Organizations)</head>
				<corpname encodinganalog="610">Chicago White Sox (Baseball team) --
					History.</corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects</head>
				<subject encodinganalog="650">World Series (Baseball) -- History.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="650">Sports -- United States -- History -- 20th
					century.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="650">Authors, American -- 20th century --
					Archives.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="650">Television broadcasting -- United States.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="650">Motion picture plays -- United States.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="650">World War, 1939-1945 -- United States.</subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Places</head>
				<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf">United States -- History -- 20th
					century.</geogname>
			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
			<head>Preferred Citation</head>
			<p>Eliot Asinof Papers, [ca. 1930s-2000s], Dolph Briscoe Center for American History,
				The University of Texas at Austin.</p>
		</prefercite>
		<processinfo>
			<head>Processing Information</head>
			<p>This collection contains unprocessed materials.</p>
				<p>Basic processing and cataloging of this collection was supported with funds from the National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC) for the Briscoe Center’s <emph render="doublequote">History Revealed: Bringing Collections to Light</emph> project, 2009-2011.</p>
			</processinfo>
		<dsc type="in-depth">
			<head>Detailed Description of the Papers</head>
			<c01 level="series" id="ser1">
				<did>
					<unittitle>Please contact the repository for inventory.</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
