<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- wiarchives version:2012-09-20 -->
<ead id="uw-whs-tape00552a">
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" countryencoding="iso3166-1" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="whi">uw-whs-tape00552a</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Abstract to the Oral History Interview with Floyd B. Lucia, 1975 January 15</titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Wisconsin Historical Society</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Text converted and initial EAD tagging done with an in-house template, <date type="publication" normal="2007-06">June, 2007.</date>
    </creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <unittitle label="Title">Oral History Interview with Floyd B. Lucia, <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" certainty="y" normal="1975-01-15">1975 January 15</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname>Lucia, Floyd B., 1888-</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid label="Call Number">Tape 552A</unitid>
      <physdesc label="Quantity">2 tape recordings</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <extptr entityref="whslogo" show="embed" actuate="onload" altrender="center" title="Wisconsin Historical Society logo" role="logoimage"/>
        <extref linktype="simple" href="http://digital.library.wisc.edu/1711.dl/whsead.contact">Wisconsin Historical Society, Library-Archives Division</extref>
      </repository>
      <physloc>
        <extref href="http://digital.library.wisc.edu/1711.dl/whsead.catalog?repl1=rlin+%22wihv94-a923%22" role="handle">See the catalog entry for information on possible additional materials and shelf locations.</extref>
      </physloc>
      <physloc type="locationcode" audience="internal">whi</physloc>
      <abstract>Interview conducted by Dale Treleven of the Historical Society staff with Floyd B. Lucia concerning his work in various creameries and as a fieldman for the Wisconsin Cooperative Creamery Association, Baraboo Valley District, from the mid-1920's to 1937, with information on its competition with Land O'Lakes and other creameries, its role in farm social affairs, and related matters.</abstract>
      <note>
        <p>Part of the Wisconsin Agriculturalists Oral History Project.</p>
      </note>
      <langmaterial label="Language">
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
<!-- TOP LEVEL METADATA GO HERE: -->
    <bioghist>
      <p>Floyd B. Lucia was born in Flintville, Wisconsin, on August 6, 1888. Except for brief periods attending the dairy short course at the University of Wisconsin-Madison and serving with the United States Army during World War I, Lucia from 1906 until he retired in the early 1960's worked in the dairy industry. While he was employed in creameries in Illinois and Indiana as well as Wisconsin, Lucia spent over four decades as a fieldman for the Wisconsin Cooperative Creameries Association and as the general manager of the Dried Milk Products Cooperative, Eau Claire, Wisconsin.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Interview</emph>
      </p>
      <p>I [interviewer Dale Treleven] made arrangements to interview Lucia at the urging of Melvin Sprecher, Route 3, Sauk City, Wisconsin, who believed the State Historical Society would be interested in the remembrances of an old creameryman. I taped Lucia in the living room of his apartment on January 15, 1975, while his wife sat nearby, observing the entire interview session. After nearly one and one half hours, it was apparent that Lucia was getting very tired and we decided it would be best for me to return at some mutually agreeable date in the future. Unfortunately, before I had an opportunity to hold another interview session that would have concentrated on his years with the Dried Milk Products Cooperative, Floyd Lucia died on March 17, 1976.</p>
      <p>Researchers should welcome Lucia's remembrances of his association with the state's dairy industry, observed by an individual involved in a phase other than dairy farming or retail marketing. He started doing field work at a time when Wisconsin's creameries must give more attention to quality control to compete against private butter plants as well as other cooperatives within and outside the state. Lucia, with quick wit and good humor, relates several anecdotes that help illustrate the relationship between farmers and buttermakers, buttermakers and creamery fieldmen, and fieldmen and private butter buyers. He also reminds us that the cooperative creamery was a social institution as well as an economic organization in the community.</p>
      <p>
        <emph render="bold">Abstract to the Interview</emph>
      </p>
      <p>The abstract below lists, in order of discussion, the distinct topics covered on each tape and indicates the time-marking on the user tape at which point the beginning of the particular discussion appears. These time-markings are keyed to a time announcement, heard at five-second intervals, on the second track of each tape.</p>
      <p>Thus, the researcher may listen to distinct topics without listening to all of the material on the tapes. For instance, the user who wishes to listen to the topic on Description of Creamery Operation Before 1906 should locate the place on the second track of tape one, side one, where the voice announces the 06:15 time-marking (the voice says at this point, six minutes, fifteen seconds), and at this point switch to the first track to hear the discussion. The discussion on Description of Creamery Operation Before 1906 continues until approximately 10:25 at which point discussion of the next topic (Employment after Short Course Completed) listed in the abstract begins.</p>
      <p>Notice that in most cases sentences beneath each headline explain more about the contents of the topic. For example, the sentences underneath Description of Creamery Operation Before 1906 give further details on what appears on the tape between 06:15 and 10:25.</p>
      <p>The abstract is designed to provide only a brief outline of the content of the tapes and cannot serve as a substitute for listening to them.</p>
    </scopecontent>
<!-- END TOP LEVEL METADATA -->
<!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->
    <descgrp type="admininfo">
      <head>Administrative/Restriction Information</head>
      <processinfo>
        <p>Finding aid prepared by Dale E. Trevelen, August 30, 1976.</p>
      </processinfo>
    </descgrp>
<!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
<!-- START DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
    <dsc type="in-depth">
      <head>Contents List</head>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">00:00</container>
          <unittitle>Introduction</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">01:55</container>
          <unittitle>Background and Early Connection with Dairy Industry</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Born in Flintville where his family worked in lumber. In 1906 began working in uncle's creamery in De Pere. Paid $50.00 per month. After thirteen months took Short Course in dairying at the University of Wisconsin-Madison, which cost $110.00.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">06:15</container>
          <unittitle>Description of Creamery Operation before 1906</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Farmers delivered whole milk; took skim milk back for hogs. Farmers talked, smoked or visited tavern while waiting to dump milk or pick up skim.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">10:25</container>
          <unittitle>Employment after Short Course Completed</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Various creamery jobs in Iowa and Illinois. Worked at a Kankakee, Illinois creamery, then left for Indiana to make butter for Beatrice Creamery Company.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">17:50</container>
          <unittitle>Work in Arsenal during World War I</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Drafted into Army. Because of experience with refrigeration, made gas for shells at arsenal in Maryland.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">20:25</container>
          <unittitle>Employment after World War I Ends</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Immediately rehired by Beatrice. Crew dissatisfied with lack of good cream; returned to Wisconsin to take a job with the Lafayette creamery, near Chippewa Falls.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">27:20</container>
          <unittitle>Anecdote about Soapy Butter at Lafayette Creamery</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Wife of former buttermaker washed clothes in butter vats. Chicago customers complained of soapy-flavored butter, much to the distress of the creamery's Irish patrons.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">29:55</container>
          <unittitle>Lucia Becomes Fieldman for Wisconsin Cooperative Creameries Association</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Became fieldman for District No. Two, Baraboo Valley District, Wisconsin Cooperative Creameries Association in mid-1920's.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">00:00</container>
          <unittitle>Introduction</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">00:55</container>
          <unittitle>Duties as Fieldman for Baraboo Valley District</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Got acquainted with individual buttermakers, located in thirteen different plants, to help them rather than be regarded as an inspector.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">03:20</container>
          <unittitle>Contact with Individual Farmers</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Infrequent contact because cream delivered to creamery by truck. Occasionally accompanied cream truck to talk to individual farmers.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">04:50</container>
          <unittitle>Buttermakers Urged to Produce at Least 92-Score Butter</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Buttermakers urged to make the desired 92-score butter. Could recommend dismissal of individual buttermakers if persisted in making poor quality product.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">06:50</container>
          <unittitle>Testing Milk for Butterfat Content Before and After Development of Babcock Test</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Explanation of how milk was tested before and after milk tester developed by Professor Babcock at the University of Wisconsin-Madison.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">09:50</container>
          <unittitle>More Discussion on Fieldman's Duties</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Regular circuit difficult because some creameries needed more attention than others. Most important goal; standardize quality at all factories so butter could be sold in railroad car lots.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">11:45</container>
          <unittitle>Creameries Begin Direct Sales to Chain Stores</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Butter originally sold by creameries to commission houses. After districts set up creameries began to market directly to chain stores, especially National Tea and Consumers companies. Lucia met with chain store buyers. Creamery districts did not compete against one another for sales. S. B. Cook, fieldman for District No. Four (Barron County), important in initiating chain store sales in New York as well as Chicago.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">16:25</container>
          <unittitle>Competition Between Wisconsin Cooperative Creameries and Land 0' Lakes in 1920's</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Land 0' Lakes in the 1920's tried to break up districts of Wisconsin Cooperative Creameries; succeeded in Polk County.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">21:25</container>
          <unittitle>Butter Quality Agreement Between Creameries and Chain Stores</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Gentleman's agreement that creameries produce the best butter possible for chain stores.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">24;20</container>
          <unittitle>How to Get Proper Moisture Content When Making Butter</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">24:45</container>
          <unittitle>Observation on How Some Buttermakers Cut Butterfat Test of Farmers</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Some buttermakers cut farmer's test to get an overrun.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">26:55</container>
          <unittitle>End of Part 1 of Tape 1, Side 2</unittitle>
          <note>
            <p>Tape 1, Side 2 continues with the time-markings beginning again with 00:00.</p>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">00:35</container>
          <unittitle>Lucia as Fieldman Required to Live in Rural Area</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Required to live at La Valle, but finally argued successfully that he needed to live at Reedsburg for close access to train.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">02:15</container>
          <unittitle>Location of Some Creameries in Baraboo Valley District</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Some located at Cazenovia, La Valle, Elroy. Remembers Gary Carter of Elroy as an important director, and Ed Carlson as good buttermaker.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">1/2</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">06:10</container>
          <unittitle>End of Part 2 of Tape 1, Side 2</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">2/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">01:05</container>
          <unittitle>Role of Cooperative Creamery in Community</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Sponsored many social affairs; entire family attended. Helped develop rapport and openness with patrons and their families, unlike private creameries.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">2/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">04:10</container>
          <unittitle>Effect of Great Depression on Creameries</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>In early-1930's some highbinders down there in the Baraboo Valley participated in milk strikes of 1933. Prevented delivery of milk to creameries, sometimes by threat of force. Recalls that farmers around Hillsboro rather radical.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">2/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">14:00</container>
          <unittitle>Beginning of Lucia's Involvement in Dry Milk Industry</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Roller dryer improvement meant that small creameries could utilize skim economically and efficiently. Colfax Cooperative Creamery about 1935 one of first in region to install the improved spray dryer.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <container type="othertype" label="Tape/Side">2/1</container>
          <container type="othertype" label="Time">22:05</container>
          <unittitle>Beginning of Lucia's Association with Wisconsin Dried Milk Products Cooperative in Eau Claire</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Believes a recommendation from Mrs. Lulu Mattson was main reason why he was hired as general manager of the Dried Milk Products Cooperative in 1937.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01>
        <did>
          <unittitle>End of Interview</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
<!-- END DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
  </archdesc>
</ead>
