<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!-- wiarchives version:2012-10-29 -->
<ead id="uw-whs-mss00586">
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" countryencoding="iso3166-1" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="whi">uw-whs-mss00586</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Register of the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party Records, 1962-1971</titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Wisconsin Historical Society</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Text converted and initial EAD tagging done with an in-house template, <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian" type="publication" normal="2007-09">September, 2007.</date>
    </creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <unittitle label="Title">Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party Records, <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" certainty="y" normal="1962/1971">1962-1971</unitdate></unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <corpname>Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid label="Call Number">Mss 586; Micro 788; PH 6705</unitid>
      <physdesc label="Quantity">0.4 c.f. (1 archives box), 3 reels of microfilm (35 mm), and 1 filmstrip (35 mm)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <extptr entityref="whslogo" show="embed" actuate="onload" altrender="center" title="Wisconsin Historical Society logo" role="logoimage"/>
        <extref linktype="simple" href="http://digital.library.wisc.edu/1711.dl/whsead.contact">Wisconsin Historical Society, Library-Archives Division</extref>
      </repository>
      <physloc type="locationcode" audience="internal">whi</physloc>
      <physloc>
        <extref href="http://digital.library.wisc.edu/1711.dl/whsead.catalog?repl1=rlin+%22wihv3937s-a%22" role="handle">See the catalog entry for information on possible additional materials and shelf locations.</extref>
      </physloc>
      <abstract>Records of the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party (MFDP) from 1962 to 1971. The collection consists of manuscript and microfilmed documents illustrating the organization of the party, its two challenges and subsequent law suits, its voter registration and community organizing work, and Mississippi politics in general. Included are correspondence and printed mailings, statements, and press releases; legal documents; reports and general papers; the proceedings of the Credentials Committee of the Democratic National Convention; election and registration materials; news clippings; newsletters; materials concerning related organizations; and copies of a masters' thesis and other term papers written about the MFDP by historian Leslie B. McLemore.</abstract>
      <langmaterial label="Language">
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
<!-- TOP LEVEL METADATA GO HERE: -->
    <bioghist>
      <p>The Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party (MFDP) was officially established at a mass meeting in Jackson, Mississippi on April 26, 1964. The roots of the party originated in the widespread dissatisfaction among Mississippi African Americans who were not recognized by the powerful regular Democratic Party in the state, and who were not permitted to register or to vote. During the campaign preceding the fall 1963 elections, the discontent coalesced and when an unofficial freedom ballot for governor was held, state NAACP chair Aaron Henry received 80,000 votes.</p>
      <p>In 1964, MFDP organized a statewide political structure parallel to that of the Mississippi Democratic Party. During the summer, the Freedom Democrats, in conjunction with the Council of Federated Organizations (COFO), registered over 50,000 African Americans. MFDP candidates Victoria Gray, Fannie Lou Hamer, John Cameron, and James Houston, opposed regular Democrats Senator John Stennis, and Representatives Jamie Whitten, William M. Colmer, and John Bell Williams in the Democratic primary of June 2, 1964, but were defeated.</p>
      <p>Following this defeat, and an abortive attempt to place the candidates on the ballot as independents, the MFDP initiated the first of two challenges to the regular Democratic Party. During the weeks preceding the Democratic National Convention in August, precinct meetings and county conventions were held throughout the state and delegates were selected to attend the MFDP state convention held on August 6. At the state convention, 68 delegates and alternates were chosen for the National Convention. In Atlantic City, the MFDP delegates challenged the seating of the white Mississippi delegation. Although there was a certain amount of support among state delegations partial to the MFDP challenge, the credentials sub-committee of the Democratic National Committee rejected the MFDP slate. Subsequently, on December 4, 1964, the MFDP challenged the seating of the entire Mississippi delegation to the House of Representatives, on the grounds that the election in November was illegal and unconstitutional, and the results void. The Congressional Challenge also demanded that the three MFDP representatives, Gray, Hamer, and Annie Devine, be seated in the House. This challenge was also defeated, by Congressional vote, on September 17, 1965.</p>
      <p>After these two major defeats, party members concentrated their efforts on local and statewide voter registration, demonstrations, civil rights projects, and election campaigns. A massive registration and election campaign held prior to the May 1966 special elections in Sunflower County also failed, as all African Americans and MFDP candidates were defeated. However, the following year Robert Clark was elected as Mississippi's first black representative in nearly a century. The party began to splinter in 1967-1968, and some MFDP members joined with young progressive whites to form the Loyal Democrats of Mississippi. Only in this way were some Mississippi black leaders able to gain the recognition needed to challenge the state's regular Democratic organization. By 1969 and 1970, the MFDP was virtually defunct.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent>
      <p>The records, both in paper form and on microfilm, have been arranged in two series: MISSISSIPPI FREEDOM DEMOCRATIC PARTY RECORDS; and MISSISSIPPI GENERAL POLITICS.</p>
      <p>The MISSISSIPPI FREEDOM DEMOCRATIC PARTY RECORDS include files of correspondence to and from party chairman Lawrence Guyot, and with the party's attorney, Joseph L. Rauh Jr., the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, and other groups and individuals. There is a folder of organizational papers, with platform statements of MFDP candidates, a few minutes and other documents from the formative stages of the party, and files of general papers containing printed MFDP form letters, reports, news releases, position papers, and copies of the challenges, law suits, and court documents. In addition, there are items received by party headquarters in Jackson or in Washington, D.C., some material on the 1963 freedom ballot, and a few papers regarding the Loyal Democrats of Mississippi, 1967-1968. Also present are copies of formal notices of intention to contest election results, and a copy of the partial proceedings of the Credentials Committee of the Democratic National Convention, including Fannie Lou Hamer's statement.</p>
      <p>Records of the Mississippi Summer Project and voters registration campaign of 1964 consist of an incomplete run (last names P-S) of applications to work on the project, supporting letters (which are filed immediately behind the application to which they refer), and a Current Personnel List. These projects were sponsored jointly with COFO. The Freedom Primers and other manuals were published by MFDP as part of its educational work. The Clippings file contains photocopied news clippings from Mississippi newspapers, and from major national papers, especially the <title render="italic">New York Times</title>. Within the folder pertaining to Robert Clark's election to the Mississippi House may be found news clippings, campaign documents, and a typewritten paper by David Emmons analyzing the victory. Following a court order voiding the regular election and setting a special May 1966 election in Sunflower County, the MFDP conducted a massive voter education, registration and awareness campaign. These efforts are documented in the files concerning Sunflower County, by news clippings, press releases, flyers, and other mailings. Also included are some records of the National Committee for Free Elections in Sunflower. Leslie B. McLemore's papers include a copy of his 1965 Master's thesis on the MFDP, a paper entitled Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, A Case Study of Grass Roots Politics (1969), and another titled 1967 Sunflower and Mississippi Municipal Elections (1970).</p>
      <p>The second series, MISSISSIPPI GENERAL POLITICS, contains printed reference material about state elections, voter registration statistics, state officers, politics, the Democratic Party, and similar material. The writings by McLemore and others consist mainly of notes and drafts. A file on the Young Democratic Clubs of Mississippi includes a few flyers and a report of activities.</p>
    </scopecontent>
<!-- END TOP LEVEL METADATA -->
<!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION GOES HERE: -->
    <descgrp type="admininfo">
      <head>Administrative/Restriction Information</head>
      <acqinfo>
        <p>Portions loaned for microfilming by Leslie B. McLemore, Jackson, Mississippi, 1979; loaned for copying by Joseph L. Rauh Jr., Washington, D.C., 1979; presented by the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, via Lawrence Guyot, 1967, and via Michael Morgalla, 1975; and transferred from the Social Action Vertical File. <num type="accession">M67-226, M67-459, M75-422, M79-510, M79-577</num></p>
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo>
        <p>Processed by Menzi Behrnd-Klodt, December 1979; additions processed by Susan Bertocchi, January 1982.</p>
      </processinfo>
    </descgrp>
<!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
<!-- START DESCRIPTION OF SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS-->
    <dsc type="in-depth">
      <head>Contents List</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party Records</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unitid>Mss 586</unitid>
            <unittitle>Paper Documents</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>Organizational papers, platform statements, <unitdate>1964-1966, undated</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous minutes and reports, <unitdate>1964, undated</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>Correspondence and mailings, <unitdate>1964-1966, undated</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>Key list mailings, <unitdate>1966</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>Papers and reports, <unitdate>1965-1966, undated</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>Press releases, <unitdate>1964-1966, undated</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">7</container>
              <unittitle>Public statements and speeches, <unitdate>1964-1965, undated</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">8</container>
              <unittitle>The Congressional Challenge, <unitdate>1964-1965, undated</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">9</container>
              <unittitle>Proceedings of the Democratic National Convention Credentials Committee (partial), <unitdate>1964 August 22</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">10</container>
              <unittitle>Legal briefs and memoranda, <unitdate>1964-1966</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">11</container>
              <unittitle>Formal notices of intention to contest elections, <unitdate>circa 1965</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">12</container>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous legal documents, <unitdate>1964-1965</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">13</container>
              <unittitle>Political primers and handbooks, <unitdate>circa 1965</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">14</container>
              <unittitle>Election and registration materials, <unitdate>1965-1966, undated</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">15</container>
              <unittitle>Memos, leaflets, flyers, and petitions, <unitdate>1964-1966, undated</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">16</container>
              <unittitle>Miscellaneous materials regarding Elections and Politics</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">17</container>
              <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">18</container>
              <unittitle>Mississippi Freedom Labor Union, <unitdate>1965</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box" label="Box">1</container>
              <container type="folder" label="Folder">19</container>
              <unittitle>Miscellany regarding Other Groups, <unitdate>1962-1965</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unitid>PH 6705</unitid>
              <unittitle><title render="italic">Freedom Democratic Party Challenge</title>: filmstrip, <unitdate>1964</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unitid>Micro 788</unitid>
            <unittitle>Microfilmed Documents</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="reel" label="Reel">1</container>
              <container type="segment" label="Segment">1</container>
              <unittitle>Correspondence, <unitdate>1964-1965</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>General Papers</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <container type="reel" label="Reel">1</container>
                <container type="segment" label="Segment">2</container>
                <unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1963-1965</unitdate>
                </unittitle>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <container type="reel" label="Reel">2</container>
                <container type="segment" label="Segment">2</container>
                <unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1965-1971</unitdate>
                </unittitle>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="reel" label="Reel">2</container>
              <container type="segment" label="Segment">3</container>
              <unittitle>Mississippi Summer Project and Voters Registration, <unitdate>1964</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="reel" label="Reel">2</container>
              <container type="segment" label="Segment">4</container>
              <unittitle>Freedom primers and other manuals, <unitdate>circa 1965, 1967</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <container type="reel" label="Reel">2</container>
                <container type="segment" label="Segment">5</container>
                <unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1964-1968</unitdate>
                </unittitle>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
                <container type="segment" label="Segment">5</container>
                <unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1968-1970</unitdate>
                </unittitle>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
              <container type="segment" label="Segment">6</container>
              <unittitle>Clark, Robert, Election to Mississippi House of Representatives, <unitdate>1967-1968</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
              <container type="segment" label="Segment">7</container>
              <unittitle>Flyers of other candidates, <unitdate>1966-1967</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
              <container type="segment" label="Segment">8</container>
              <unittitle>Sunflower County elections, <unitdate>1965-1967</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
              <container type="segment" label="Segment">9</container>
              <unittitle>The Sunflower County Project report, <unitdate>1964-1965</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
              <container type="segment" label="Segment">10</container>
              <unittitle>McLemore, Leslie B., Master Thesis, <unitdate>1965, and Other Papers, 1969, 1970</unitdate></unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <title render="italic">MFDP News Letters</title>
              </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
                <container type="segment" label="Segment">11</container>
                <unittitle>Nos. 1, 3-6, 8-10; <unitdate>1965 March 17, April 24, June 5, July 7, 28, September, November 5, December 20</unitdate></unittitle>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
                <container type="segment" label="Segment">11</container>
                <unittitle>No. 1; <unitdate>1967 October 1</unitdate></unittitle>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
                <container type="segment" label="Segment">11</container>
                <unittitle>Volume 1?, No. 3; <unitdate>1967 November 27</unitdate></unittitle>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
                <container type="segment" label="Segment">11</container>
                <unittitle>Volume 2, Nos. 2, 4-6, 8, 9, [misnumbered]; <unitdate>1967 [undated], December 19; 1968, January 30, [undated], June 22, November 5</unitdate></unittitle>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <title render="italic">Hinds County FDP News</title>
              </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04>
              <did>
                <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
                <container type="segment" label="Segment">12</container>
                <unittitle>Volume 1, Nos. 11, 13, 22, 23, 25, 27-29, 32-34, 37-39, 45; <unitdate>1967 March 23, April 8, June 10, 16, 30, July 14, 21, 28, August 18, 25, September 1, 23, 29, October 6, 27</unitdate></unittitle>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
          <container type="segment" label="Segment">12</container>
          <unittitle>Mississippi General Politics</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
            <container type="segment" label="Segment">13</container>
            <unittitle>Mississippi voting and voters registration, elections, politics, and reference materials, <unitdate>1963-1968</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
            <container type="segment" label="Segment">14</container>
            <unittitle>General information, State Officers, <unitdate>1964-1968</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
            <container type="segment" label="Segment">15</container>
            <unittitle>Election results, <unitdate>1966-1969</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
            <container type="segment" label="Segment">16</container>
            <unittitle>General information on politics and the Democratic Party - writings of McLemore and others, <unitdate>undated</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="reel" label="Reel">3</container>
            <container type="segment" label="Segment">17</container>
            <unittitle>Young Democratic Clubs of Mississippi, <unitdate>1965</unitdate></unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
