<?xml version="1.0"?>
<ead>
  
  
  
  
  <eadheader xmlns:cdlpath="http://www.cdlib.org/path/" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" scriptencoding="iso15924" audience="internal" langencoding="iso639-2b" findaidstatus="unverified-full-draft"><eadid countrycode="us" identifier="ark:/13030/tf738nb1md" mainagencycode="CHi" publicid="PUBLIC -//California Historical Society::North Baker Research Library//TEXT (US::CHi::MS 3582::William Daegener Papers)//EN ms_3582.sgm " cdlpath:parent="ark:/13030/tf7v19p5mm">ms_3582.xml</eadid><filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the William Daegener Papers, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1850-1871</date></titleproper><titleproper type="filing">Daegener (William) Papers, 1850-1871</titleproper>
        <author>Processed by California Historical Society staff; machine-readable finding aid created by Brooke Dykman Dockter</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>California Historical Society</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>North Baker Research Library</addressline>
          <addressline>678 Mission Street</addressline>
          <addressline>San Francisco, California 94105-4014</addressline>
          <addressline>Phone: (415) 357-1848, ext. 220</addressline>
          <addressline>Fax: (415) 357-1850</addressline>
          <addressline>Email: reference@calhist.org</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: http://www.californiahistoricalsociety.org/</addressline>
        </address>
        <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> 2000</date>
        <p>California Historical Society. All rights reserved.</p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc><profiledesc>
      <creation>Machine-readable finding aid derived from MS Word. Date of source: <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 28, 1996 and May 2, 1996.</date></creation>
      <langusage>Description is in <language>English.</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc><revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20040323">March 23, 2004</date>
        <item>PUBLIC "-//California Historical Society::North Baker Research Library//TEXT (US::CHi::MS 3582::William Daegener Papers)//EN" "ms_3582.sgm"  converted from EAD 1.0 to 2002 by v1to02.cdl.xsl (2004-09-16).</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc></eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Guide to the William Daegener Papers, <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1850-1871</date></titleproper>
      <num>Collection number: MS 3582</num>
      <publisher>California Historical Society <lb/><extptr linktype="simple" entityref="chsseal" show="embed" actuate="onload" inline="true"/><lb/>North Baker Research Library <lb/>San Francisco, California</publisher>
      <list type="simple">
        <head>Contact Information:</head>
        <item>California Historical Society</item>
        <item>North Baker Research Library</item>
        <item>678 Mission Street</item>
        <item>San Francisco, California 94105-4014</item>
        <item>Phone: (415) 357-1848, ext. 220</item>
        <item>Fax: (415) 357-1850</item>
        <item>Email: reference@calhist.org</item>
        <item>URL: http://www.californiahistoricalsociety.org/</item>
      </list>
      <list type="deflist">
        <defitem>
          <label>Processed by: </label>
          <item>California Historical Society staff</item>
        </defitem>
        <defitem>
          <label>Date Completed: </label>
          <item>March 28, 1996 and May 2, 1996</item>
        </defitem>
        <defitem>
          <label>Encoded by: </label>
          <item>Brooke Dykman Dockter</item>
        </defitem>
      </list>
      <p> 2000 California Historical Society. All rights reserved.</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc xmlns:cdlpath="http://www.cdlib.org/path/" level="collection">
    <did id="did-1.7.1">
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">William Daegener Papers, </unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" type="inclusive">1850-1871</unitdate>
      <unitid label="Collection number">MS 3582</unitid>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname>Daegener, William</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc label="Extent">301 items</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <corpname>California Historical Society, North Baker Library</corpname>
        <address>
          <addressline>San Francisco, California 94105-4014</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <langmaterial label="Language">
        <language langcode="eng">English.</language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <descgrp type="admininfo" id="descgrp-1.7.2">
      <head>Administrative Information</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>Collection is open for research by appointment only.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict>
        <head>Publication Rights</head>
        <p>Copyright has not been assigned to The North Baker Research Library. All requests for permission to publish or quote from manuscripts must be submitted in writing to the Library Director. Permission for publication is given on behalf of The North Baker Research Library as the owner of the physical items and is not intended to include or imply permission of the copyright holder, which must also be obtained by the reader.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Preferred Citation</head>
        <p>[Identification of item], William Daegener Papers. MS 3582, California Historical Society, North Baker Research Library.</p>
      </prefercite>
    </descgrp>
    <scopecontent id="scopecontent-1.7.3">
      <head>Scope and Content</head>
      <p>The documents in this collection (letters, receipts, checks and other business and legal documents) are dated from October 12, 1850 to August 31, 1871.  The document descriptions below are in chronological order, with undated documents at the end.  The documents themselves are arranged in two folders, with date ranges October 12, 1850  to May 1871 (Folder 1) and February 19, 1863 to August 31, 1871 (Folder 2).</p>
      <list>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 12, 1850.  </unitdate>A two-page handwritten letter addressed to "My Dear cousin" comes from Susie Nourse in Washington. Nourse describes her trip from Washington to New York ( the Astor House and Steweart's dry goods store) and then by ship through the Sound to Stamford, CT.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 2, 1850.  </unitdate>A two-page handwritten letter addressed to "My Dear friend" comes from Susie in Washington.  She describes a trip down the river to Alexandria, then on to Mt. Vernon, where the group toured George Washington's  tomb and house.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January  1851.  </unitdate>A two-page handwritten letter addressed to "My dear teacher" (also referred to as "cousin" in the body of the lettter) comes from Susie Nourse in Washington.  (A notation in a different hand indicates that the letter was written "To Rosalie".  Someone has made spelling and grammatical corrections on the letter.)  Nourse describes her family's Christmas festivities.  She quotes from a Longfellow poem about childhood.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 20, 1859.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt from Columbia for $20.80 paid to Nudd  Canavan by Northern Light Mining Co. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 20, 1859 to April 23, 1860.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice for $303.99 paid to Smith Morse  Company by Northern Light Mining Company.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 29, 1959.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt from Columbia for $3.00 paid to Giles Keys.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 3, 1859.  </unitdate>A handwritten IOU from Columbia indicates that John Berry received $200 at 3% interest from J. M. Carr.   Notations on the reverse show that Berry paid $120 interest on September 2.  The note and mortgage were transferred to William Daegener on Berry's order on October 24, 1862.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 3, 186?.  </unitdate>A printed invoice to Wells Fargo  Co. in Sonora from Bostwick  Wilhoit in Stockton indicates payment was received.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 15, 1860.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt from Sonora indicates that $25 was received from J. J. Clapp for the account of Northern Light Fluming Co. by N. P. Barber.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 20, 1860.  </unitdate>A handwritten listing from Shaw's Flat by the treasurer of the Northern Light Mining and Fluming Co. indicates charges made to Northern's account with Lict Co. between December 31 and February 27 and payments made between December 26 and April 28.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 7, 1960.  </unitdate>Six handwritten payment orders (numbers 3 through 8) are signed in Shaw's Flat by John Fahey, Secretary Pro Tem of Northern Light Mining and Tunneling Co.  By order of the trustees, the treasurer is directed to pay $8 to C. G. Noyes, $11 to Raging Canal Co., $30 to Murty Gargan, $141.50 to Charles Hamilton, $28.50 to J.  M. Harrington, and $12.50 to  N. Talbot.  The latter three are endorsed on the reverse for funds received.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 18, 1860.  </unitdate>N. P. Barber's handwritten two-page treatise on the rights of and process to be followed by Northern Light Co. to resell stock for which the second assessment was not paid.  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 31, 1860.  </unitdate>A handwritten copy of a claim by the Northern Light Co. of 400 feet of ground on which to mine was recorded and signed by Smith Morse  Co., J. C. Noyes, J. S. Whttem(?) and J. C. Russell.  E. G. Jones, Recorder, attests as to the truth of the copy.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 19, 1860.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt made out to William Daegener by Northern 
Light Co. for 21 lbs. nitric acid and 50 revenue stamps totalling $9.82.  On the reverse are columns of figures and notations about the amount of gold dust in the treasury, etc.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 3, 1860.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice from Clapp  Noyes made out to Northern Light Mining  T. Co. lists items purchased between July 23 and November 30 totalling $548.41.  A notation on the bottom, signed by Clapp  Noyes, indicates that the bill was paid.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 21, 1860.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia by Westley  Wiler indicates that Northern Light F.  M. Co. paid its bill of 50.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 21, 1860.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia by J. B. Tinkum indicates that Northern Light Fluming and Mining Co. paid its bill for goods delivered to William Daegener.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 21, 1860.   </unitdate>A printed receipt signed by William Daegener, Treasurer, in Columbia is for $31 received for the account of North Light Flum  M. Co. from William Shea.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 31, 1860.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a piece of lined blue paper indicates that Daniel Sewell was paid $220 by the Treasurer of Northern Light Tunnel  Mining Co. for "laying down flume".  The receipt is dated on the reverse.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 9, 1861.  </unitdate>A printed receipt signed by William Daegener, Treasurer, in Columbia is for $30 received for the account of North L. Fl.  T Co. from William Shea.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 26, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed in Columbia indicates that W. S. Shea paid $5 to Daegener for drawing a contract for Northern Light T  M Co., E. R. Galvin, Director.  Galvin has signed on the reverse.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 2, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt from Columbia indicates that Westley Welch  Wheeler received payment of $1 from W. W. and W. D. of Northern Light Tunnel Co. for paper and envelopes.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 2, 1861.  </unitdate>An invoice handwritten in Sonora for various items of lumber ordered from Clapp  Noyes by N. L. M  T. Co. is signed by Murty Gargan.  The invoice is marked "paid" on March 11.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 7, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed in Shaws Flat indicates that Henry Allen was paid $26.25 for 8 days' work putting in timbers for the Northern Light Mining Co.  Allen has signed on the reverse.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 11, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt indicates that Clapp  Noyes received payment of $555.71 from Northern Light M.  T. Co. for lumber ordered between December 1, 1860 and March 11, 1861.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 11, 1861. </unitdate>A handwritten receipt from Shaw's Flat and signed by W. S. Shea, Secretary of N. L. Mining Co. orders $555.571 as payment for lumber to Clapp  Noyes by July 1, 1861.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 12, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt from Shaw's Flat indicates that Murty Gargan received 7,971 feet of lumber for N. L. Mining Co. from Clapp  Noyes.  Both companies have signed on the reverse.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 16 to 25, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice from C. E. Gorham  Co. shows that orders totalling $19.50 were paid by Northern Light. C. E. Gorham has signed on the reverse.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 20, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt from Shaws Flat, signed by Henry Allen indicates that he was paid $8.75 for 3 and 1/2 days' work from March 11 by Northern Light Mining Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 8, 1861.   </unitdate>A printed receipt signed in Columbia by William Daegener, Treasurer, is made out to Thomas Walsh  for $60 paid to the account of N. L. Fl.  M. Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 8 to July 18, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice indicates that Gorham  Parker, over the signature of Bacon, were paid $68.80 by Northern Light Fluming Co. for various goods ordered.  Gorham  Parker have signed on the reverse.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 10, 1861.  </unitdate>A receipt 

written on a printed form of Wells, Fargo  Co., Columbia to N. L. F  M Co. for a total of $2,124.70.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 14, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice and receipt signed in Columbia by Bacon for Gorham  Parker indicates that they received payment from Northern Light Co. for $40.12 worth of tiles, hatchet, hinges, auger and bit, etc. ordered between February 27 and April 4.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 17, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten bill presented to Northern Lite, W. H. Cone, Director, for $68.09 for lumber, requests payment to E. G. Gilkey.  Gilkey has signed on the bottom, indicating that he was paid $62.12 on June 24.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 22, 1861.  </unitdate>A printed receipt signed by William Daegener, Treasurer, indicates William Shea paid $2 to the account of North L. Fl  M. Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 3 to July 29, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten bill  to Northern Light Mining Co. for water from the Phoenix Water Co. totals $230.  A notation on the reverse, signed by N. B. Harriman, indicates that $103 was paid.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 1, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice for lumber totalling $248.79 ordered from Clapp  Noyes between May 13 and June 20 was paid by Northern Light M  T Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 6, 1861.  </unitdate>A printed receipt signed in Columbia by William Daegener, Treasurer, indicates that W. S. Shea, Secretary, paid $2.25 to the account of North L Fl  M Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 19, 1861.  </unitdate>A printed receipt signed in Columbia by William Daegener, Treasurer, indicates that W. A. Shea, Secretary, paid $4 to the account of N L Fl  M Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 16, 1861  </unitdate>A printed receipt signed in Columbia by William Daegener, Treasurer, indicates that  Murty Gargan paid $2,652.35 to the account of Northern Light Fl  M. Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 19, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice for lumber totalling $181.30 ordered from Clapp  Noyes between July 24 and August 16 was paid by Northern Light F  M Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 24, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice for miscellaneous items including drills, picks and handles, cranks, crowbar, etc. totalling $54.90 ordered from Nathaniel Talbot was paid by Northern Light Tunnel and Minn.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 26, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice for 4 kegs of blasting powder and 550 feet of fuse ordered from R. M. DeChen (and signed by N. Miles) was paid by Northern Light Mining Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 26, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice for $6.28 worth of nitric acid ordered by Northern Light Fluming Co. from Eagle Drug Store in Columbia is signed for Dr. E. Schmidt by A. Heitz.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 31, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed by William Daegener, Treasurer, in Columbia indicates that M. Gargan paid $107.35 to the account of North Light Fl  M Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 2, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed by William Daegener, Treasurer, in Columbia indicates that William Shea paid $10 to the account of North Light Flum  M Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 25, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed by William Daegener, Treasurer, in Columbia indicates that William Shea paid $16 to the account of North Light fl  M Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 8, 1861.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in the <title linktype="simple" inline="true">Times </title>office in Columbia indicates that H. A. Bennett received payment via Mr. Chen of $4 for an advertisement of Northern Light Tunnell (sic) Company's $100,000 worth of capital stock.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 21, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed by William Daegener, Treasurer, in Columbia indicates that M. Gargan paid $17 in taxes for "running into Flume" to the account of North L Fl.  M. Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 16, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt for $42.67 worth of rope purchased from William Bosworth by North Light Mining Comp. indicates payment was received, as signed 

by A. Madison (?).   Bosworth has signed on the reverse, indicating payment as well.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 14, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed by William Daegener, Treasurer, in Columbia indicates that M. Gargan paid $348 to the account of the North Light fluming  Mining Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 16, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed by William Daegener, Treasurer, in Columbia  indicates that M. Gargan paid $32 to the account of North Light fl.  M Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 16, 1861.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed by William Daegener, Treasurer, in Columbia indicates that M. Gargan paid $2,358.85 (i. e. 124 ounces, 2 and 1/2 drams of gold @ $19 per ounce) to the account of the North Light fl.  Mining Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 30, 1862.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice from S. Knapp indicates that William Daegener bought various kinds of lumber totalling $20.41 ordered between July 31 and August 3, 1861.  A notation at the bottom, partially torn off, says that payment was received in Columbia on October 26, 1861.  S. Knapp has signed diagonally across the invoice, however, indicating payment on June 30, 1862.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 1, 1862.  </unitdate>A printed Wells, Fargo  Co.'s Express order form  for stationery, franks, etc. has been used for writing a note in Columbia.  The note, asking for "2 crucibles of N. D.",  is addressed to William Daegener from Sohnakey (?)</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 15, 1862 to December 14, 1863.  </unitdate>A  handwritten annual report of the Secretary (of the mining company) indicates a healthy financial situation.  Details are given of gold dust sold, costs of construction work, dividends paid, etc.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 19, 1863.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt on a scrap of lined paper written in Columbia indicates that William Daegener paid D. M. Waggoner $23 for work done on the American Camp steam engine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 2, 1863.  </unitdate>A handwritten document signed by Walter Forrester appoints William Daegener his attorney and the receiver of all money due Forrester from the Raging Cannal (sic) Company of Shaws Flat.  The document also gives Daegener the power to vote in Forrester's behalf at all official meetings of the company.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 4, 1863.  </unitdate>A bill of sale handwritten on lined paper indicates that Edward Salbach (witnessed by Louis Ehemann) sold to William Daegener of Columbia 25 feet in a gold and silver bearing quartz vein called the Isabella in the Makelumne (sic) District of Amador County as well as 10 feet in the Winnemuck Gold and Silver Mining Company and 10 feet in the Rough and Ready Mining Company.  The total cost to Daegener was $540.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 28 to December 9, 1863.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice indicates that Enterprise Co. (signed by M. H. White, Secretary Pro Tem) purchased lumber totalling $14.86 from A. Fletcher, who signs for receipt of payment.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 19, 1863.  </unitdate>A tally of votes for the election of Trustees is signed by William Daegener and Michael Maguire.  Those elected Trustees were John Wallace, M. Gargan, B. T. Ryder, E. Schmidt, and S. Bixel.  William Daegener was elected Treasurer and W. S. Shea Secretary.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 5, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten announcement of an assessment of $10 per share on Enterprise M. Co. stock was levied in Columbia by the Board of Trustees, payable January 15.  The announcement is signed by William Daegener, President, and M. H. White, Secretary.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 11, 1864.  </unitdate>A torn, stained, lined sheet contains a letter (only partially readable) to Daegener from W. H. Cummings of San Jose.  The letter says Cummings has decided to accept Daegener's offer of ?? hundred dollars for his interest in the Enterprise Quartz Claim.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 15, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten letter on letterhead of Wells, Fargo  Co. from "Chinese" comes to 
Daegener from C. M. H. Solinsky.   Solinsky thanks Daegener for his letter and for the crucible to replace the broken one.  He asks that two special crucibles be sent by return express, as he destroyed the first crucibles during the annealing process.  He sends regards to Mrs. Daegener and the family.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 17, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on a folded lined sheet is addressed to Daegner (sic) from M. Van Gemmerez in Virginia City.  The letter is written in German.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 18, 1864.  </unitdate>An official printed form from Francis E. Spencer, Notary Public, in Santa Clara County attests as to the identity of William H. Cummings.  The document has been impressed with Spencer's official seal and is attached to the back of a lined sheet, signed by Cummings, a resident of Columbia in Tuolumne County.  The document states that Cummings has sold his interest (shares 15, 16, 17, and 18) in the Enterprise Quartz Mining Company in Sugar Pine to William Daegener for the sum of $700.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 18, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined paper is addressed to W. Dagner (sic) from W. H. Cummings in San Jose.  Cummings says he is enclosing the bill of sale for his shares (see above).  He reiterates to Daegener that he should send him $130 and deposit $500 to his account with Sleeper (?)  Co., then send him the certificate of deposit.  Cummings says he has authorized transferral of the stock from his name to Daegener's.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 18, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on a lined sheet is addressed to Daegener from R. Norton of San Francisco.  Norton acknowledges receipt of Daegener's letter and hastens to reply that he, too, has paid more than his share of the company's debts.  He says he paid $50 more than his portion of the water bill and $35 of the company's debt for a piece of hose, which totals $72 more than his share of the bill.  He hopes Geo  Kit will refund the overpayments which he and Daegener have made.  Norton says he has not yet given anyone a bill of sale for the quartz claim.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 20, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on a lined sheet is addressed to Daegener from Solinsky of "Chinese".  Solinsky thanks Daegener for his kindness to him, and says he is enclosing $11.50 to pay for the wringer and the last crucible he sent.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 20 and 25, 1864.  </unitdate>Three handwritten receipts on one sheet are signed in Columbia indicating that Enterprise Quartz Mining Co. paid $173 to F. M. Baker, $70.50 to William Peacock and $5 to H. Piley.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 21, 1864.  </unitdate>A bill of sale handwritten on lined paper indicates that H. Piley (witnessed by C. H. White) sold nine shares (numbers 1, 2, 3, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 and 10) of capital stock in the Enterprise Quartz Mining Company to William Daegener for $1,000.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 21, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia indicates that E. A. Briggs received $20 from William Daegener for work done.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 21, 1864.  </unitdate>An announcement handwritten in Columbia says that the Board of Trustees of the Enterprise Quartz Mining Company have levied an assessment of $100 per share payable on February 1.   The announcement is signed by M. H. White, Secretary Pro Tem.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 25, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a scrap of lined paper and signed by William Peacock, indicates that William Daegener paid an assessment of $11.50 on one share of the Invincible Claim.  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 26, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt from Haskell, White  Ford in Columbia to Enterprise Mining Company shows steel, pads and mortar and pestle totalling $26.13, ordered between November 24, 1863 and January 8, 1864.  The invoice is signed as paid by Haskell, White  Ford. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 27, 1864.  </unitdate>A bill of sale handwritten on lined paper, signed in Columbia by H. W. G. Gerry and F. R. Cowles 

(witnessed by H. Piley and C. H. White),  indicates that Gerry and Cowles sold a steam engine, machinery, blacksmith tools, anvil, bellows, saws, tracks, belts and other items belonging to the American Mill near Comstocks Ranch in Tuolumne County to William Daegener for $2,000.  The sellers state that there is no mortgage outstanding on any of the materials sold.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 29, 1864.  </unitdate>A printed receipt signed by William Daegener                                                 in Columbia indicates that Joseph Smith paid $200 as assessment no. 7 on his 2 shares of Enterprise Q Min stock.  Smith has signed the reverse.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 3, 1864.  </unitdate>A printed receipt signed by William Daegener, Treasurer, in Columbia indicates that J. H. Housman paid $50 as assessment no. 7 on his 1/2 share of Enterprise Q M. Co. stock.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 5 to May 25, 1864.  </unitdate>Three long, thin sheets of accounting paper contain lists of lumber ordered by William Daegener between these dates.  The total of the items on the first page is $233.83, page two $165.20 and page three $227.42.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 6, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten letter is addressed to Daegner (sic) from B. R. Norton of San Francisco.  Norton acknowledges receipt of Daegener's letter and says he is sorry he could not fill his order sooner.  He is enclosing some gold thimbles, but says they have no gold hair pins (he suggests gilt ones instead).  Norton congratulates Daegener on the birth of another baby.  He asks Daegener whether he could send him some good quartz for cutting.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 7, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a scrap of accounting paper indicates that Daegener paid A. B. Crook $34.86 for hauling services on February 7, 11 and 16 from the mountain to Sonora .</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 20, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed by W. T. Garrison in Columbia indicates that William Daegener paid him $12.50 for work on the soapstone quarry.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 22, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed by R. G. Northes in Columbia indicates that William Daegener paid him $45 for work on the steam engine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 24, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener, treasurer of the Enterprise Q. M. Co., paid $200 to Haskell White  Ford in return for their paying this amount as Daegner's assessment no. 7.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 28, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice/receipt made out to William Dagener (sic) for chisels, iron, etc. totalling $27.44 is signed by Haskell White  Ford as paid.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 1, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten on a scrap of blue accounting paper indicates that William Daegener paid $19.25 to I.and S. W. Shotwell for windows, oil, brushes, paint and lead.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 1, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten on a scrap of blue accounting paper indicates that William Daegener paid $11.37 to I. and S. W. Shotwell for tar and windows ordered on February 3.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 1, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten on a scrap of blue accounting paper indicates that William Daegener paid $9.92 to Haskell White  Ford for items ordered on the same date.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 4, 1864.  </unitdate>A note handwritten on letterhead of Wells, Fargo  Co., San Francisco, indicates that L. T. Zander sent  W. Daegener the steam gauge, steam whistle and rubber packing he had ordered, and now requests payment of $52.70.  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 4, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed by R. Raymond, President, indicates that William Daegener paid $25 as assessment no. 2  on "the peacock Claim on sugarpine".</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 8, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid A. Fletcher  Co. $400 for lumber.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 8, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/ receipt handwritten in Sonora on a scrap of lined paper indicates that A. B. Crook was paid freight costs for transporting 1427 pounds of dies, shoes, screws, grate bars, battery plates and forge fixtures.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 9, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of accounting paper indicates that William Daegener paid Haskell White  Ford $37.92 for various items.  (The reverse of this receipt contains dates, names and amounts as from an account book.)</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 9, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of blue accounting paper indicates that W. J. Daegener  paid I. and S. W. Shotwell $13.77 for varnish, borax, a paint brush, hinges, screws, washers and lead.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 10, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Sonora on a scrap of lined paper indicates that A. B. Crook was paid freight costs for transporting 2,054 pounds of gear, buttons, shafting, pillow with cap and flanges from the Sonora Foundry to Daegener's mill near Enterprise.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 14, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid T. W. Povrenen (?) $4, representing Daegener's share of a note dated April 14, 1863 by Norton  Co. for $26.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 18, 1864.  </unitdate>A note handwritten to William Daegener on letterhead of Wells, Fargo  Co., San Francisco, by Zander requests payment for Daegener's $214.85 order of sheet copper and rubber which was sent on this date.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 19, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid $73 to R. D. Smart for 36 and 1/2 days of work.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 19, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice/receipt to Daegener represents various days of work by big and small teams, meals and hay between February and March 2 by S. Knapp  Co. totalling $408.06.  S. Knapp has signed as paid.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 21, 1864.   </unitdate>A Wells, Fargo  Co.'s Express freight form from Stockton is addressed to W. Daegener, c/o S. Starbuck and signed by R. Larmis (?) for W. F.  Co.  The charge is for $5 freight on 10 copper sheets.  An attached handwritten invoice/receipt addressed to William Daegner (sic) and signed by S. Starbuck shows that total charges of $11 were paid to Monroe Lucas for him.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 21, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten on a scrap of blue accounting paper indicates that William Daegener paid I. and S. W. Shotwell $14 for a screw plate, varnish, a tool brush and emery paper.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 23, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a scrap of accounting paper indicates that A. B. Crook was paid freight costs for transporting 2,349 pounds of heads, stems, tappets, a crank, grate bars and washers.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 26, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt to Enterprise Gold and Silver Mining Co. from J. C. Duchow is for 1 square of advertising for 4 weeks totalling $7.50.  The amount is marked as paid.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 26, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid Alfred Flood $85 for work at Sugarpine. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 27, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in Howland Flat on lined paper is addressed to William Daegner (sic) from J. G. Fredenburr, who is responding to Daegener's letter re selling his wheel.  Fredenburr explains that the wheel would not be of use to him because the claims in his area have double inclines and therefore require reels that have reverse gears and run both ways, which Daegener's wheel apparently doesn not.  However, Fredenburr says he will contact Mr. Andrews about disposing of the wheel.  If Daegener has not sold it by "the latter part of this season", when Fredenburr expects to be in Columbia, he promises to dispose of the wheel for 

Daegener.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 29, 1864.  </unitdate>A note handwritten from San Andreas on a small lined sheet is addressed to William Daegner (sic) from Thornton Westlup (?), who informs Daegener that the Florence Sewing Machine he ordered left San Francisco on March 23.  He asks Daegener to write to him in Angels to let him know of the machine's arrival and to send there anything else for him.  At the bottom, Daegener has answered that the machine arrived in good condition and that he is leaving the packing untouched until Westlup arrives -- soon, he hopes, as Mrs. Daegener is "anxious to. . ." (and the note trails off).</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 5, 1864.  </unitdate>An memo handwritten on a small piece of paper  and signed by M. H. White, Secretary, directs the treasurer of the Enterprise Q. M. Co. to pay $60 to C. Dachen.  Across the document has been written in another hand "paid April 5, 1864".</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 6, 1864.  </unitdate>A note handwritten from Chester on a small lined sheet is addressed to Dagnener (sic) from E. S. Bates.  Bates says he hopes Daegener has collected the balance due on the "banding burgh" note and asks that the amount be sent to him in Griggsville, Illinois, via a draft.  Bates says he has been in Chester for the winter, buying horses and mules for the government.  He reports he is thinking seriously of getting married.  He is engaged to "a smart young lady" whom he is trying to persuade to go to California with him.  Bates reports a cold winter, but says his health and economic times are both good.  He has not yet been drafted, but the end of the war is not in sight.   In a postscript, Bates asks Daegener to remind Jack 'Bandingburg"  that he owes him two letters. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 9, 1864.  </unitdate>Two handwritten orders to the Enterprise Q. M. Co. treasurer, signed by M. H. White, Secretary, directs that $117 be paid to Mather Young and $7.75 to D. S. Larner.  William Daegener has written diagonally across both orders indicating payment.  M. Young has signed on the reverse of the first.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 13, 1864.  </unitdate>A note handwritten in Sonora on a small piece of lined paper is addressed to Daugener (sic) from the Sonora Foundry Co.  The note informs Daegener that he owes the foundry a total of $194.71 for two bills, receipts for which are enclosed.  The foundry asks that Daegener send the $194.71 by stage driver and at the same time return the receipt for $200 which he was given on Saturday last.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 18, 1864.  </unitdate>A bill of sale handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that Orrin Goss sold 1/2 share in the Norton Claim on Knapps Ranch to William Garrison for $10.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 20, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Sugar Pine on a scrap of lined paper indicates that H. Piley, acting for William Daegener, paid $84 to M. McGuirk for 21 days of blacksmith work.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 20, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia indicates that William Blug (?) received $1240 from William Daegener.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 22, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined paper on lined paper from the Sonora Foundry by  J. Phelps is addressed to Daugener (sic).  Phelps says he will send a man up on Monday to check on the items the foundry made for Daegener.  He thinks they were made to order -- but says if not, they will repair them at the foundry's expense.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 23, 1864.  </unitdate>A bill of sale handwritten on lined paper in Columbia is signed by Charles Williams and witnessed by E. R. Galvin.  Williams transfers  title and interest (three and one-half shares) in the quartz lode in the Sugar Pine District of Tuolumne County, known as the Enterprise Claim, to William Daegener for $600.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 25, 1864.  </unitdate>A bill of sale handwritten on lined paper in Columbia is signed by J. A. Smith and witnessed by W. A. Davis. Smith transfers title and interest (two shares -- 1/16 of the 
entire claim) in the quartz lode in the Sugar Pine District of Tuolumne County, known as the Enterprise Claim, to William Daegener for $300.  A brown 25 certificate stamp is affixed in the upper right corner and initialed and dated by Smith.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 26, 1864.  </unitdate>A bill of sale handwritten on lined paper in Columbia is signed by Haskell, White  Ford and witnessed by H. Piley.  Haskell, White  Ford transfer title and interest (two shares -- nos. 31 and 32) in the quartz lode in the Sugar Pine District of Tuolumne County, known as the Enterprise Claim, to William Daegener for $380. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 27, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid W. V. Andrews $250 for work on Quartzmill, Sugarpine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 30, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined paper in San Francisco by B. R. Norton is addressed to Daegener.  Norton says Daegener's watch has been repaired.  He is happy that Daegener's "quartz prospects are good".  Norton says his own business is good, too.  He sends his regards to Mrs. Daegener and to Hattie.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a scrap of lined paper in Columbia indicates that William Garrison paid R. Norton $15 towards his share of expenses for the Norton Claim on Knapps Ranch.  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 5, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in pencil on lined paper from Saw Mill Flat is addressed to Daegner (sic) from Robert Burgess.  Burgess claims that, though he continually agrees to do so, Mr. Black has never put quicksilver in the sluices.  Burgess says this is preventing himself and unspecified others from working their claims.  He proposes that those involved buy the quicksilver and put it in the slices themselves.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 5, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined paper in San Francisco comes from Ackerman Bros. to William Daegener in Columbia.  The company explains that the blankets Daegener ordered were erroneously delivered to him at the Sacramento-bound boat, instead of the Stockton-bound boat.  Therefore, Ackerman Bros. is now sending the errant blankets to him by express.  A postscript asks Daegener to call on the company when next he is in San Francisco.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 11, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a scrap of lined blue paper indicates that M. W. Parsons of Piley Co. received payment of $1.25 for four sponges from M. W. P.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 13, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of paper indicates that William Daegener paid Charles McDonald $15.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 14, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Sugar Pine on a scrap of blue paper indicates that H. Piley paid $207 to Willy Reynolds for 69 days' work at $3 a day.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 14, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in pencil from H. Piley of the Piley Mill is addressed to Daegener.  Piley's spelling is poor.  He tells Daegener that he is ready to start up, but the Foundry has removed the gear.  He asks Daegener to "hury them up".  Piley says it is raining hard.  He has hired McPherson of the Excelsior as a blacksmith.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 14, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on both sides of a small sheet in Copperopolis is addressed to Dagener (sic) from J. Angeli.  Angeli reports that the Star of the West company held a meeting on May 11  to elect officers for the next six months.  He says the company does not intend to work the claim, except as required by law, until their financial situation is straightened out.  Angeli says they have found silver on the claim and they believe this "will prove to be valuable".  He advises Daegener to wait until they have prospected a bit more.  He says Daegener owes $15 for the February 1 assessment.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 17, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on a small sheet of lined blue paper from Peters  Jackson in Stockton tells W. Daugner (sic) that his check for 
$107.82 has been received and credited.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 18, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined paper from San Francisco is addressed to William Daegener from S. S. Hallidie  Co.  The company acknowledges receipt of Daegener's check for $116.45 as payment for wire rope.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 20, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined paper from San Francisco is addressed to Daegner (sic) from B. R. Norton.  Norton  acknowledges receipt of Daegener's $10 check and sends regards to Mrs. Daegener and Hattie.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 23, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt, printed on blue paper, for an assessment no. 2 on stock in the Isabella G.  S. M. Co. is made out in Vallecito to William Daegener and signed by John Cramer, Secretary.  The receipt indicates that Daegener paid $6.25, representing an assessment of 25 per share, levied on May 21. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 27, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia indicates that William Daugener (sic) paid $50 against his bill, as acknowledged by Mr. Piley, at the Sonora Foundry Co.  J. Phelps has signed the receipt.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 2, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of paper indicates that William Daegener paid W. V. Andrews $206.75.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 2, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten on lined blue accounting paper indicates that William Daegner (sic) paid Bowen Bacon  Co. a total of $249.71 for various items ranging from raisins, coffee and other food stuffs to nails, files and a blacksmith hammer to two kegs of powder, ordered on March 28, April 26, May 2 and May 10.  Payment for the bill was received on December 22, 1864.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 3, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt, handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of paper and signed by John McNally, Secretary, indicates that William Daegener paid $25 as assessment no. 2 of the Peacock Q. M. Co. on Sugarpine.  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 4, 1864.   </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined paper to Deagener (sic) from H. Piley in Sugar Pine reports on the abundance of shale and lead.  He says he will send an order soon.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 4, 1864.  </unitdate>A note handwritten on a scrap of accounting paper comes from A. Fletcher  Co. in Sugar Pine Mill and asks Mr. Piley to pay Bowen  Bacon $66 on his account.  The reverse is endorsed by Piley and by Bowen  Bacon.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 5, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten from Arlington, Columbia County, Wisconsin on lined paper is addressed to Daegener from William Shaw.  Shaw says it is a long time since he has heard from Daegener.  He reports he is fine, and anticipates soon joining the army.  He says the weather is like California's, dry and warm.  Shaw asks about the flume and how much shares in it are worth currently.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 8, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Sonora on a scrap of lined accounting paper indicates that William Daegener paid M. Dyer $5.50.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 18, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of paper indicates that William Daegener paid Albert A. Moose $40 for work done in the quartz mill at Sugarpine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 20, 1864.   </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid A. Fletcher $46.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 21, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid William Littlefield $92 for work done at the quartz lode of Enterp. M. Co.  Attached by pin is another receipt handwritten on lined blue paper and signed by H. Piley. It directs Daegener to pay Littlefield $88.   A pencilled "+$4" has been circled on the receipt.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 25, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on both sides of a lined sheet in Sonora is addressed to Daegener from Joseph Phelps of the Sonora Foundry Co.  Phelps reports on the findings of the man sent from the foundry to investigate 
Daegener's complaints about the wheel and cam fashioned for the mill.  Phelps reports they are fine, despite slight wearing on one corner of the cam which is to be expected.  He says Mr. Kirkwood reports that the pinion is worn, but he chipped off some of the uneven places in an attempt to make it run smoother.  If it does not do so, the foundry will replace it at a "reasonable discount".  Phelps says he is enclosing the bill for repairing the engine pump, which brings the total of Daegener's unpaid bills to four.  He asks for whatever payment Daegener can send immediately.  Phelps tells Daegener to let the foundry know  if he wants duplicates of any machinery.  He suggests having on hand an extra cam, tappet and head so work would not be delayed if these pieces fail to function. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 28, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice for court costs indicates that James M. Stewart was paid $4.85 for mileage, serving notice, making copies, filing, etc. in the legal case of William Daegener vs. J. Labusin (?) in Justices Court. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 28, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Clumbia (sic) on a scrap of blue accounting paper indicates that Dagner (sic) paid $15 to Haskell, White  Ford for items ordered on June 18.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 28, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid $100 to S. F. Owens for work done at the Sugarpine quartz mill.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 2, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid $30 to Dennis McKenna for work done on the Enterprise Claim in Sugarpine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 2, 1864.  </unitdate>Three receipts handwritten on a single sheet of lined paper indicate that William Daegener of Columbia paid J. Manna  (whose mark is witnessed by William Wagner) $25 for work, William Wagner $50 for work and M. Young $100 on the Enterprise Q. Claim, Sugarpine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 2, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid $100 to Kenneth McPherson for work done on the quartz mill in Sugarpine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 2, 1864.  </unitdate>An order handwritten in pencil on a scrap of paper in "Camp Law" directs H. Piley to pay J. B. Douglas $40 and charge this amount to the account of (name unreadable).  J. B. Douglas has signed the reverse in pen.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 4 to 6, 1864.  </unitdate>Four receipts handwritten on a single sheet of lined paper indicate that William Daegener of Columbia paid Dennis McKenna $10 for work, a Chinese  (whose signature in Chinese characters is witnessed by H. Piley) $160 for cooking, Kenneth McSherrey $14, and Dennis McKenna $5 for work on the Enterprise Quartz Lode, Sugarpine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 7, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid $40 to S. F. Owens for work done at the Sugarqine quartz mill.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 7, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on lined paper indicates that J. Alderman received $20 from William Daegener in Columbia.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 9, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid $50 against  his account with the Sonora Foundry Co.  J. Phelps has signed the receipt.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 13, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt  handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of paper indicates that William Daegener paid $10 to Orrin Goss.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 18, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice addressed to William Dreyer (sic) of Enterprise Mill from Well Teas Co. in Sonora totals $37.84 for miscellaneous merchandise and freight costs incurred between May 25 and July 24.  The signature of H. Piley on the reverse indicates that the bill is correct.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 20, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten notice on a small piece of paper from S. H. Owen in Sugar Pine 
asks Piley to pay George Benadom, tax collector of district no. 1, the sum of $7.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 21, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a sheet of paper indicates that William Daegener paid $65 for wood deliveries to Rodolph  Davis.  The receipt is signed by John A. Brown and J. McCutchen.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 22, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid $20.50 to Dennis McKenna for work done on the Enterprise Tunnel in Sugarpine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 22, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice handwritten on a small piece of blue accounting paper comes from Shotwell in Columbia indicating that William Daegener paid J.  S. W. Shotwell $5.20 for oil, turpentine, varnish and lamp black.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 26, 1864.  </unitdate>An order handwritten by H. Piley in Sugar Pine on a scrap of lined paper directs William Dageaner (sic) to pay the bearer, James Mercener, $43 for 34 days' work on the "clame".  Piley says Mercener has already received $25.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 28, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten order signed by H. Piley in Sugarpine on a scrap of lined paper directs Daegener to pay William Wagner $154 for 77 days' work, minus the amount already paid to Wagner.  On the reverse, Wagner signs as having received $97 on July 29.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 28, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten order signed by H. Piley in Sugarpine on a scrap of lined paper directs Daegener to pay Mathew Young $210.50 for 105 and 1/4 days' work, minus the amount already paid to Young. M. Young signs on the reverse.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 1, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten order signed by H. Piley in Sugarpine on a scrap of lined paper directs Daegener to pay Frank the cook $60.  The order has been signed on the reverse in Chinese characters.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 1, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a small piece of blue accounting paper with a 2 U. S. Internal Revenue stamp affixed indicates that C. E. Gorham of Gorham  Parker received payment of $56 for fuse, candles and powder kegs ordered on June 10 by  Enterprise G.  S. M. Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 2, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a small piece of blue accounting paper with a 2 U. S. Internal Revenue stamp affixed indicates that C. E. Gorham of Gorham  Parker received payment of $18.30 for rope, mustard, peaches and codfish ordered between June 3 and 14 by William Daegner (sic).</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 5, 1864.  </unitdate>A bill of sale, handwritten on a lined sheet, indicates that Samuel C. Morse of Sugarpine, Tuolumne County  (witnessed by H. Piley) has sold to William Daegener of Columbia County for $500 all his interest (ten shares) in the Invincible Gold and Silver Mining Company on Sugarpine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 10 to 29, 1864.   </unitdate>Three receipts handwritten on a single lined sheet indicate that William Daegener of Columbia paid $125, $25 and $50  to S. F. Owen.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 21, 1864.   </unitdate>A bill of sale, handwritten in Columbia on a sheet of paper bearing the Wells, Fargo  Co. letterhead, indicates that William Daegener purchased title to the quartz lode known as Invisible Claim in Sugarpine, Tuolumne County plus five shares in the company for $200.  The document is signed by M. H. Morse and J. S. R. Bowen. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 8, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten on a small piece of accounting paper indicates that McNally  Anderson received payment of $3.84 from William Daegener of Enterprise Quartz Mill, Sugarpine for tallow ordered on March 9 and April 16.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 12, 1864.  </unitdate>A statement from the Tuolumne County Water Company in Columbia indicates that William Daegener was paid $2.13.37 of the $325 due him as salary for 3 months and 8 days of serving as "acting Treasurer pro tem" for the company @ $100 a month.  Daegener is still owed $111.63.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 13, 1864.  </unitdate>A "due on demand" notice, handwritten on a  small piece of lined paper which has been torn in half,  indicates that F. J. Byrd was paid $600.  Byrd has signed on the reverse.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 19, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of accounting paper indicates that William Daegener paid J.  S. W. Shotwell $15 for lead, oil and windows.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 20, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a small piece of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid the Tuolumne County Water Company the balance due of $213.37.  The receipt is signed by C. C. Holton, President.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 22, 1864.  </unitdate>A printed stock assessment receipt, signed by J. S. R. Bowen, Secretary, indicates that William Daegener (for H. Piley) paid assessment no. 2 of $10 on a single share of Invincible Gold and Silver Mining Company stock.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 22, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt printed on blue paper is made to William Daegener and signed by J. L. R. Bowen, Secretary.  It indicates that Daegener paid $290 as assessment no. 2 on his 29 shares of  Invincible Gold  Silver Mining Co. stock.  The assessment of $10 per share was levied on August 8. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 26, 1864.  </unitdate>A printed stock assessment receipt, signed by J. S. R. Bowen, Secretary, indicates that William Daegener paid assessment no. 2 of $50 on his five shares of Invincible Gold and Silver Mining Company stock.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 30, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a scrap of lined paper  indicates that William Daegener of Columbia paid S. F. Owen $82.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 11, 1864.  </unitdate>A note from William Daegener addressed to Daniel is handwritten from Columbia on a small memo sheet bearing the Wells, Fargo  Co. letterhead.  Daegener asks Daniel to secure a report from surveyor William Cooper of Sonora who was hired to find out how far the Sugarpine tunnel was off from the shaft.  He wants to know how far they have yet to run the tunnel and whether or not they are going in the right direction.  He asks for a reply via the Stockton Stage.  On the reverse, in a different hand (ostensibly Cooper's), the survey report on  the Invincible Claim indicates that the distance from the end of the tunnel to the shaft is 49 feet, that by running the tunnel about 5 feet further they would strike a vein, that the depth of the shaft is 58 feet and that the height from the end of the tunnel to the surface is 47 feet.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 12, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice handwritten on a long sheet of blue accounting paper indicates that S. S. Bradford was paid a total of $141.75 by Gardener  Co. for a miscellany of board lumber ordered between May 25 and August 18.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 18, 1864 to January 4, 1865. </unitdate>A handwritten invoice to William Daegener indicates orders totalling $46.65 for cabbage, beets, boards, turnips and pork barrels, less a cash payment of $27.50, leaving a balance due of $19.15  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 22, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt signed in Columbia in Chinese characters indicates that William Daegener paid $105 to the signatory for unspecified work.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 31, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that W. Daegener paid N. Levening (?) $15.75 for wheat, butter, potatoes and pork.  Daegener has signed the reverse. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 4, 1864.  </unitdate>A bill of sale handwritten in Columbia indicates that Benjamin F. Crosby sold to William Daegener for $750 his interest (1 original share or 4 new shares, equalling 1/20 part of the whole) in the Rio Vista Claim, a quartz and placer mining claim, situated on Austrian Hill on the Stanislaus River in Calaveras County.  The document is signed by Crosby and witnessed by Charles C. Holton.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 7, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a small 
piece of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid H. Snering (?) $1 for raisins and currants.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 10, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a scrap of lined blue paper indicates that William Daegener paid $20 to M. H. Morse.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 10, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on a small piece of lined paper to William Daegener of Columbia by G. W. Page for John Taylor acknowledges receipt of a check for $13 which has been duly credited.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 11, 1864.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in Sugar Pine by Charles McDonald, asks William Daegener to pay $7 to William Wagener and charge the amount to McDonald</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 12, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a small piece of lined paper indicates that William Dagener (sic) paid M. W. Parsons $2.25 for crucibles and medicine ordered between August 8 and 27.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 14, 1864.  </unitdate>A handwritten letter to William Daegener from Francis Valentine  Co. in San Francisco indicates that they have sent a 500-certificate book for the Rio Vista G. and S. Mining Co. as per the order of Charles C. Holton.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 16, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a small piece of blue accounting paper indicates that J. Vanderbilt, signing for George C. Bush, received payment of $8 from Messrs. Daegener  Piley for a bellows ordered on November 10.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 28, 1864.  </unitdate>A group receipt signed in Columbia indicates that William Daegener paid $4 each to D. S. Turner, John McNally, J. C. Scott and C. Williams and $8 each to J. H. Hurd, E. E. White, Piter Michell, Gerdamo Sincily (?), J. B. Douglass, A. Bacigalupi, P. Mullon and C. William.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 10, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a small piece of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid $45 to Joseph Phelus (?) of Sonora Foundry Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 15, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Sonora on blue paper indicates that L. Charnucca (?) paid William Daegener $50 against a $100 promissory note signed by Charnucca and B. Dominique.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 17, 1864.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a small piece of paper indicates that William Daegener paid S. C. Morse $76 for work at the Quartz mill on Sugarpine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 22, 1864.  </unitdate>Two receipts, printed on blue paper and made out in Columbia to William Daegener, are signed by J. L. R. Bowen, Secretary of the Invincible G.  S. Mining Co.  The receipts are for payments of assessments nos. 3 and 4, levied on October 1 and November 6 respectively.  Daegener paid $1020 (at $15 per share on 34 shares of stock) on his own behalf and $30 (at the same rate but on a single share) on behalf of H. Piley.   </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 22, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten on a piece of blue accounting paper indicates that Bowen Bacon  Co. of Columbia received $58.10 from Enterprise G.  S. M. Co. for handles, lengths of fuse and powder kegs ordered between March 28 and May 24.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 23, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten in Sugar Pine on a scrap of lined paper indicates that Deagner (sic) ordered from William F. Russell  33  cords of wood delivered to the mine and another 13 cords for the boardinghouse for a total cost of $93.75.  On the reverse, Russell signs for payment on December 26.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 26, 1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of accounting paper indicates that Dagner (sic) paid L.  H. Levy $40.62.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 31, 1864.   </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten in Sonora on a piece of blue accounting paper indicates that W. M. Teas received payment of $637 from Dagner (sic) for freight to Sugar Pine  and powder kegs ordered between November 3 and December 14.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1864.  </unitdate>A 
bill for court costs indicates that E. E. White, signing for C. Gelcey (?), was paid $25.20 for various fees generated by the case of J. Menendez vs. William Daegener case in Justices Court.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1864.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that Piley Daegner (sic)  Co. paid $4 to Way Towle  Co. for live oak planks. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 16, 1865.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Sugar Pine on a scrap of accounting paper indicates that H. Piley paid $30 to A. Fletcher  Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 25, 1865.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten on a piece of accounting paper indicates that Joseph Aldermen received $100 from William Daegener as partial payment for potatoes and cabbages ordered by Henry Pilley (sic), acting on behalf of Daegener, between August 27 and November 15, 1864.  The total bill was for $241.69; a balance of $141.69 remains.  J. Aldermen has signed on the reverse for receipt of the $100. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 6, 1865.  </unitdate>A invoice/receipt, handwirtten on a piece of blue accounting paper with a  2 U. S. Internal Revenue stamp affixed, indicates that William Daegener has paid C. E. Gorham, signing for Gorham  Parker, $249.53 for sryup and whole pepper ordered on January 9, plus a balance brought forward on January 1.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 11, 1865.  </unitdate>A handwritten copy of a resolution passed by the Board of Trustees of the Invincible Gold and Silver Mining Co. states that the board has leased the mine to William Daegener for $1 (which has been paid) for as long as it takes him and two men to remove up to 200 tons of rock.  Daegener must operate the mine "in a proper, workmanlike manner" and keep the board apprised of the amount of gold he extracts.  The resolution is signed by Secretary J. S. R. Bowen. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 21, 1865.  </unitdate>A memo, handwritten on a small piece of blue accounting paper and signed by M. H. White, Secretary, directs the treasurer of the Enterprise Quartz Mining Company to pay $120.98 to Bowen  Bacon, who have signed on the reverse.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 1, 1865.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt, handwritten on lined paper with a blue 2 U. S. Internal Revenue stamp affixed, indicates that C. E. Gorham  Co. has received payment of $196.44 from Enterprise Quartz Mining Co. for iron, hemp packing, struts, a shovel, belts, leather, screws, coal, etc. ordered between March 28 and May 31, 1864.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 1, 1865.  </unitdate>A statement signed for R. B. Parker by C. E. Gorham indicates that William Daegener has paid $629 for "all demands against him" by C. E. Gorham  Co., Gorham  Parker and Gorham Bacon  Co. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 14, 1865.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of paper indicates that William Daegener paid William Bergel $18.37.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 2, 1865.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of lined paper indicates that William Daegener paid $45 to Rolodph  Davis (signed for by J. McCutchen) for wood delivered to his quartz mill on Sugarpine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 7, 1865.  </unitdate>A printed invoice on letterhead of Trout, Whitsel  Co in Columbia indicates that Northernlight Flume Co. ordered 24 pieces of lumber 16 feet long for $46.08.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 12, 1865.  </unitdate>A note, handwritten on a small piece of lined paper  with a torn brown 5 U. S. Internal Revenue stamp affixed, indicates that William Daegener owes You Quong, alias Frank, $50 three months after this date.  Someone has signed in Chinese characters on the reverse (ostensibly You Quong).</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 11, 1866.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten on a piece of accounting paper indicates that Northern Light Co. paid Parker  Bacon $16.50 for candles, fuses, a powder keg and a shovel, ordered between November 20, 1865 and February 21, 1866.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 16, 1866.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt 
handwritten in Columbia on a small piece of lined paper indicates that William Daegener was paid $9.35 for a crucible and nitric acid by North Light Fl. M. Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 16, 1866.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a small piece of paper indicates that J. P. Duham paid into the treasury of Northern Light Fl.  M. Co. 151.82 ounces of gold dust worth $2,778.30.  The receipt is signed by William Daegener, Treasurer.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 19, 1866.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt handwritten in Columbia indicates that S. S. Bradford received $15.38 from Northern Light Mining Co. for various amounts of board lumber ordered on March 3.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 9, 1866.  </unitdate>A receipt, handwritten in Columbia on a lined memo sheet bearing the letterhead of Wells, Fargo  Co., indicates that William  Daegener, Treasurer, received $20 from the Secretary of the North Light Fl.  Mining Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 24, 1868.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York, 424 Montgomery Street, San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegener in Columbia from C. B. Miller (for H. S. Homans, General Agent).  Miller tells Daegener that he is enclosing the new book of rates and application forms.  He hopes to hear from Daegener soon "with new business".</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 2, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on a small lined sheet is addressed to "Dear Sir" from T. Wainwright.  Wainwright  says that the scarcity of water has prevented him for washing down the flume, but that he hopes to be able to do so next week.  He hopes also to visit and to pay up in the following week.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 4, 1870.  </unitdate>A handwritten order on letterhead of Wells, Fargo  Co. Express directs that $500 be given to John Millington.  On the reverse, Millington has signed this amount over to Georges Faber, and Faber has added his signature.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 18, 1870.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a scrap of paper indicates that William Daegener paid $179.20 to John Smith (witnessed by P. Smith).</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 21, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of Richards  Harrison, dealers in ales and ports, 708 Sansome Street, San Francisco, is addressed to William Daugener (sic) of Columbia.  The letter acknowledges receipt of Daegener's check for $49.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 24, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in French on letterhead of the French Savings and Loan Society, 411 Bush Street,  San Francisco, is addressed to W. Daegener in Columbia from Gustave Mah, Director.  Mah says he is returning to Daegener via Wells, Fargo  Co. Express his books credited with $152.70 and $10.80, for a total of $163.50.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 6, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of the German Savings and Loan Society, 513 California Street, San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegener in Columbia from George Lette, Secretary.  In answer to Daegener's queries, Lette tells him that the bank's attorney had reported that all bank deposits are subject to state and county taxes.  The bank pays monthly federal taxes at the rate of 1/24 of 1% of deposits, but no state or county taxes.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 6, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of the San Francisco Savings Union, 532 California Street, San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia from John Archbald, Cashier.  Archbald tells Daegener that their bank pays federal tax on all deposits but no state, county or city taxes.  He says their bank does not furnish any information to any state, county or city assessors re taxes.  In a postscript, Archbald brings Daegener's attention to the "enclosed slip", especially because his health will cause him to leave his job immediately for a few months.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 6, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of the Hibernia Savings and Loan Society, 506 Jackson Street, San Francisco, 

is addressed to William Daegener from Edward Martin, Treasurer.  Martin tells Daegener that the county assessor can not assess him on money deposited with Hibernia, since this money is loaned on real estate and therefore exempt, according to the law passed during the last session.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 18, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of R. H. McDonald  Co., druggists, corner of Pine and Sansome Streets, San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegner (sic).  The company tells Daegener they are not responsible for fluctuations in the price of acids.  Nitric acid in the strength Daegener ordered, however, has cost 12 and 1/2 cents for the past 3 months.  They charge him for carboys exactly what the manufacturer charges them.  The company encourages Daegener to "act responsible in this matter and pay the regular price for your acid the same as any one else is willing to pay".</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 19, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined and folded letterhead of Henry G.  Langley, Publisher, 612 Clay Street, San Francisco, with listings and descriptions of his publications on the inside, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia.  Langley tells him he wants to include in the next edition of the <title linktype="simple" inline="true">Pacific Coast Business Directory </title>a list of various cities and towns.  He asks Daegener to fill out the enclosed list for Tuolumne County, paying attention to the information requested in the different columns. Langley says he hopes eventually to get the names and addresses of every businessman and professional on the coast.  He says the enclosed list may not have the name of every locality in Tuolumne County, and he asks Daegener to supply those  that are missing.  Langley pledges to reciprocate at some future time.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 21, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on a scrap of lined paper is addressed to William Daegener from John Taylor  Co.  The letter acknowledges receipt of Daegener's check for $48.20 as full payment.   </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 21, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of Richards  Harrison, dealers in ales and ports, 708 Sansome Street, San Francisco, is addressed to William Dangean (sic) of Columbia.  The company acknowledges receipt of Daegener's check for $79.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 24, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of Redington, Hostetter  Co., druggists, of San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia.  The company quotes prices requested by Daegener -- nitric acid, 12 and 1/2; carboy $2.75; bicarbonate of soda kegs, 6; cream of tartar powder, 35; and 6 dozen crucibles, $2.25. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 25, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined letterhead of Henry G. Langley, Publisher, 612 Clay Street, San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia.  Langley acknowledges receipt of and thanks Daegener for the "partially corrected" list of Tuolumne County and requests the list of business and professional men in his town. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 29, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined and folded letterhead of L. E. Chicard  Co., Starbuck's Building, corner of Levee and Commerce Streets, Stockton, with advertisements of various Stockton businesses on the reverse, is addressed to William Dagner (sic).  The company tells Daegener that the ship with his boxes on it is due in Stockton on Sunday.  Therefore they will be able to send his boxes on to him by the first team going out on Monday morning.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 27, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined paper from San Francisco is addressed to William Dagener (sic), Wells, Fargo  Co. Agent in Columbia, from George A. Hill of Samuel Hill, general agents for Florence sewing machines.  Hill tells Daegener they have repaired instead of replacing the hemmer and have returned it with oil, needles and an invoice for $1.25.  He says Daegener can send $1.40 in stamps instead of $1.25 in coin as payment if he prefers. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 1, 1870.  
</unitdate>A small folded  advertising hand-out printed on rust-colored paper gives the particulars and statistics of the Stockton Savings and Loan Society -- J. M. Kelsey, President; James Littlehale, Cashier; and S. S. Littlehale, Assistant Cashier.  The brochure lists the various kinds of deposits accepted, a statement of assets and liabilities, a history of the society and a list of its financial activities. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 7, 1870.  </unitdate>A printed account sheet from The Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York, made out to William Daegner (sic), Agent at Columbia, shows $845.70 due on August 17 as premium on Daegener's policy #51771.  A printed letter on the reverse from A. B. Forbes, General Agent Pacific Coast, 204 Montgomery Street, San Francisco, is made out to William Daegner (sic) of Columbia.  It informs him that these account receipts must be returned to the San Francisco office by September 5 with unpaid premiums so marked.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 12, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined letterhead of Henry G. Langley, Publisher, 612 Clay Street, San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia.  Langley acknowledges receipt via William S. Hutchinson of the list of merchants in Daegener's locale which Daegener asked Hutchinson to fill in and return.  Langley says he can't understand why Daegener wouldn't furnish the requested information himself and asks for an explanation.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 15, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined letterhead of Henry G. Langley, Publisher, 612 Clay Street, San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia.  Langley acknowledges receipt of Daegener's July 13 letter and thanks him for "explaining" the "misunderstanding".</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 18, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined letterhead of Richards  Harrison, dealers in ales and ports, 708 Sansome Street, San Francisco, is addressed to "Dear Sir".  The company acknowledges receipt of a check for $48.75 and says they will try to ship future orders in stronger packages.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 11, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in purple ink on a scrap of accounting paper is addressed to Dagner (sic) from I. B. Robbins.  Robbins says Daegener's money was sent in two checks before he left home and must be in the post office somewhere.  He will be there the first of the week, and reports he has done as well as expected. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 17, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of The Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York, 204 Montgomery Street, San Francisco, is addressed to William Dagener (sic) from F. W. Eaton (writing on behalf of A. B. Forbes, General Agent for the Pacific Coast).  Forbes, through Eaton, acknowledges receipt of Daegener's letter and its contents.  He notes Daegener's deduction of 5% as his commission, as per agreement with H. S. Homans (former General Agent). However, Homans sold his interest in the company as of January 1.  Forbes himself earns only 1% as his compensation, so he can not allow Daegener the additional 4%.  He does offer to pay him two years' commission on all renewal business.  If this is agreeable to Daegener, Forbes will send him $42.25 and ask for a receipt.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 22, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of the S. F. Savings Union, 532 California Street (corner of Webb), San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegener from Lovell White, Cashier. White says he is returning Daegener's bank book with the latest dividend recorded in it.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 30, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on lined paper is addressed to William Daegener from A (?) Chanders of Riehn, Hemme  Co.  The letter admits to Daegener that indeed their reassay of bar #8067 does reveal the figure 907, as Daegener had stated.  The company  regrets its error and says they have paid $17 to Daegener's Wells, Fargo  Co. account to cover the difference.  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 7, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter 

handwritten on letterhead of R. H. McDonald, wholesale druggists, corner of Pine and Sansome Streets, San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia from the company.  The letter is a formal bill, telling Daegener he owes $18.50 for merchandise ordered on June 5.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 26, 1870.  </unitdate>A draft of text for a card is handwritten by Daegener on a small sheet of lined paper.  It expressed appreciation to friends in Columbia and vicinity and to teachers and fellow students for their sympathy on the occasion of the death of their daughter Hattie.   The draft is signed in Columbia "Mr. and Mrs. William Daegener". </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">September 26, 1870.  </unitdate>An official printed document (in deteriorating condition), addressed to William Daegener of Columbia, announces the bankruptcy of his creditor, Isaiah Robbins, also of Columbia, and the October 13 date set for the case in Bankruptcy Court.  The document is issued by William Gouverneur Morris, U. S. Marshal. The announcement has been folded, addressed on the reverse to Daegener and postmarked from San Francisco on September 27.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 6, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in French on small letterhead paper of the Caisse d'Epargues Francaise (French Savings and Loan Society), 411 Bush Street, San Francisco, is addressed to Monsieur W. Daegener of Columbia from Gustave Mah, Director.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 7, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten from Santa Cruz on a piece of lined paper is addressed to William Dignar (sic), Secretary of Northern Light Tunnel  Mining Co., from Michael Ward.  The letter asks that Ward's dividends from the Northern Light company be sent to him through Wells, Fargo  Co., minus the cost of "expressage".  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 23, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in German from San Francisco on a small piece of lined paper is addressed to Daegener from F. (Frederick) Issendorf. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 25, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten from Stockton on letterhead of the Stockton Savings and Loan Society is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia from J. Littlehale, Cashier.  Littlehale tells Daegener that his $225 check arrived too late to be collected on this day.  However, presuming that the check is all right, Littlehale has credited it and is returning Daegener's bank book.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 1870.   </unitdate>A letter handwritten from 328 Montgomery Street, San Francisco is addressed to William Daeganer (sic) from Mosheimer  Co.  The company asks Daegener to become their agent for receiving samples of ores for testing or working by the ton.  They charge $3 for each assay (less if a large number of assays are ordered at one time) and $50 to $150 for working each ton or ore.  The company would pay Daegener $1 for each assay and 10% on all other work he might send them as well as 10% for each student he might refer.  They are enclosing a brochure about their company.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 12, 1870.  </unitdate>A dual receipt handwritten on a scrap of lined paper in Columbia indicates that William Daegener owes J. A. S. Trout $2850 and $600.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">November 19, 1870.  </unitdate>A receipt written in Daegener's hand on a scrap of lined paper and torn in half is for $750.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 7, 1870.  </unitdate>A printed receipt from John Taylor  Co. of San Francisco indicates that William Daegener paid the company $27.50.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 8, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in German from San Francisco on lined paper is addressed to Daegener from W. Kroning.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 14, 1870.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in German on small folded lined paper is addressed to Daegener from C. F. Issendorf, S. W. corner of Howard and Beal Streets, San Francisco.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">December 31, 1870.  </unitdate>A printed year-end report of the "business and condition" of the California Trust Company describes services available, 
provides a balance sheet and lists officers, trustees and stockholders.  Henry L. Davis is shown as President and D. W. C. Thompson as Cashier.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 19, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten from Stockton on letterhead of the Stockton Savings and Loan Society is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia from J. M. Kelsey, President.  Kelsey says the society has voted to increase their capital stock (par value $100 per share) from $250,000 to $500,000.  They are particularly interested in having "friends in the mountain towns" buy the new stock, despite the fact that they could sell  all the new stock in the Stockton area alone. If Daegener is interested, Kelsey asks him to fill in the enclosed blank and send it to James Littlehale, Cashier.  In a postscript on the reverse, Kelsey adds that payment will not be required before March 1.  A pencilled note at the bottom suggests that Daegener might have friends interested in purchasing the stock, and therefore blanks are enclosed for them as well.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">January 22, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in German on a small piece of lined paper is addressed to William Dagener (sic) of Columbia from C. F. Issendorf, corner of Howard and Beal Streets, San Francisco.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 7, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of the California Trust Company, 421 California Street, San Francisco and addressed to William Daegener of Columbia from D. W. C. Thompson, Cashier.  Thompson tells Daegener that the company pays 5% interest credited quarterly on average daily balances over $1,000 and under $5,000 and 6% on those over $5,000.  There is no charge for collections,  payments, exchanges or other banking business in San Francisco.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 14, 1871.  </unitdate>A official announcement of an assessment, handwritten on a scrap of lined paper, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia by A. Bullerdieck, Secretary of the Rio Vista Mining Company in Shaw's Flat.  The announcement notifies Daegener that at its February 13 meeting the board of trustees of the company  levied an assessment of $1.25 per share of capital stock, due March 15.  Daegener owes $10 on his 8 shares.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 27, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in German from San Francisco on thin lined paper is addressed to Dangener (sic) from (?) Hess (?).</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 5, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten from San Francisco on letterhead of John Taylor  Co., 512  514 Washington Street, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia.  The company acknowledges receipt of Daegener's $34.75 check as payment in full on his account.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 25, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten from San Francisco on a small sheet of paper is addressed to W. Daegener of Columbia from Amable Gen (?).  In the letter, Gen tells Daegener he just received his letter when he returned to the hotel from a trip into the country.  Since Daegener is willing to modify his terms, Gen will attempt to "get some additional means" either in San Francisco or in Sonora.  He will be in Columbia in a few days and will report to Daegener on his success.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">April 28, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten from San Francisco on small lined paper is addressed to Daegener from C. F. Issendorf.  Issendorf thanks Daegener for the information he supplied about Gus Reye.  He says he would have asked earlier, but Daegener seemed "a little angry" in his last letter and so Issendorf didn't want to bother him.   Issendorf says he has written two or three times to Reye, but has had no answer.  In the last letter, Issendorf offered to settle the matter if Reye would send him $100 by March 15, but Reye did not reply.  Issendorf asks Daegener to "give the mortgage to some lawyer".</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 7, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten from San Francisco on small lined paper is addressed to Daegener from C. F. Issendorf.  Issendorf reports he received a letter from Gus Reye asking 
permission to sell the derrick and reporting that Daegener won't allow Reye to sell it.  Issendorf says he leaves the matter to Daegener's discretion -- providing Reye pays Issendorf $100 and pays Daegener for his time.  Otherwise, Issendorf suggests turning the matter over to a lawyer.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May 10 and 11, 1871.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia and signed by J. S. Nugent, Attorney,  indicates that William Daegener turned over to him a note and mortgage for $150 executed by Augustus Reye in favor of Fred Issendorf.  The note and mortgage was on a mining flume, claim derrick, etc. which was Issendorf's property.  This receipt is attached to a printed "Notice to Creditors" from the U. S. District Court in San Francisco re the bankruptcy case of Isaiah B. Robbins of Columbia, dated May 10.  The notice, addressed to William Daegener of Columbia and signed by A. D. Grimwood, Deputy Clerk, for Edward B. Cotter, Clerk of the U. S. District Court, states that June 13 is the date for Robbins' bankruptcy court hearing.   The notice has been folded and addressed on the reverse to Daegener, stamped with a green 3 stamp and postmarked in San Francisco on May 12.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May, 1871.   </unitdate>A printed exam for Physiology -- First Grade originated in San Francisco and contains seven questions with four parts each.  Each question is valued at five credits.  The questions concern the bones, muscles, skin, heart, lumphatic system, various organs, nervous system, brain and eye.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 1, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in German on small lined paper embossed with J. B. Golly  Co., San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia from Wentzel for Golly  Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 1, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten from San Francisco on letterhead of R. H. McDonald  Co., corner of Pine and Sansome Streets, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia.  The company quotes prices to Daegener, as requested -- nitric acid at 12 per lb.; carboys at $2.75 each; quicksilver at 80 cash; bicarbonate of soda in 112 lb. keg at 6; and borax in 112 lb. case at 25.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 2, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter  handwritten on thin letterhead of Redington, Hostetter  Co., wholesale druggists, of San Francisco is addressed to William Daegener.  The company quotes prices to Daegener, as requested -- nitric acid at 12 and 1/2 per lb.; carboys at $2.75; quicksilver (76 and 1/2 lbs. per flask) at 80; bicarbonate of soda in 112 lb. keg at 5 and 1/2; and borax in 50 lb. box at 27.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 5, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on half a lined sheet of letterhead from Florence Sewing Machines, 19 Montgomery Street South, Grand Hotel Building, San Francisco, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia from George A. Hill (writing on behalf of Samuel Hill, Agent).  Hill acknowledges receipt of Daegener's letter containing $1 and says they are sending herewith the Florence needles as ordered.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 5, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of Richards  Harrison, 314  316 Battery Street, San Francisco, is addressed to William Daugner (sic).  The company acknowledges receipt of Daegener's letter and check for $90 which has been credited to his account.  They tell Daegener that all orders sent him leave their company in perfect condition and that they can not be held responsible for orders which arrive in bad condition due to shipping.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">June 8, 1871.  </unitdate>A bill of sale handwritten in Columbia indicates that Charles Koch, H. Schmidt and N. Jacobi have sold to William Daegener a piece of land and the brick wall on it for $25.  The property adjoins the south side Daegener's lot which is on the west side of Main Street in Columbia.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 22, 1871.  </unitdate>An invoice handwritten in Stockton on lined paper and signed by George J. Ladd, indicates that W. Daegener of Columbia will receive acid, quicksilver and boxes worth a total of 
$4.85.  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 28, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten in German on small lined letterhead of S. Zickel, 19 Dey Street, New York, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 16, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on letterhead of Richards  Harrison, 314  316 Battery Street, San Francisco is addressed to William Daugner (sic).  The company acknowkedges receipt of Daegener's letter and $90 check.  They report they have part of a shipment of superior Worthingtons ale left, and suggest Daegener telegraph them if he wants some as "there is great demand for it".</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 16, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten from San Francisco on small lined letterhead of The Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York, is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia from Eaton (writing on behalf of A. B. Forbes, General Agent for the Pacific Coast).  Forbes says they can not accept Daegener's draft for $803.50 to pay his premium as it is $42.20 short.  (Daegener deducted this amount as 5% due him as per his agreement with Mr. Homans.) Forbes asks Daegener to refer to his letter of August 17, 1870 (see above).  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 17, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten on thin letterhead of Redington, Hostetter  Co. of San Francisco is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia.  The company says it did indeed receive Daegener's $93.10 check.  They are at a loss to explain why it was not acknowledged.  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 22, 1871.  </unitdate>A letter handwritten from San Francisco on two lined pages of letterhead of The Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York is addressed to William Daegener from Eaton (writing on behalf of A. B. Forbes, General Agent).  Forbes charges Daegener is "complicating the company with the transactions of Mr. Homans".  When Forbes bought out Homans' interest in the company, he did not assume the various arrangements Homans had made with his agents.  He did, however, agree to pay several agents 2 years' renewals out of his own pocket -- hoping to collect same from Homans at some future date -- as he had suggested to Daegener in his letter of August 17, 1870.  Forbes says he hopes Daegener will reconsider this offer.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 28, 1871.  </unitdate>A terse letter handwritten from San Francisco on small letterhead of The Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia from Eaton (writing on behalf of A. B. Forbes, General Agent).  Forbes encloses the receipt for Daegener's 2-year renewal commission on his policy and asks him to sign and return it.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 31, 1871.  </unitdate>A  letter handwritten from San Francisco on small letterhead of The Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York is addressed to William Daegener of Columbia from Eaton (writing on behalf of A. B. Forbes, General Agent).  Forbes acknowledges Daegener's letter and encloses his requested receipt.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">February 10.  </unitdate>A handwritten invoice/receipt indicates that William Daegener paid J. L. Haslam $10.83 for 261 lbs. of potatoes (@ 3 a pound), ordered on this date.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">March 15.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt indicates that William Daegener paid S. C. Morse $40 for work done at his claim and mill in Sugarpine.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 2.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten in Columbia on a small piece of lined blue paper indicates that William Daegener, Treasurer, received $250 from Murty Gargan for the account of the Northern Light Tunnel Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 17.  </unitdate>A printed bill from The Mutual Life Insurance Company of New York, 204 Montgomery Street, San Francisco, A. B. Forbes, General Agent, is made out to William Daegner (sic) of Columbia.  It informs him that his premium of $845.70 on policy #51771 is due on this date.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>Susie S. Nourse has handwritten a poem of eight stanzas entitled "Seaweed" by Henry W. Longfellow on three pages of  
folded blue paper. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a small piece of lined paper indicates that John C. Hale was paid $50 by William Daegener for 200 bushels of charcoal.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>A note handwritten on a small piece of accounting paper and signed by M. H. White, Secretary, directs the Treasurer of the Enterprise Q. M. Company to pay  $130.50 to Charles McLannake (?).</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>A note handwritten on a small piece of lined paper and signed by M. H. White, Secretary, directs the Treasurer of the Enterprise Quartz Mining Company to pay $51.90 to A. Fletcher  Co.  The note is signed on the reverse by A. Fletcher  Co.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>An invoice/receipt, handwritten on a piece of lined paper, indicates that N. S. Morrill was paid $10 by William Daegener for work, soda and lumber incurred between June 6 and 9.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>A note, handwritten on a small piece of paper and signed by John Fahey and by Murty Gargan, President, directs the Treasurer of Northern Light Mining and Fluming Co. to pay William Kinsby $4.62 and 1/2.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>A small lined sheet contains a list of names and the amount of assessment no. 5 which each paid, ranging from $11 to $209 (H. Piley) and totalling $704.00.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>A piece of blue accounting paper contains a list of names and corresponding amounts, totalling $689.50.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>Two pieces of lined white paper, joined in the upper left corner contain lists of names and corresponding amounts on the first page and various columns of figures on the second.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>A small piece of paper contains three figures added together to total $2,738.35 without explanation. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>A handwritten receipt indicates that C. Harigan received $250 from William Daegener for two shares in the Rio Vista  G.  S. Mining Co. claim situated on Austrian Hill.</item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>A handwritten letter from A (?) Chanders of Riehn, Hemme  Co. is addressed to William Daegener.  The company admits an error in assay on bar #8936 and says there is a balance due of $1.89.  They claim they forgot the "special rates" agreed upon with Daegener and charged him the regular 1/8 of 1% instead.  </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>A receipt handwritten on a scrap of lined paper indicates that the justice's, constable's and witness fees plus hearing costs (totalling $23.8) in the Justice's Court case of William Daegener vs. J. Labusthe have been paid.  The receipt was signed by James McGowen, Township Constable.  The receipt appears to have been used as scratch paper for adding some columns of figures. </item>
        <item><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">Undated.  </unitdate>A printed notice "To Capitalists and Miners" from Mosheimer  Co., 328 Montgomery Street, San Francisco, suggests ways to invest and make money in mining and outlines the areas of instruction taught in their mining school and metallurgic works.</item>
      </list>
    </scopecontent>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
