<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924"><eadid identifier="011294849">bak00044</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Bank of the United States (1791-1811). Boston Branch (Boston, Mass.) Records, 1792-1794 (inclusive): A Finding Aid</titleproper></titlestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">10/25/2007</date>Tim Mahoney</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><frontmatter><titlepage><num>Mss:781 1792-1794 U58</num><titleproper> Bank of the United States (1791-1811). Boston Branch (Boston, Mass.) Records, 1792-1794
(inclusive): A Finding Aid</titleproper><author>Baker Library</author><p><extptr xlink:href="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HUL.OIS:hbs_shield" xlink:type="simple" /></p><publisher>Harvard Business School, Boston, MA 02163</publisher><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 2007</date><p>© 2007 President and Fellows of Harvard College</p></titlepage></frontmatter><archdesc level="collection"><did><repository><extref xlink:href="http://www.library.hbs.edu/hc/" xlink:type="simple">Baker Library, Harvard Business School</extref></repository><unitid>Mss:781 1792-1794 U58</unitid><origination><corpname>Bank of the United States (1791-1811). Boston Branch (Boston, Mass.)</corpname></origination><unittitle>Bank of the United States (1791-1811). Boston Branch (Boston, Mass.) records, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1792-1794 (inclusive)</unitdate></unittitle><physdesc><extent>3 linear ft. (2 vols.)</extent></physdesc><abstract>Two volumes of financial records, dated 1792-1794, of the Boston branch of the first Bank of the United States (1791-1811.) </abstract></did><processinfo><p>Processed: <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 2006</date></p><p>By: <persname role="processorFirst name">Kristy Sharpe</persname></p></processinfo><acqinfo><head>Provenance: </head><p>Presented by the New England Historical Genealogical Society. Original   Gift of Mr. Edward H. Gleason, vice president of the Merchants National Bank of Boston.</p></acqinfo><accessrestrict><p>Appointment necessary to consult collection.</p></accessrestrict><prefercite><head>Preferred Citation</head><p>Cite as: Bank of the United States (1791-1811). Boston Branch (Boston, Mass.) Collection, Baker Library, Harvard Business School.</p></prefercite><altformavail><p>Both v.1  Ledger, April 1792-November 1793, and v.2 Discount bill book, August 1793-November 1794, are available as <extref xlink:href="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HBS.Baker.AC:1473974" xlink:type="simple">digital surrogates</extref>.</p></altformavail><bioghist><head>Historical Note: </head><p>The first Bank of the United States was chartered by Congress in 1791. Alexander Hamilton was the guiding force behind the creation of the bank, which he envisioned  as a central bank for the new United States. Modeled after the Bank of England, the bank began accepting subscriptions at its  Philadelphia headquarters in 1791. The bank's charter authorized 25,000 shares at $400 each, which raised $10 million in capital. The federal  government owned 5,000 shares, while the remaining 20,000 shares were tendered in initial public offering.  The Bank of the United States would hold a 20 percent share in the country’s money supply, while private banks accounted for the rest.</p><p>Subscriptions for the Bank of the United States were soon in high demand throughout the country. In cities beyond Philadelphia, subscriptions were accepted at local banks. However, the need for  local branches of the  Bank of the United States soon became apparent.  Branches were subsequently opened in Boston, Baltimore, Charleston, and New York. Positions on the local boards of directors, which were chosen by the Philadelphia board, were eagerly sought by local business leaders.</p><p>In  Massachusetts, subscriptions for the bank were initially  accepted at the Massachusetts Bank.  The Boston branch of the Bank of the United States took over this role when it  was established in 1792. Four Boston branch board members—Peter Roe Dalton, Christopher Gore, Jonathan Mason, Jr., and Thomas Russell—had previously served on the Massachusetts Bank board. Dalton, who served as  cashier of the Boston branch for  nearly twenty years, formerly held the same position at the Massachusetts Bank. These relationships helped the  Boston branch and the Massachusetts Bank to avoid an adversarial relationship that other branches shared with their state banks.</p><p>A number of prominent American businessmen had accounts with the Boston branch of the Bank of the United States. They  include Ebenezer Storer, Thomas Amory, Oliver Wendell, John Kean (who was also the  cashier of the Philadelphia branch of the bank,) Nathaniel Appleton, Samuel Breck, Samuel Otis, and John Coffin Jones, among others.</p><p>Although successful, the first Bank of the United States had many enemies, whose fears included corruption, financial manipulation, and speculation. As a result of the controversy, Congress declined to renew the bank's  charter in 1811.  All branches were forced to liquidate their affairs and pay off their stockholders.</p></bioghist><scopecontent><head>Scope and Content Note:</head><p>The collection consists of two volumes, dating from 1792 to 1794.</p><p>Volume one is a ledger that  includes account information for individuals, businesses, state and national offices that did business with the Boston branch of the first Bank of the United States. The entries, which  date from April 1792 to November 1793, record general banking activities such as deposits, withdrawals, and balance information. 
 
There are large blocks of pages missing from the front and back of the volume. The ledger begins with page 74 and ends with page 271.</p><p>Volume two is a discount bill book for the Boston branch, which dates from  August 5, 1793  to November 6, 1794. Discounts, which was the term used for bank loans, were approved twice weekly when the branch's board of directors met to judge the bills. Borrowers, usually merchants,  brought  their trade receipts, or bills of exchange, to be discounted. The borrower would expect to receive a payment for goods shipped, and would present paper drawn on the buyer of his goods to the bank. The bank, in turn, would discount the paper at the current rate and the merchant would receive specie (gold or silver) or bank notes as payment at a discounted rate. The bill was also required to contain two responsible names for endorsements.  Entries were made on  Monday and Thursday. Each entry lists the following information: date, number of days to be paid, promissor, to whom payable, second endorser, by whom presented, time when due, number of days discounted, amount each, of note, when discharged, discount, sum to be paid. 
 
</p></scopecontent><dsc type="in-depth"><head>Detailed Description of the Collection</head><c level="item"><did><container>v.1</container><unittitle>Ledger, April 1792-November 1793 </unittitle></did><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HBS.Baker.AC:1473974" xlink:show="new" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Click here to view digital surrogate.</p></daodesc></dao></c><c level="item"><did><container>v.2</container><unittitle> Discount bill book, August 1793-November 1794 </unittitle></did><dao xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HBS.Baker.AC:1473974" xlink:show="new" xlink:type="simple"><daodesc><p>Click here to view digital surrogate.</p></daodesc></dao></c></dsc><controlaccess><head>Additional catalog entries</head><p>The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection.  
An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic 
databases.  THIS IS NOT AN INDEX.</p><p>Authors</p><corpname>Bank of the United States (1791-1811). Boston Branch (Boston, Mass.)</corpname><p>Subjects</p><corpname>Bank of the United States (1791-1811). Boston Branch (Boston, Mass.)</corpname><corpname>Bank of the United States (1791-1811).</corpname><subject>Amory, Thomas, 1762-1823</subject><subject>Appleton, Nathaniel, 1731-1798</subject><subject>Breck, Samuel</subject><subject>Jones, John Coffin</subject><subject>Kean, John, 1756-1795</subject><subject>Otis, Samuel</subject><subject>Storer, Ebenezer</subject><subject>Wendell, Oliver, 1733-1818</subject><subject> Finance.</subject><subject>Banks and banking</subject><subject>Banks and banking--Massachusetts</subject><genreform>Ledgers</genreform><geogname>Boston (Mass.)</geogname></controlaccess></archdesc></ead>
