<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924"><eadid identifier="009132315">ajp00015</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Arnold Arboretum. Records of James Russell Lowell Memorial Park (Cambridge, Mass.) (1995-1996): A Finding Aid</titleproper></titlestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">06/18/2003 </date> Jessica M. Parr </creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20060517">June 8, 2006</date><item>ajp00015 converted from EAD 1.0 to 2002 by v1to02.xsl (sy2006-06-08).</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><frontmatter><titlepage><num>VI LMP </num><titleproper>Arnold Arboretum. Records of James Russell Lowell Memorial Park (Cambridge,
Mass.) (1995-1996): A Finding Aid </titleproper><author>Archives of the Arnold Arboretum of Harvard University</author><p><extptr xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:3007484" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple" /></p><publisher>Harvard University</publisher><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> June 2003 </date><p>© 2003 President and Fellows of Harvard College</p></titlepage></frontmatter><archdesc level="collection"><did><unitid>VI LMP</unitid><repository>Arnold Arboretum Archives of Harvard University, Jamaica Plain, MA 02130.</repository><origination><corpname role="originator">Arnold Arboretum</corpname></origination><unittitle> Records, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1995-1996</unitdate></unittitle><physdesc><extent>2 Linear
Inches </extent></physdesc></did><processinfo><p>Processed: <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> June 2003 </date></p><p>By: <persname role="processor">Jessica M. Parr </persname></p></processinfo><acqinfo><p>These records were collected as part of a discussion involving the Arnold
Arboretum in the restoration of the James Russell Lowell Memorial Park. The HOLLIS catalog
number is # 009132315 and this file is ajp00015.</p></acqinfo><accessrestrict><p>Researchers seeking to examine archival materials are strongly encouraged
to make an appointment. The Director, or an office of origin, may place restrictions on the use of
some or all of its records. The extent and length of the restriction will be determined by the
Director, office of origin, and the Archivist and will be enforced equally for all researchers.	</p></accessrestrict><userestrict><p>The copyright is held by The President and
Fellows of Harvard College for the Arnold Arboretum Archives of Harvard University. The
copyright on some materials in the collection may be held by the original author or the author's
heirs or assigns.	Researchers are responsible for obtaining written permission from the
holder(s) of copyright and the Arnold Arboretum Archives prior to publishing any quotations or
images from materials in this collection. </p><p>Photocopies may be made at the discretion of
the Arnold Arboretum Archives staff. Permission to make photocopies does not constitute
permission to reproduce or publish materials outside the bounds of the fair use guidelines. </p></userestrict><bioghist><p> Lowell Memorial Park (Cambridge, Mass.) was created in 1898 as a memorial to
James Russell Lowell, who was born in Cambridge, Massachusetts on February 22, 1819. An
1838 graduate of Harvard College, Lowell succeeded Henry Wadsworth Longfellow as a
Professor of Modern Languages and Literature at Harvard in 1855. Lowell also served as editor
of the Atlantic Monthly (1857-1862) and the North American Review (1863-1872). He was
American minister to Spain for 3 years (1877-1880) and ambassador to England (1880-1885). In
addition to his teaching and diplomatic service, Lowell was the composer of several sonnets and
hymns. He died on August 12, 1891 and is buried in Mount Auburn Cemetery in Cambridge,
Massachusetts. The park, which is located at the end of Brattle Street in Cambridge,
Massachusetts, encompasses 140,000 square feet of land behind the area where James Russell
Lowell's estate once stood. It is held in trust by the Metropolitan District Commission. </p></bioghist><scopecontent><p> These records include copies of the original deed and
correspondence from the park's creation. Also included is some contemporary correspondence
regarding the park. In addition, there are recent color photographs of the park taken by <persname>Gary Koler</persname>, an Arnold Arboretum horticulturalist, and a folder with a
small amount of biographical material on James Russell Lowell. </p><arrangement><p>The
Collection is organized into one alphabetical sequence.</p></arrangement></scopecontent><dsc type="in-depth"><c><did><unitid>1. </unitid><unittitle> Background Information, Lowell Memorial Park, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">ca. 1898</unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>2. </unitid><unittitle>Biographical Information, James Russell Lowell, </unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1819-1891</unitdate></did></c><c><did><unitid>3. </unitid><unittitle>Correspondence (National Park Service; MA
Metropolitan District Commission) Olmsted National Historic Site, </unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1996</unitdate></did></c><c><did><unitid>4. </unitid><unittitle>Photographs,</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">ca. 1995</unitdate></did></c><c><did><unitid>5. </unitid><unittitle>State Archives, n.d.</unittitle></did></c></dsc></archdesc></ead>
