<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924"><eadid identifier="008911492">ajp00034</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Boston Parks Department. Records of the Boston Parks Department, (1890-1995)</titleproper></titlestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">08/05/2003</date>Jessica M. Parr</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20060517">June 8, 2006</date><item>ajp00034 converted from EAD 1.0 to 2002 by v1to02.xsl (sy2006-06-08).</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><frontmatter><titlepage><num>I A-6</num><titleproper>Boston Parks Department. Records of the Boston Parks Department,
                (1890-1995)</titleproper><author>Archives of the Arnold Arboretum of Harvard University</author><p><extptr xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:ARB.JPLIB:3007484" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple" /></p><publisher>Harvard University, Cambridge, MA 02138 </publisher><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">August 2003</date><p>© 2003 The President and Fellows of Harvard College</p></titlepage></frontmatter><archdesc level="collection"><did><repository>Arnold Arboretum Archives of Harvard University, Jamaica Plain, MA
                02130.</repository><unitid>I A-6</unitid><unittitle>Records,</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">(1890-1995)</unitdate><origination label="originator"><corpname role="originator">Boston Parks Department</corpname></origination><physdesc><extent>4 linear in, 1 box</extent></physdesc></did><note><p>Access to Finding Aid record in <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://hollisclassic.harvard.edu/F/?func=find-cCCL_TERM=sys=008911492" xlink:show="new" xlink:type="simple">Hollis Classic</extref> or <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://holliscatalog.harvard.edu/?itemid=|library/m/aleph|008911492" xlink:show="new" xlink:type="simple">Hollis</extref>.</p></note><otherfindaid><p><extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://arboretum.harvard.edu/wp-content/uploads/I_A-6_BPC_2012.pdf" xlink:show="new" xlink:type="simple">Current version of this finding aid</extref> is available at the <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://arboretum.harvard.edu/library/archive-collection/" xlink:show="new" xlink:type="simple">Archives of the Arnold Arboretum of Harvard
                    University</extref>. </p></otherfindaid><processinfo><p>Processed by: Lisa Pearson</p><p>July 2001</p></processinfo><acqinfo><p>In 1872 it was proposed that the Arboretum be combined with the Boston Parks System,
                with the hope that the lands would be protected from encroachment, taxation and
                seizure by eminent domain. These records were created as a result of the Arboretum's
                involvement in that process. The HOLLIS # for this collection is 008911492 and the
                file name is ajp00034.</p></acqinfo><accessrestrict><p>Researchers seeking to examine archival materials are strongly encouraged to make an
                appointment. The Director, or an office of origin, may place restrictions on the use
                of some or all of its records. The extent and length of the restriction will be
                determined by the Director, office of origin, and the Archivist and will be enforced
                equally for all researchers.</p></accessrestrict><userestrict><p>The copyright is held by The President and Fellows of Harvard College for the Arnold
                Arboretum Archives of Harvard University. The copyright on some materials in the
                collection may be held by the original author or the author's heirs or assigns.
                Researchers are responsible for obtaining written permission from the holder(s) of
                copyright and the Arnold Arboretum Archives prior to publishing any quotations or
                images from materials in this collection.</p><p>Photocopies may be made at the discretion of the Arnold Arboretum Archives staff.
                Permission to make photocopies does not constitute permission to reproduce or
                publish materials outside the bounds of the fair use guidelines.</p></userestrict><bioghist><p>The Arnold Arboretum was founded in 1872 according to the will of James Arnold on
                land willed to the Harvard College by Benjamin Bussey. Very soon after, the director
                Charles S. Sargent engaged Frederick Law Olmsted to begin planning the design of the
                grounds. At the same time it was proposed that the Arboretum be combined with the
                Boston Parks System, with the hope that the lands would be protected from
                encroachment, taxation and seizure by eminent domain. The plan was approved by the
                Boston City Council in December 1881 and ratified by the Boston parks commissioners
                and the president of Harvard College in 1882. The plan called for the College to
                sign the title of the land over to the City of Boston and the City to lease the land
                back to Harvard for $1 per year for 1000 years with the lease renewable at that
                time. The City retained lease to the land that was to be made into the Arboretum
                driveways. They also agreed to spend $75,000 to construct those driveways. They were
                to provide policing and promised not to tax the lands or allow any encroachments on
                the property. Harvard agreed to maintain the Arnold and Bussey trusts, maintain the
                living collections and open the grounds to the public at reasonable times.</p></bioghist><scopecontent><p>The bulk of the materials consist of administrative papers relating to the
                interaction between the Arnold Arboretum and the Boston Parks Department, including
                general correspondence, and correspondence relating to the acquisition of the South
                Street tract and the installation of donations canisters. In addition there are
                several folders of copies of historical papers, including a copy of the indenture of
                1882 between the City and Harvard College</p></scopecontent><dsc type="in-depth"><c level="series"><did><unittitle>I: Correspondence</unittitle></did><note><p>Correspondence mainly between the Directors of the Arnold Arboretum,
                            <persname>Karl Sax, </persname>and <persname>Richard A.
                            Howard,</persname> and the Commissioners of the Boston Park Department,
                        who where <persname>John J. Murphy</persname> until 1949, <persname>Frank R.
                            Kelley</persname> until 1957, <persname>Martin F. Walsh</persname> until
                        1963, <persname>William J. Devine </persname>until 1967, <persname>John J.
                            Tierney</persname> until 1970, <persname>Joseph E. Curtis</persname>
                        until 1974, <persname>Anthony Forgione</persname> until 1975, Peter Meade
                        until 1977.</p></note><c level="file"><did><unitid>Folder 1: </unitid><unittitle>1948-1950.</unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence between Karl Sax and John J. Murphy, then
                                Frank R. Kelley.</unittitle></did><note><p>Content includes building a road, specifically to the top of Peter's
                                Hill, snow removal at the Arnold Arboretum, repairing macadam paths
                                at the Arnold Arboretum, signage, dealing with drought, and
                                repairing walls.</p></note></c></c><c level="file"><did><unitid>Folder 2: </unitid><unittitle>1951-1955.</unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence between Karl Sax and Frank R.
                                Kelley.</unittitle></did><note><p>Content includes fences in and around the Arnold Arboretum, signage,
                                a road to the top of Peters Hill, parking permits, the removal of
                                some <subject>Dutch Elm Disease</subject> infected Elms, the
                                building of a garage on Walter St., keeping arboretum gates locked
                                and in good condition, and other general maintenance needs.</p></note></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondents include Casey, Kelley, O'Keefe, Pigeon, Sax,
                                Schwarten.</unittitle></did><note><p>1 letter from Thomas F. Casey of the Boston Police Department to Sax
                                concerning the policing of the Arnold Arboretum after dark, 1 letter
                                from Kelley to Rose Dopoyan of Milton High School and 1 letter from
                                Kelley to E. F. Pigeon of Medford High School, both granting
                                permission to park a bus in the arboretum parking lot, and 1 letter
                                from Arthur J. O'Keefe to <persname>Lazella Schwarten</persname> of
                                the Herbarium and Library in Cambridge concerning the naming of
                                Peters Hill.</p></note></c></c><c level="file"><did><unitid>Folder 3: </unitid><unittitle>1957-1965.</unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence between Howard and Kelley, then Walsh, then
                                Devine.</unittitle></did><note><p>Content includes repairing benches, persecuting plant thieves, times
                                that the gates are locked, driving permits, illegal dumping in the
                                Arnold Arboretum, a memorial to <persname>Grace S.
                                    Batchelder,</persname> the Arnold Arboretum becoming a
                                    <subject>National Historic Site,</subject> and vandalism within
                                the grounds. 1 letter from Kelley to captain John F. McElhinney of
                                the Boston Police Department concerning police protection of the
                                Arnold Arboretum, 1 letter to Howard from Joseph F. McLaughlin,
                                Editor of "Tell it to Joe" concerning a complaint about cars in the
                                Arnold Arboretum and 1 response to him from Howard, 2 letters from
                                devine to <persname>Truman W. Eustis III</persname> regarding money
                                left for the Arnold Arboretum in the will of Grace S. Batchelder, 1
                                letter from Howard to Edwin W. Small concerning the Arnold Arboretum
                                becoming a National Historic Site.</p></note></c></c><c level="file"><did><unitid>Folder 4: </unitid><unittitle>1966-1970.</unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence between Howard and Devine, then Howard and
                                Tierney in 1967, then Curtis in 1970.</unittitle></did><note><p>Contents include vandalism by the "Shot Brothers," putting in a fence
                                to keep out trash, lewd conduct of drivers within the Arnold
                                Arboretum, a gift of spruce trees given by <persname>Peter L.
                                    Hornbeck,</persname> repairing or replacing the Arborway
                                entrance, <corpname>Arboretum Visiting Committee</corpname> meeting,
                                disposing of debris, parking permits, general maintenance of paths,
                                roads, fences, gates, signs and water sources, protection of
                                visitors and their property, 1 letter from Devine to Captain
                                Cornelius F. O'Brien concerning vandalism at the Arnold Arboretum, 1
                                letter from Mayor of Boston John F. Collins to Howard and 1 response
                                letter from Howard regarding the development of an Anti-Poverty
                                Program, 1 letter from Peter L. Hornbeck, Assistant Professor of
                                Landscape Architecture to Tierney, 1 letter from John J. Tierney to
                                F. B. Jackson concerning a new service building.</p></note></c></c><c level="file"><did><unitid>Folder 5: </unitid><unittitle>1971-1977.</unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondence Between Howard and Curtis until 1974, then
                                Forgione until 1975, then Meade.</unittitle></did><note><p>Contents include discussions of a bicycle path, general maintenance
                                as well as repairs of damages as a result of heavy snow, and a plan
                                to repair the driveways and paths of the Arnold Arboretum.</p></note></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondents include Cosgrove, Howard, Leahy,
                                Moulton.</unittitle></did><note><p>1 letter from Marti F. Cosgrove, chief engineer, to Howard concerning
                                a guard rail along the street, 1 letter from Howard to Mr. Donald C.
                                Moulton concerning building a pedestrian walkway, 1 letter from
                                Howard to <persname>Dean Richard Leahy</persname> concerning repairs
                                to driveways, paths, fences, and gates.</p></note></c></c><c level="file"><did><unitid>Folder 6: </unitid><unittitle>1978-1983.</unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Correspondents include Ashton, Berenson, Howard, Marks, Shaw,
                                Stone.</unittitle></did><note><p>Correspondence between Howard and <persname>Robert G.
                                    Stone,</persname> then <persname>Peter S. Ashton</persname> and
                                    <persname>O. M. Shaw,</persname><persname>Paul F. Perkins,</persname><persname>Wendy Marks,</persname> and <persname>Paul S.
                                    Berenson.</persname></p></note></c></c></c><c level="series"><did><head>II: Annual Reports</head><note><p>Photocopies of the sections pertaining to the Arnold Arboretum</p></note></did><c level="file"><did><unitid>Folder 1: </unitid><unittitle>Boston Parks Department annual reports, 1880-1889</unittitle></did></c><c level="file"><did><unitid>Folder 2: </unitid><unittitle>Boston Parks Department annual reports, 1890-1900</unittitle></did></c></c><c level="series"><did><unittitle>III: Administrative Papers</unittitle></did><c level="file"><did><unittitle>Maintenance</unittitle></did><note><p>photocopies</p></note><c level="item"><did><unitid>Folder 1: </unitid><unittitle>Expenditures for maintenance, 1943-1976,</unittitle></did><note><p>digest and photocopies of original City documents</p></note></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>Folder 2: </unitid><unittitle>Contract and specifications for grading for the Arnold
                                Arboretum, 1890</unittitle></did></c></c><c level="file"><did><unittitle>South Street Tract </unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unitid>Folder 1: </unitid><unittitle>Acquisition of the South Street Tract, 1992-1995,
                                    <genreform>correspondence,</genreform><genreform> maps</genreform> and proposals</unittitle></did></c></c><c level="file"><did><unittitle>Admissions</unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unitid>Folder 1: </unitid><unittitle>Voluntary admissions canisters, 1979-1983, correspondence,
                                design specifications</unittitle></did></c></c><c level="file"><did><unittitle>General Reports  Records</unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unitid>Folder 1: </unitid><unittitle>Report of the Common Council on the Arnold Arboretum, 1881,
                                photocopy</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>Folder 2: </unitid><unittitle>Petition of the Taxpayers of Boston for the Arnold Arboretum,
                                1881</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>Folder 3: </unitid><unittitle>Indenture between the City of Boston and Harvard College,
                                1882, copy</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>Folder 4: </unitid><unittitle>Landscape restoration of the Olmsted Parks, 1995</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>Folder 5: </unitid><unittitle>Rules and guides, n.d.</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>Folder 6: </unitid><unittitle>General papers, 1892-1990</unittitle></did></c></c></c></dsc></archdesc></ead>
