<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://hul.harvard.edu/ois/xml/xsd/oasis/ead2002/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924"><eadid identifier="011822780">mus00022</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Harold Fielding, Ltd. Contracts and correspondence for productions of Frank Loesser's Hans Anderson, 1974-1978: Guide.</titleproper></titlestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">04/08/2009</date>Sarah Adams</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><frontmatter><titlepage><num>Ms. Coll. 129</num><titleproper>Harold Fielding, Ltd. Contracts and correspondence for productions of
Frank Loesser's Hans Anderson, 1974-1978: Guide</titleproper><author>Eda Kuhn Loeb Music Library, Harvard College Library</author><p><extptr xlink:href="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HUL.OIS:fas_shield" xlink:type="simple" /></p><publisher>Harvard University, Cambridge MA 02138</publisher><p>© 2009 The President and Fellows of Harvard College</p></titlepage></frontmatter><archdesc level="collection"><did><repository>Eda Kuhn Loeb Music Library, Harvard College Library</repository><unitid>Ms. Coll. 129</unitid><physloc>Merritt Room </physloc><unittitle>Harold Fielding, Ltd. Contracts and correspondence for productions of Frank
Loesser's Hans Anderson: Guide</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1974-1978</unitdate><physdesc><extent>1 box</extent></physdesc><abstract>This collection consists of contracts, memorandums, and letters relating to
Harold Fielding's stage production of Frank Loesser's musical <title xlink:type="simple">Hans Anderson </title>which opened in London on December 17, 1974.</abstract></did><processinfo><head>Processed by: </head><p>Sarah Adams</p></processinfo><userestrict><p>Access to the collection is unrestricted.</p></userestrict><scopecontent><head>Scope and Content</head><p>The collection contains contracts that specify terms of engagement and related paperwork, including letters, and memorandum, relating to Harold Fielding's production of <title xlink:type="simple">Hans Andersen, </title>
        which opened at the London Palladium on 17 Dec 1974 and ran for 383 performances. A revival opened in London on 17 Dec 1977 and closed on 28 Feb 1978.  Includes contracts signed by Alyn Ainsworth, Willougby Goddard, Sally Ann Howes, Milo O'Shea, Albin Pahernik, and Anthony Valentine. 
        The stage musical was based on the 1952 screen musical <title xlink:type="simple">Hans Christian Andersen, </title>
        produced by Sam Goldwyn and including music and lyrics by Frank Loesser.</p></scopecontent><bioghist><head>Historical Note</head><p>In 1952 lyricist and composer Frank Loesser was hired by film producer Samuel Goldwyn to write the songs for his movie <title xlink:type="simple">Hans Christian Andersen, </title>
    starring Danny Kaye in the title role. Though critics did not hold the screenplay in high regard, they praised Loesser's score and Kaye's performance.
    In 1974, five years after her husband's death, Loesser's widow, Jo Sullivan, was instrumental in bringing about a stage version of the work, titled <title xlink:type="simple">Hans Andersen, </title>
        at the Palladium in London. Though drawing on a book by TOmmy Steele and Beverly Cross, it was based on Goldwyn's movie. Loesser's songs were retained, with additional songs by Marvin Laird.
        Produced by Harold Fielding (in association with Louis Benjamin), and directed by Freddie Carpenter, the cast included Tommy Steele as
        Hans Andersen, Colette Gleeson as Jenny Lind, Milo O'Shea as Otto Pedersen, Bob Todd as Meisling and Lila Kaye as Madame Meisling. The musical was revived
        at the Palladium on 17 Dec 1977, with Tommy Steele as Hans Andersen, Sally Ann Howes as Jenny Lind, Anthony Valentine as Otto Pedersen, and Lila Kaye as Madame Meisling.
     
    </p><p>Harold Fielding (1916-2003) was one of the foremost producers of stage musicals in Britain from the 1950s to the 1980s. After some success
        as an orchestral and concert promoter he made his first foray into musical theater in 1958 with a staged version of Rodgers and Hammerstein's 
        <title xlink:type="simple">Cinderella </title> at the London Coliseum. Among his most successful theater productions were the original <title xlink:type="simple">Half a Sixpence </title>
        (1963), <title xlink:type="simple">Charlie Girl </title> (1965), the London versions of <title xlink:type="simple">Sweet Charity </title> (1967), and <title xlink:type="simple">Mame </title>
        (1969). </p></bioghist><controlaccess><head>Controlled Access </head><p>The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics
documented in this collection. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line
Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated databases. </p><corpname>Harold
Fielding, Ltd.</corpname><persname>Loesser, Frank, 1910-1969</persname><persname>Ainsworth, Alyn</persname><persname>O'Shea, Milo, 1926-</persname><persname>Valentine, Anthony</persname><persname>Howes, Sally Ann</persname><persname>Pahernik, Albin</persname><persname>Goddard, Willoughby</persname><persname>Hart, Moss, 1904-1961</persname></controlaccess><dsc type="in-depth"><head>Container List</head><c><did><unittitle>Ainsworth, Alyn.</unittitle></did><c><did><unitid>(1)</unitid><unittitle>Signed agreement between <corpname>Harold Fielding Ltd.</corpname>
                and <persname>Alyn Ainsworth, </persname>signed<unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1 Oct 1974, </unitdate> engaging 
                the recipient as Musical Director in the play <title xlink:type="simple">Hans Andersen </title> at the London Palladium. </unittitle><physdesc><extent>2s.</extent></physdesc></did><note><p /></note></c><c><did><unitid>(2)</unitid><unittitle>Signed agreement between Harold Fielding, Ltd. and Alyn Ainsworth, signed <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">14 Oct 1974.</unitdate></unittitle><physdesc><extent>1s. </extent></physdesc></did><note><p>Agreement is with regard to Ainsworth's schedule and the scheduling of rehearsals.</p></note></c><c><did><unitid>(3)</unitid><unittitle>T.L.s. from Dick Katz of M.A.M. Agency to Harold Fielding, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">11 Feb 1974. </unitdate></unittitle><physdesc><extent>1s.</extent></physdesc></did></c></c><c><did><unittitle>Goddard, Willoughby .</unittitle></did><c><did><unitid>(1)</unitid><unittitle>Esher Standard Contract for London Theatres between <corpname>Harold Fielding Ltd.</corpname>
                and <persname>Willoughby Goddard, </persname>signed <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">25 Oct 1974, </unitdate> engaging the artist to rehearse and play the part of "Colonel Guldberg" in the play <title xlink:type="simple">Hans Andersen. </title></unittitle></did><note><p>Several related documents are attached to the contract including an addendum dated 25 Oct 1974 and an amendment operative from 6 Mar 1974.</p><p>There is an additional copy of this contract, unsigned.</p></note></c><c><did><unitid>(2)</unitid><unittitle>T.L. from M.J. Fielding to Willoughby Goddard, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">25 Oct 1974</unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(3)</unitid><unittitle>A.L.s. from Willoughby Goddard to Harold Fielding, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">12 Dec 1974. </unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(4)</unitid><unittitle>Memorandum from Ian Bevan of Harold Fielding, Ltd.,  to the company's contract department regarding Goddard's contract, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">25 Oct 1974.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(5)</unitid><unittitle>Signed contract addendum, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">20 Jan 1975. </unitdate></unittitle><note><p>Agreement is with regard to scheduling of rehearsals and Goddard's billing. Additional copy of </p></note></did></c><c><did><unitid>(6)</unitid><unittitle>T.L.s. from Joyce Edwards of Representation Joyce Edwards to Ian Bevan at Harold Fielding, Ltd., <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">18 Feb 1975. </unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(7)</unitid><unittitle>T.L.s. from Joyce Edwards of Representation Joyce Edwards to Ian Bevan at Harold Fielding, Ltd., <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">27 Aug 1975. </unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(8)</unitid><unittitle>Note relaying phone message from Mrs. Fielding, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">9 Sep 1975. </unitdate></unittitle></did></c></c><c><did><unittitle>Howes, Sally Ann.</unittitle></did><c><did><unitid>(1)</unitid><unittitle>Esher Standard Contract for London Theatres between <corpname>Harold Fielding Ltd.</corpname>
                and <persname>Sally Ann Howes, </persname>signed<unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1 July 1977, </unitdate> and engaging the artist to rehearse and play the part of Jenny Lind in the play <title xlink:type="simple">Hans Andersen. </title></unittitle></did><note><p>An additional copy of the contract is signed on behalf of Howes by the President of All Media Management.</p><p>Related documents are attached to the contract including an addendum dated 19 Nov 1974 and an amendment operative from 6 Mar 1974.</p></note></c><c><did><unitid>(2)</unitid><unittitle>Memorandum from Ian Bevan of Harold Fielding, Ltd., to the company's contract department regarding Howes; contract. <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" /></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(3)</unitid><unittitle>Note from 'Hilary' relaying phone message from Charles Lubar to unknown recipient, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> 4 Mar 1978.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(4)</unitid><unittitle>T.L. from G.M. Keighley at Harold Fielding, Ltd., to Fraser and Dunlop, Ltd., regarding Howes' contract, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">22 Mar 1978.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(5)</unitid><unittitle>T.L. from G.M. Keighley at Harold Fielding, Ltd., to Charles Lubar, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">5 Oct 1978.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(6)</unitid><unittitle>T.L.s., from Charles Lubar to G.M. Keighley,  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">28 Sep 1978.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c></c><c><did><unittitle>Wells, Tony. </unittitle></did><c><did><unitid>(1)</unitid><unittitle>T.L.s., from Louis Benjamin, Managing Director of Moss Empire Limited to Harold Fielding, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" /></unittitle></did><note><p>Letter is in regard to engaging the services of Tony Wells as Public Relations Officer.</p></note></c></c><c><did><unittitle>O'Shea, Milo, 1926- .</unittitle></did><c><did><unitid>(1)</unitid><unittitle>Esher Standard Contract for London Theatres between <corpname>Harold Fielding Ltd.</corpname>
                and <persname>Milo O'Shea, </persname>signed <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">19 Nov 1974, </unitdate> engaging the artist to rehearse and play the part of "Otto Pedersen" in the play <title xlink:type="simple">Hans Andersen. </title></unittitle></did><note><p>Several related documents are attached to the contract including an addendum dated 19 Nov 1974 and an amendment operative from 6 Mar 1974.</p></note></c><c><did><unitid>(2)</unitid><unittitle>T.L. M.J. Fielding for Harold Fielding, Ltd., to Milo O'Shea, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">28 Oct 1974.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(3)</unitid><unittitle>Memorandum from Ian Bevan of Harold Fielding, Ltd., to the company's contract department regarding O'Shea's contract. <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" /></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(4)</unitid><unittitle> T.L.s. from Hugh J. Alexander of International Artistes Representation to Ian Bevan at <corpname>Harold Fielding, Ltd. </corpname><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> 28 Nov 1974.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(5)</unitid><unittitle>T.L.s. from Milo O'Shea to Harold Fielding, Ltd., <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">10 Dec 1974.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c></c><c><did><unittitle>Pahernik, Albin.</unittitle></did><c><did><unitid>(1)</unitid><unittitle>Esher Standard Contract for London Theatres between <corpname>Harold Fielding Ltd.</corpname>
                and <persname>Albin Pahernik, </persname>signed<unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">8 Oct 1974, </unitdate> and engaging the artist as a chorister in the play <title xlink:type="simple">Hans Andersen. </title></unittitle></did><note><p>Related documents are attached to the contract including an addendum dated 8 Oct 1974 and an amendment operative from 6 Mar 1974.</p></note></c><c><did><unitid>(2)</unitid><unittitle>A.L.s., from Albin Pahernik to Harold Fielding, Ltd., , <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">20 Dec 1974.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(3)</unitid><unittitle>T.L., from the Director of the production fo Albin Pahernik, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">16 Dec 1974.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c></c><c><did><unittitle>Valentine, Anthony. </unittitle></did><c><did><unitid>(1)</unitid><unittitle>Esher Standard Contract for London Theatres between <corpname>Harold Fielding Ltd.</corpname>
                and <persname>Anthony Valentine, </persname>signed<unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1 Jul 1977, </unitdate> and engaging the artist to rehearse and play the part of Otto in the play <title xlink:type="simple">Hans Andersen. </title></unittitle></did><note><p>Several related documents are attached to the contract including an addendum dated 1 Jul 1977 and an amendment operative from 6 Mar 1974.</p></note></c><c><did><unitid>(2)</unitid><unittitle>Memorandum from Ian Bevan of Harold Fielding, Ltd., to the company's contract department regarding Valentine's contract. <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" /></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(3)</unitid><unittitle> T.L.s. from Anthony Valentine to <corpname>Harold Fielding, Ltd. </corpname><unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">18 Jul 1977.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c><c><did><unitid>(4)</unitid><unittitle>T.L.s. from David White Associates to Ian Bevan of Harold Fielding, Ltd., regarding Valentine's contract,  <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">25 Jul 1977.</unitdate></unittitle></did></c></c></dsc></archdesc></ead>
