<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="file:///C|Program%20Files/SoftQuad/XMetaL%202/display/ead2002.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924"><eadid identifier="006473303">law00115</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Harvard Law School. Moot Court Records, 1825-1873: Finding Aid</titleproper></titlestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">5-25-2004</date>Erica
Bicchieri</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><frontmatter><titlepage><num>HOLLIS 6473303</num><titleproper>Harvard Law
School. Moot Court Records, 1825-1873: Finding Aid</titleproper><author>Harvard Law School Library, Cambridge, MA 02138</author><p><extptr xlink:href="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HUL.OIS:hls_shield" xlink:type="simple" /></p><publisher>Harvard Law School</publisher><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">May, 2004</date><p>© 2004 The
President and Fellows of Harvard College</p></titlepage></frontmatter><archdesc level="collection"><did><head>Summary
Information</head><repository label="Repository:">Harvard Law School
Library, Harvard University.</repository><physloc label="Location:">Harvard Depository</physloc><unitid label="System No.:">HOLLIS 6473303</unitid><origination label="Originator:"><persname>Harvard Law
School</persname></origination><unittitle label="Title">Moot Court
Records, 
<unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1825-1873</unitdate></unittitle><physdesc label="Quantity:"><extent> 24 volumes in 2 Paige
boxes</extent></physdesc><abstract label="Abstract:">This
collection consists of handwritten notes of moot court cases taken by
students. Notebooks were kept either by individual students or by
groups. There are also several volumes of docket lists.</abstract></did><processinfo><p>Processed by <persname role="processor">Erica
Bicchieri, </persname>2002. Edited by Ed Moloy, May 2004.</p></processinfo><acqinfo><p>Contact Curator of Modern Manuscripts and
Archives.</p></acqinfo><accessrestrict><p>Access to these papers
is governed by the rules and regulations of the Harvard Law School
Library. This collection is open to the public, but is housed
off-site at Harvard Depository and requires 2 business-day advance
notice for retrieval. Consult the Special Collections staff for
further information. </p></accessrestrict><userestrict><p>The
Harvard Law School Library holds copyright on some, but not all, of
the material in our collections. Requests for permission to publish
material from this collection should be directed to the Special
Collections staff. Researchers who obtain permission to publish from
the Harvard Law School Library are also responsible for identifying
and contacting the persons or organizations who hold copyright. </p></userestrict><scopecontent><p>This collection contains records of
Moot Court cases argued at Harvard Law School between the years 1825
and 1873. The collection is made up of three distinct groups of
material. The first consists of what may be considered to be
“official” records of Moot Court cases, which appear to have been
kept collectively by classes of students. Most entries include the
faculty members serving as justices for each case. Presiding judges
are indicated in the container list. The volumes in this group cover
the years 1845 to 1873, excluding the years 1828-1831, 1834-1841 and
1853. The second group consists of records kept by individual
students who observed or participated in the Moot Court cases. The
volumes in this group cover the years 1832-1833, 1836-1839,
1845-1846, 1848, 1848, and 1860. The third consists of docket lists
of cases heard in the Moot Court each term between 1838 and 1868.
Volumes of Moot Court records include docket lists, transcriptions of
statements of facts, briefs, and judges decisions. </p></scopecontent><arrangement><head>Series List</head><list><item>
Series I: <unittitle>“Official” Volumes of Moot Court
Records</unittitle><note><p>The volumes are arranged
chronologically. </p></note></item><item> Series II: 
<unittitle>Moot Court Records Kept by Individual Students</unittitle><note><p>The volumes are arranged chronologically.</p></note></item><item> Series III: Moot Court Docket Lists</item></list><note><p> Within each series and/or subseries individual items or
folders are identified by box and folder number. For example, the
number 5-12 corresponds to box 5, folder 12.</p></note></arrangement><bioghist><head>Historical/Biographical
Information</head><note><p>Moot court cases were argued as part of
the Harvard Law School curriculum from the 1820’s until 1897.
Professor Stearns instituted the practice in the first years of the
Law School, when the student body averaged only a dozen students.
During the mid-1820’s the students generally held over 30 moots over
the course of the school year, with each case lasting two to three
hours.</p><p> Under Professors Story, Ashmun and Greenleaf, the moot
courts became even more central to the curriculum. Moots were held
once a week, usually on Friday afternoons; in later years, as the
number of students at the Law School grew, the frequency increased to
two or three times each week. The professor wrote a statement of
facts the week before a case was to be heard, and two counsel were
assigned to each side, one from the Senior class and one from the
Junior class. Each student at the school was assigned to a case in
rotation according to class standing. Every student present,
regardless of his role, took detailed notes on the proceedings, often
transcribing in full the statement of facts, the briefs and the
judge’s opinion. Professor Story presided over many of the moots.
Many of the cases he gave out had been or were to be argued before
him in the U.S. Circuit or Supreme Court. Professor Greenleaf also
presided over moots, and he often gave out cases that arose before
him in the Massachusetts Supreme Court. Cases given out by Story
generally focused on subjects like commercial law, agency, and
equity, while those given out by Greenleaf were more varied.</p><p>
During the 1850’s, moots continued to be of great importance at the
Law School. They were generally held twice each week, and the cases
were often actual ones that were pending or had been recently
decided. Lawyers from Boston would often attend these sessions to
take notes on the proceedings. However, in the years immediately
preceding the Civil War interest in the moots decreased, as did their
frequency. </p><p> Under the leadership of Christopher Columbus
Langdell, the utility of the moot court system was questioned. With
the extension of the program of study to three years, professors were
already overburdened, and in November 1879 the Law School faculty
voted to suspend the moots for the rest of the year. In 1880, rather
than abolishing them completely, the faculty made the moots a
voluntary exercise, and began to hold only four per year. Interest in
the faculty-sponsored moots continued to wane, while participation in
moot courts held by various student law clubs increased. This pattern
continued until the faculty decided to discontinue the moot court
system. The last moot was held on March 10, 1897. </p></note></bioghist><controlaccess><head>Additional Index Terms</head><p>The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations,
and topics documented in this collection. An entry for each appears
in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other
automated bibliographic databases. THIS IS NOT AN INDEX.</p><persname>Allen, Frederick Hunt</persname><persname>Ashmun, John
Hooker, 1800-1833</persname><persname>Bradley, Charles
Smith</persname><persname>Franklin, Dexter, 1793-1857</persname><persname>Cushing, Luther Stearns, 1803-1856</persname><persname>Green, Nicholas St. John, 1830-1876</persname><persname>Greenleaf, Simon, 1783- 1853</persname><persname>Holmes,
Nathaniel, 1815-1901</persname><persname>Langdell, C.C. (Christopher
Columbus), 1826-1906</persname><subject>Law--Study and
teaching--united states</subject><persname>Loring, Edward Greely,
1802-1890 </persname><subject>Mock trials</subject><subject>Moot
courts</subject><persname>Parker, Joel, 1795-1875</persname><persname>Parsons, Theophilus, 1797-1882</persname><persname>Stearns, Asahel, 1774-1839</persname><persname>Story,
Joseph, 1779-1845</persname><persname>Sumner, Charles,
1811-1874</persname><persname>Washburn, Emory, 1800-1877</persname></controlaccess><dsc type="in-depth"><head>CONTAINER LIST</head><c id="law00115s1" level="series"><did><head>Series I: </head><unittitle>“Official” Volumes of Moot Court
		Records</unittitle><note><p>Paige Box 1</p></note></did><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1825-[1828]. Presiding judge: Stearns. (John Cochrane Park,
		 LLB 1826, kept records for 1825-1826)</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1832-1833. Presiding judges: Story, Ashmun</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1842. Presiding judges: [Story, Greenleaf]</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1842-1845. Presiding judges: Story, Greenleaf</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1845-1847. Presiding judge: Greenleaf</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1848-1849. Presiding judges: Greenleaf, Parker, Parsons,
		 Dexter, Cushing</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1850-1852. Presiding judges: Parker, Allen, Parsons,
		 Cushing</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1854-1855. Presiding judges: Parsons, Parker,
		 Loring</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1854-1857. Presiding judges: Parsons, Loring, Washburn,
		 Parker</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1857-1861. Presiding judges: Parsons, Parker,
		 Washburn</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1866-1871. Presiding judges: Parsons, Parker, Washburn,
		 Holmes, Bradley, Langdell, Green </unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1872-1873. Presiding judges: Holmes, Washburn, Green,
		 Langdell</unittitle></did></c></c><c id="law00115s2" level="series"><did><head>Series II: </head><unittitle>Moot Court Records Kept by Individual Students</unittitle><note><p>Paige Box 2</p></note></did><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1832-1833. Student: John Rand; Presiding judges: Ashmun,
		 Story</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1837-[1839]. Student: John Phelps Putnam (LLB ’39);
		 Presiding judges: Story, Greenleaf</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1836-1837. Student: John Phelps Putnam; Presiding judges:
		 Sumner, Greenleaf, Story</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Fall Term 1839. Student: John Phelps Putnam; Presiding judges:
		 Greenleaf, Story </unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Fall Term 1845 - Spring Term 1846. Student: George S. Hale;
		 Presiding judge: Greenleaf </unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Spring/Fall Terms 1848. Student: Horace Gray;Presiding judges:
		 Greenleaf, Parker, Parsons</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Fall Term 1848. Student: Horace Gray; presiding judges:
		 Parker, Parsons </unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>Spring Term 1860. Student: John Chipman Gray, Jr.; Presiding
		 judges: Parker, Parsons, Washburn</unittitle></did></c></c><c id="law00115s3" level="series"><did><head>Series III: </head><unittitle>Moot Court Docket Lists</unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1838–1846</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unittitle>1847–1867</unittitle></did></c></c></dsc></archdesc></ead>
