<?xml version="1.0" standalone="yes"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader findaidstatus="Completed" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="us-gaatrbr"></eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>
                    <num>RBRL/026/ATFA</num>
                </titleproper>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Richard B. Russell Library for Political Research and Studies</publisher>
                <address>
                    <addressline>Athens, Georgia , 30605</addressline>
                </address>
                <date>2010</date>
            </publicationstmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date>2013-01-15T11:13-0500</date>
            </creation>
            <langusage>English</langusage>
            <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle>American Turpentine Farmers Association Minute Books</unittitle>
            <unitid>RBRL/026/ATFA</unitid>
            <repository>
                <corpname>Richard B. Russell Library for Political Research and Studies</corpname>
            </repository>
            <langmaterial>
                <language langcode="eng"/>
            </langmaterial>
            <physdesc>
                <extent>4.0 volumes</extent>
            </physdesc>
            <unitdate normal="1936/1999" type="inclusive">1936-1999</unitdate>
            <abstract id="ref2" label="Abstract">Judge Harley Langdale of Valdosta, Georgia, along with 900 other men from the Southern turpentine industry established the 
                <extref actuate="onLoad" show="new" title="ATFA" href="http://russelldoc.galib.uga.edu/atfa/">American Turpentine Farmers Association</extref> (ATFA) in March of 1936. ATFA was formed to represent the interests of gum naval stores factors, producers, and dealers in the United States "turpentine belt" (Georgia, Alabama, Florida, South Carolina, North Carolina, Tennessee, Kentucky, Virginia, Mississippi, Louisiana, Texas). Activities of ATFA document the interconnection of land use and environmental stewardship to the broader issues and policies of modern Georgia's rural development. The American Turpentine Farmers Association Minute Books provide the administrative record of the organization. The minute books are available online at 
                <extref href="http://russelldoc.galib.uga.edu/atfa/">http://russelldoc.galib.uga.edu/atfa/</extref>.</abstract>
            <origination label="Creator">
                <persname source="ingest" role="creator">American Turpentine Farmers Association</persname>
            </origination>
        </did>
        <userestrict id="ref4">
            <head>User Restrictions</head>
            <p>Library acts as "fair use" reproduction agent.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <userestrict id="ref5">
            <head>Copyright Information</head>
            <p>Before material from collections at the Richard B. Russell Library may be quoted in print, or otherwise reproduced, in whole or in part, in any publication, permission must be obtained from (1) the owner of the physical property, and (2) the holder of the copyright. It is the particular responsibility of the researcher to obtain both sets of permissions. Persons wishing to quote from materials in the Russell Library collection should consult the Director. Reproduction of any item must contain a complete citation to the original.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <prefercite id="ref6">
            <head>Preferred Citation</head>
            <p>American Turpentine Farmers Association Minute Books, Richard B. Russell Library for Political Research and Studies, University of Georgia Libraries, Athens, Georgia, 30602-1641.</p>
        </prefercite>
        <bioghist id="ref7">
            <head>Historical Note</head>
            <p>Judge Harley Langdale of Valdosta, Georgia, along with 900 other men from the Southern turpentine industry established the 
                <extref actuate="onLoad" show="embed" title="ATFA" href="http://russelldoc.galib.uga.edu/atfa/">American Turpentine Farmers Association (ATFA)</extref> in March of 1936. ATFA was formed to represent the interests of gum 
                <extref actuate="onLoad" show="embed" title="Naval Stores" href="http://www.georgiaencyclopedia.org/nge/Article.jsp?id=h-3549">naval stores</extref> factors, producers, and dealers in the United States "turpentine belt" (Georgia, Alabama, Florida, South Carolina, North Carolina, Tennessee, Kentucky, Virginia, Mississippi, Louisiana, Texas). Activities of ATFA document the interconnection of land use and environmental stewardship to the broader issues and policies of modern Georgia's rural development. The American Turpentine Farmers Association Minute Books provide the administrative record of the organization.</p>
            <p>The minute books are available online at 
                <extref href="http://russelldoc.galib.uga.edu/atfa/">http://russelldoc.galib.uga.edu/atfa/</extref>.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent id="ref8">
            <head>Scope and Content</head>
            <p>Four volumes of meeting minutes produced by the American Turpentine Farmers Association Board of Directors from 1936 to 1999.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement id="ref9">
            <head>Organization and Arrangement</head>
            <p>The volumes are arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <relatedmaterial id="ref10">
            <head>Related Collections in this Repository</head>
                <archref>
                    <unittitle id="RBRL107HPS-ead">Hugh Peterson, Sr. Papers</unittitle></archref>
                <archref>
                    <unittitle id="RBRL012IFB-ead">Iris F. Blitch Papers</unittitle></archref>
                <archref>
                    <unittitle id="RBRL001RBR_C_IX-ead">Richard B. Russell, Jr. Collection</unittitle></archref>
                <archref>
                    <unittitle id="RBRL131JLP_III-ead">John Leonard Pilcher Papers</unittitle></archref>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <separatedmaterial id="ref11">
            <head>Related Collections in Other Repositories</head>
                <extref href="http://www.abac.edu/museum/">
                    <unittitle>American Turpentine Farmers Association Papers, Georgia Agrirama, State Museum of Agriculture, Tifton, Georgia. </unittitle></extref>
                <extref>
                    <unittitle>USDA History Collection, Special Collections of the National Agricultural Library, Beltsville, Maryland.</unittitle></extref>
                <extref href="http://www.libs.uga.edu/media/index.html">
                    <unittitle>J. Aubrey Smith Collection, Walter J. Brown Media Archives and Peabody Awards Collection, University of Georgia Libraries, Athens, Georgia</unittitle></extref>
                <extref>
                    <unittitle>Harley Langdale Papers, The Langdale Company, Valdosta, Georgia.</unittitle></extref>
                <extref href="http://hmfa-maint.libs.uga.edu/hmfa/search">
                    <unittitle>Georgia Forestry Association Papers, Hargrett Rare Book and Manuscript Library, University of Georgia Libraries, Athens, Georgia.</unittitle></extref>
                <extref href="http://hmfa-maint.libs.uga.edu/hmfa/search">
                    <unittitle>Southern Forest Institute Collection, Hargrett Rare Book and Manuscript Library, University of Georgia Libraries, Athens, Georgia.</unittitle></extref>
                <extref href="http://find.sos.state.ga.us/archon/">
                    <unittitle>Georgia Forestry Commission, record group 64, Georgia Department of Archives and History, Atlanta, Georgia.</unittitle></extref>
                <extref href="http://www.georgiahistory.com/containers/2">
                    <unittitle>Naval Stores Collection, MS 2202, Georgia Historical Society, Savannah, Georgia. </unittitle></extref>
        </separatedmaterial>
        <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh">American Turpentine Farmers Association Cooperative.</subject>
            <subject source="ingest">Minutes.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Naval stores industry--Georgia.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Naval stores industry.</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh">Turpentine industry and trade--Georgia.</subject>
        </controlaccess>
        <dsc/>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
