<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://hul.harvard.edu/ois/xml/xsd/oasis/ead2002/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924"><eadid identifier="013375222">sch01412</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Two Girls Working. Two Girls Working Collection, 2002-2011: A Container List</titleproper></titlestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">
10/15/2012 
</date>
Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki
</creation></profiledesc></eadheader><frontmatter><titlepage><num>2012-M173</num><titleproper>Two Girls Working.  Two Girls Working Collection, 2002-2011: A Container List </titleproper><author>Arthur and Elizabeth Schlesinger Library on the History of Women in America</author><p><extptr xlink:href="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HUL.OIS:radcliffe_shield" xlink:type="simple" /></p><publisher>Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study, Harvard University</publisher><address><addressline>Cambridge, Mass.</addressline></address><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 2012</date><p>© 2012 President and Fellows of Harvard College</p></titlepage></frontmatter><archdesc level="collection"><did><unitid countrycode="US" repositorycode="MCR-S">2012-M173</unitid><repository><extref xlink:href="http://www.radcliffe.edu/schles/" xlink:type="simple">Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institute</extref></repository><origination><corpname>Two Girls Working</corpname></origination><unittitle>Two Girl Working Collection, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2002/2011" type="inclusive">2002-2011</unitdate></unittitle><physdesc><extent>.6 linear ft.  </extent><extent>(1+1/2 file boxes)</extent></physdesc><langmaterial>Materials in English.</langmaterial><abstract>Publicity and other printed material about Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing, a collaborative project by Two Girls Working whose principals are Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki.</abstract></did><processinfo><p>Container list: <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">October 2012</date></p><p>By: <persname role="processor">Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki</persname></p></processinfo><acqinfo><p>Accession number: <num>2012-M173</num></p><p>The collection of Two Girls Working was given to the Schlesinger Library in October 2012 by <persname role="donor">Tiffany Ludwig</persname> and <persname role="donor">Renee Piechocki</persname>. </p></acqinfo><accessrestrict><head>Access Restrictions:</head><p>Access.  Unrestricted.  </p></accessrestrict><userestrict><p>Copyright. Copyright in the papers created by  Two Girls Working is held by Two Girls Working LLC, Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki.  Copyright in other papers in the collection may be held by their authors, or the authors' heirs or assigns.</p><p>Copying.  Papers may be copied in accordance with the library's usual procedures.</p></userestrict><prefercite><p>Two Girls Working Collection, 2002-2011; item description, dates. 2012-M173, folder #. Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institute, 
Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.</p></prefercite><bioghist><head>BIOGRAPHY</head><p>Two Girls Working is a collaboration between two artists, Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki.  Between 2001 and 2006, they traveled across the United States asking groups of women to respond to the question: What do you wear that makes you feel powerful?  They talked with more than 500 women and girls, from age four to ninety-two, and from a wide range of backgrounds.  What emerged was a wider dialogue about the expectations and limitations placed upon them by their affiliation with a specific gender, culture, race, class, or profession.  The result was a project called Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing.  The project included the interviews, exhibitions around the country, a book, and a web site.</p></bioghist><scopecontent><head>SCOPE AND CONTENT</head><p>The collection consists of postcards, posters, and other publicity and printed material about Trappings.</p></scopecontent><dsc type="in-depth"><head>INVENTORY</head><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.1.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard
Description: Front image features portraits of Aylin, Jersey City; Louise, Sparta; Susan, Jersey City; and Sarah, Patchogue.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Rob Blackson and Eddie Torres

Title: Bitch School; Artists Explore our Attitudes Towards Strong Women
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Longwood Gallery, Bronx Council on the Arts, 965 Longwood Avenue, Bronx, NY 10459
Start Date: 1/26/2002
End Date: 3/30/2002

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Every person interviewed up until this exhibition was included in the show.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.2.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Flyer
Description: Exhibition flyer produced by Bronx Council for the Arts.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Rob Blackson and Eddie Torres

Title: Bitch School; Artists Explore our Attitudes Towards Strong Women
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Longwood Gallery, Bronx Council on the Arts, 965 Longwood Avenue, Bronx, NY 10459
Start Date: 1/26/2002
End Date: 3/30/2002

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.3.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard
Description: Front image: photograph of exhibition site.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Jeff Waites, Lauren Adams, and Angela Salamanca

Title: LOOM2
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Pittsboro Business Center, Chatham Mills, 480 Hillsboro Street, Pittsboro, NC 27302
Start Date: 4/27/2002
End Date: 5/18/2002

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: New interview sessions in Durham, NC were conducted for this exhibition.  A small selection of participants was included in the exhibition. The site was formerly a clothing label factory.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.4.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard
Description: Front image: lower legs and feet of six women.

Event / Exhibition Type: Solo Exhibition
Curator(s): Content curated by Two Girls Working.

Title: Trappings
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Sussex County Community College, Building B, One College Hill, Newton, NJ 07680
Start Date: 10/19/2002
End Date: 11/23/2002

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: One new interview session was conducted on the day of this exhibition opening.  The exhibition opening and event were a part of the college's Women's Weekend.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.5.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies
Description: Front image: portrait of Claire with interview quote.

Event / Exhibition Type: Solo Exhibition
Curator(s): None.  Selected by a jury who reviewed exhibition proposals.

Title: Trappings
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Durham Arts Council, 120 Morris Street, Durham, NC 27701
Start Date: 12/6/2002
End Date: 1/5/2003

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: The exhibition opening was cancelled due to a terrible ice storm.  A closing reception was hosted instead.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.6.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Print-out from internet
Description: Description from Ricardo Miranda Zuniga's website.  Also included is a photograph of the cart that broadcast the interviews.

Event / Exhibition Type: Public Art
Curator(s): Ricardo Miranda Zuniga

Title: The Public Broadcast Cart, Wireless Park Lab Days
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: City Hall Park, New York, NY 10171
Start Date: 9/19/2003
End Date: 9/20/2003

Funding Notes:  Sponsored by NYCWireless and the Downtown Alliance with funding from Franklin Furnace's Future of the Present Fund.

Other Notes: The web page of the content: www.ambriente.com/wifi/index.php. Two Girls Working were one of many artists who were presented on the Public Broadcast Cart.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.7.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Folded card, two copies
Description: Small images of all 21 Trappings interview sessions are on the front of the card, and a key is on the back.  This postcard is a calendar of upcoming exhibitions, interviews, and residencies.

Event / Exhibition Type: N/A
Curator(s): None.

Title: N/A
Informal Meta Title: Trappings Update

Place: N/A, N/A, N/A 
Start Date: February 2004
End Date: March 2005

Funding Notes: 

Other Notes: This card was mailed to more than 300 people on our mailing list, including all interview session participants.  The purpose was to give people a Trappings calendar, letting them know what we were planning for the year ahead.  It mentions an exhibition at the Yoknapatawpha Arts Council in Oxford, MS that never came to fruition.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.8.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Folded card, two copies; one postcard
Description: Image on front of each card: "Antidote, Fetish, Talisman", 2004. Digital Print and Audio Work

Event / Exhibition Type: Solo Exhibition
Curator(s): Rocio Aranda-Alvarado

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power, and Clothing. An exhibition of print, audio and video By Two Girls Working: Tiffany Ludwig + Renee Piechocki
Informal Meta Title: Jersey City

Place: Jersey City Museum, 350 Montgomery Street, Jersey City, NJ 07302
Start Date: 9/22/2004
End Date: 1/9/2005

Funding Notes: "This exhibition is the result of a residency with the Jersey City Museum funded by the Mid Atlantic Foundation's Artists and Communities grant."

Other Notes: The folded card and the postcard both included the telephone number used to present the audio work that accompanied "Antidote, Fetish, Talisman": 201-413-0303 x 130.  The folded card was sent to our mailing list.  The postcard was dropped off at local coffee shops and art spaces that advertised exhibitions and events.  The museum would not let us print the exhibition opening information, so we put a stamp on the front of the envelope that held the folded card.  Rocio Aranda-Alvarado is a Trappings participant.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.9.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies
Description: Image on front: black and white photograph by Martin Weber.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Ariel Shanberg

Title: Shifting the Political: Portraits of Power
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: The Center for Photography at Woodstock, 59 Tinker Street, Woodstock, NY 12498
Start Date: 11/6/2004
End Date: 12/19/2004

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.10.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Print-out from internet
Description: Event listing from Jersey City List. Describes film screening.

Event / Exhibition Type: Film Screening
Curator(s): Garth Kobal, a man who organized the film series at the church.

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power, And Clothing: Interviews of Women at Grace Church Van Vorst
Informal Meta Title: Jersey City

Place: Film at Grace, Grace Church Van Vorst, 39 Erie Street, Jersey City, NJ 07302
Start Date: 2/18/2005
End Date: 2/18/2005

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Three films were screened that night, "ProArts", "Belly Dancers", and "Grace Seniors", all created in 2004 and first exhibited at the Jersey City Museum exhibition.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.11.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard
Description: Image on front: black and white line drawing of bus, with photographic image insert of artists' prints installed

Event / Exhibition Type: Public Art Installation.  Film Screening.
Curator(s): None.  Content curated by Two Girls Working.

Title: Trappings: Pittsburgh
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Pittsburgh

Place: Pittsburgh City Buses.  Melwood Screening Room, 477 Melwood Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15213
Start Date: 3/1/2005
End Date: 4/3/2005

Funding Notes: Sprout Fund, Pennsylvania Council on the Arts

Other Notes: This postcard promoted both the public installation and video screening. The bus installation lasted from March 1-31, 2005.  The screenings were on March 31st and April 3rd, 2005.  The grant funding was for these public events as well as a series of interview sessions in Pittsburgh.  The bus cards received national recognition from Americans for the Arts' Public Art Network 2005 Year in Review, which noted innovative and exciting public art projects.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.12.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Tri-Fold brochure
Description: Global Women's Voices in Action

Event / Exhibition Type: Artist Residency
Curator(s): None.

Title: Trappings Video Exhibition, Two Girls Working Lecture, Trappings Interview Sessions
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Albion College, 611 East Porter Street, Albion, MI 49224-1831
Start Date: 3/13/2005
End Date: 3/16/2005

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Two Girls Working were artists in residence at Albion College for a week.  This brochure detailed our events and others coordinated for Women's History month.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.13.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies
Description: Front image: "Uruj, Tasseli, Kathleen, Marilyn", 2004

Event / Exhibition Type: Solo Exhibition
Curator(s): None.

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Centennial Gallery, University of Wyoming, 2111 Willett Drive, Laramie, WY 82071
Start Date: 3/22/2005
End Date: 4/9/2005

Funding Notes: UW Cultural Outreach, PACMWA/President's Advisory Committee on Minority and Women's Affairs, UW Art Department, UW Women's' Studies Program.
Other Notes: Two Girls Working were artists in residence at the University of Wyoming for a week.  This postcard detailed our exhibition and lecture.  We also conducted interview sessions during the residency.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.14.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard
Description: Detail of a hook rug.  No credit for image on front.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Maria Elena Buszek

Title: Extra/Ordinary: Fiber Artists Rethinking Art and Everyday Life
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: The Cube at Beco, 1922 Baltimore, Kansas City, MO 64108
Start Date: 5/23/2005
End Date: 7/9/2005

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: In addition to attending the opening on June 3, 2005, we conducted an interview session in Kansas City.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.15.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Publication, literary journal, which includes a complete set of accompanying postcards from the portfolio.
Description: literary journal title: ep;phany: a literary journal. ISBN 0-9749047-0-8.  Cover image is a bird.

Event / Exhibition Type: Publication
Curator(s): Douglas Light, Managing Editor

Title: A portfolio of Trappings by Two Girls Working: Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki.  Title of piece A Cross Country Exploration of Women, Power and Clothing.
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Epiphany Magazine, 244 East Third Street, New York, NY 10009
Start Date: Summer 2005
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.16.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies
Description: Image on front: 3 photographs: Patricia: Nashville, Crystal: Memphis, Dorchelle: Memphis. Produced by the Arts in the Airport program.

Event / Exhibition Type: Public Art Installation
Curator(s): Caroline Carlisle

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing  - The Tennessee Sessions
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Tennessee

Place: Nashville International Airport Concourse C, Nashville, TN 37214
Start Date: 9/6/2005
End Date: 11/27/2005

Funding Notes: Metropolitan Nashville Airport Authority's Arts at the Airport program.
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.17.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies
Description: Four images on front of card showing the installed artwork being seen by airport visitors.  Text includes exhibition title and location.

Event / Exhibition Type: Public Art Installation
Curator(s): Caroline Carlisle

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Tennessee

Place: Nashville International Airport Concourse C, Nashville, TN 37214
Start Date: 9/1/2005
End Date: 11/27/2005

Funding Notes: Metropolitan Nashville Airport Authority's Arts at the Airport program.

Other Notes: This card was designed by Two Girls Working for the same exhibition as Folder #16.  We wanted to have a card made after the installation to distribute nationally to our mailing list that featured photos of the show.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.18.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: 18 page pamphlet
Description: Santa Fe Art Institute's exhibition catalogue.

Event / Exhibition Type: Exhibition
Curator(s): Eileen Torpey

Title: Clothesline: Art, Clothing, Identity
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Santa Fe Arts Institute, 1600 Saint Michaels Drive, Santa Fe, NM 87505
Start Date: 10/1/2005
End Date: 11/15/2005

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Our public lecture with GuerrillaGirlsBroadBand, July 25, 2005 advertised on second to last page.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.19.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Poster
Description:  Poster to promote our lecture.

Event / Exhibition Type: Lecture
Curator(s): Mary Murray

Title:  
Informal Meta Title: 

Place: Pratt at Munson-Williams-Proctor Institute, 310 Genesee Street, Utica, NY, 13502
Start Date: 10/21/2005
End Date:  10/21/2005

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.20.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, one copy.
Description: Front image: detail of Sleeves by Deanna Dikeman.

Event / Exhibition Type: Solo Exhibtion
Curator(s): Kathy Aaron Dowell

Title:  Trappings
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Society for Contemporary Photography,520 Avenida Cesar E Chavez, Kansas City, MO 64108
Start Date: 1/2006 
End Date:  2/18/2006

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: This is the only known card in our possession for this exhibition.  Our installation was a video installation.  It is one of the rare occasions that we did not travel to install the work.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.21.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Newspaper
Description:  The Bell Buckle Echo,  front page article

Event / Exhibition Type: Exhibition
Curator(s): None. Content curated by Two Girls Working.

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing  - The Tennessee Sessions
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Tennessee

Place: Bedford County Arts Council, The Fly Arts Center, 204 South Main Street, Shelbyville, TN 37160
Start Date: 3/9/2006
End Date: 

Funding Notes:

Other Notes: This was the first time we traveled an exhibition and was paid for it.  The show from Nashville International Airport was rented by the Bedford County Arts Council.  We installed the exhibition.  Renting the exhibition became the model for our national, traveling exhibition.  We included this article in this section of the archive since no other exhibition materials exist.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.22.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Publication, photography journal, two copies.
Description: Photography Quarterly #94, Women Seeing Women issue

Event / Exhibition Type: Publication
Curator(s): Ariel Shanberg

Title: A twin-gatefold portfolio by Two Girls Working.  Titled Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing.
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Center for Photography at Woodstock, Woodstock, NY 12498
Start Date: Unsure.  Early 2006.
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.23.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Bi-fold, 8x10
Description: Exhibition brochure. Cover is white with exhibition title and artist credit

Event / Exhibition Type: Launch of National Traveling Exhibition
Curator(s): Jennifer L. Strayer

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Regina Gouger Miller Gallery, Carnegie Mellon University, 5000 Forbes Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15213
Start Date: 7/7/2006
End Date: 8/11/2006

Funding Notes: The Pittsburgh Foundation and The Heinz Endowments.

Other Notes: This bi-fold promotes the first two travelling exhibition sites: Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA and Central Wyoming College, Riverton, WY.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.24.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Poster, two copies.
Description: Poster. Folded. Orange line-drawing silhouettes, photographs of interview sessions, and portraits.

Event / Exhibition Type: Launch of National Travelling Exhibition
Curator(s): Jennifer L. Strayer

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Regina Gouger Miller Gallery, Carnegie Mellon University, 5000 Forbes Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15213
Start Date: 7/7/2006
End Date: 8/11/2006

Funding Notes: The Pittsburgh Foundation and The Heinz Endowments.
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.25.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcards,  three copies
Description: Front image: black and white Riverton street scene with color photographic prints of the artists' works inserted into storefront windows.

Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation and national traveling exhibition
Curator(s): Nita Kehoe-Gadway

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Robert A. Peck Gallery, Central Wyoming College, 2660 Peck Avenue, Riverton, WY 82501
Start Date: 11/1/2006
End Date: 12/13/2006

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Nita Kehoe-Gadway is a Trappings participant.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.26.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Bi-fold, 8x10
Description: Cover is white with exhibition title and artist credit

Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition
Curator(s): Nita Kehoe-Gadway

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Robert A. Peck Gallery, Central Wyoming College, 2660 Peck Avenue, Riverton, WY 82501
Start Date: 10/30/2006
End Date: 12/13/2006

Funding Notes: Funded in part by an award from the National Endowment for the Arts.

Other Notes: This bi-fold promotes the first two travelling exhibition sites: Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA and Central Wyoming College, Riverton, WY.  We also conducted interview sessions during our visit.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.27.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, three copies.
Description: Front image: installation shot of video projection at Carnegie Mellon University.  The postcard promotes upcoming exhibitions and events.

Event / Exhibition Type: N/A
Curator(s): N/A

Title: N/A
Informal Meta Title: Trappings Update

Place: N/A
Start Date: Unknown month, 2007
End Date: 12/31/2007

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.28.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, 2 copies
Description: Front image: white silhouette of a flower on a black background.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Claudia Sbrissa

Title: From the Inside Out: Feminist Art Then  Now
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: St. John's University, Dr. M. T. Geoffrey Yeh Art Gallery, 8000 Utopia Parkway, Queens, NY 11439
Start Date: 2/22/2007
End Date: 4/21/2007

Funding Notes: Queens Council on the Arts and The Feminist Art Project.
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.29.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Exhibition Catalog
Description: 37 page booklet, stapled binding. Artists' work on page 20. Image of 5 portraits installed.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Claudia Sbrissa

Title: From the Inside Out: Feminist Art Then  Now
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: St. John's University, Dr. M. T. Geoffrey Yeh Art Gallery, 8000 Utopia Parkway, Queens, NY 11439
Start Date: 2/22/2007
End Date: 4/21/2007

Funding Notes: Queens Council on the Arts and The Feminist Art Project.

Other Notes: Includes essays by Lori Waxman and Susan Rothenberg.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.30.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Poster, two copies.
Description: image: white silhouette of a flower on a black background, participating artists listed.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Claudia Sbrissa

Title: From the Inside Out: Feminist Art Then  Now
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: St. John's University, Dr. M. T. Geoffrey Yeh Art Gallery, 8000 Utopia Parkway, Queens, NY 11439
Start Date: 2/22/2007
End Date: 4/21/2007

Funding Notes: Queens Council on the Arts and The Feminist Art Project.
Other Notes: 

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.31.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Exhibition Marketing Catalogue
Description: The marketing brochure we designed to rent our national, traveling exhibition.  23 pages, staple bound.

Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition
Curator(s): N/A

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: N/A 
Start Date:  2/2007
End Date: 

Funding Notes: Self-funded.

Other Notes: We designed this brochure after our meeting with the Smithsonian Institution's Traveling Exhibition Service (SITES).  We used their brochures as a model.  Mailed across the country to museums and galleries to seek venues for the show.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.32.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies
Description: Front image: photograph of "Transformation" installed.

Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition
Curator(s): Amy Gipson and Monica McMurray

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Historic Costume Gallery, Lela Raney Wood Hall, 6 N. College Avenue, Stephens College, Columbia, MO 65215
Start Date: 3/11/2007
End Date: 4/22/2007

Funding Notes: Stephens College, Lori Guy of Girl Boutique, Judge Leslie Schneider, and Becky McHugh with the Carlisle Collection.

Other Notes: Two Girls Working were artists in residence at Stephens College for a week.  This postcard detailed our exhibition. We also conducted interview sessions and class visits during the residency.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.33.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Brochure, folded 8x10
Description: Brochure for East Central College Art Department's exhibition schedule.  Cover says "Greeting from the East Central College Art Department"

Event / Exhibition Type: Two Girls Working Artist Residency
Curator(s): Jill Foote-Hutton

Title: Two Girls Working Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki Artist Residency
Informal Meta Title: 

Place: East Central Gallery, East Central College, 1964 Prairie Dell Road, Union, MO 63084
Start Date: 9/17/2007
End Date: 9/21/2007

Funding Notes: East Central College Foundation.

Other Notes: We were in residence for the week, conducting a public lecture and interview sessions.  The residency was organized by Jill Foote-Hutton, Trappings participant.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.34.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Brochure, folded 8x10
Description:  Brochure for East Central College Art Department's exhibition and performing arts schedule.


Event / Exhibition Type: Two Girls Working Artist Residency
Curator(s): Jill Foote-Hutton

Title: Two Girls Working Tiffany Ludwig and Renee Piechocki Artist Residency
Informal Meta Title: 

Place: East Central Gallery, East Central College, 1964 Prairie Dell Road, Union, MO 63084
Start Date: 9/17/2007
End Date: 9/21/2007

Funding Notes: East Central College Foundation.

Other Notes: We were in residence for the week, conducting a public lecture and interview sessions.  The residency was organized by Jill Foote-Hutton, Trappings participant.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.35.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Quad-fold exhibition catalog
Description: Front image: sculpture by May Chan

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Randall Harris

Title: Well Dressed
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Nathan Cummings Foundation, 475 Tenth Avenue, New York, NY 10018
Start Date: 9/27/2007
End Date: 12/14/2007

Funding Notes: Rush Philanthropic Arts Foundation.
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.36.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies.
Description: Front image: digital print by Nick Cave.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Randall Harris

Title: Well Dressed
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Nathan Cummings Foundation, 475 Tenth Avenue, New York, NY 10018
Start Date: 9/27/2007
End Date: 12/14/2007

Funding Notes: Rush Philanthropic Arts Foundation.
Other Notes: 

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.37.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies and poster.
Description: Front Image: Christiane Leach, artist and exhibition curator in an amazing red and purple dress.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Christiane Leach

Title: The Definition of Feminine Power
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Future Tenant: A Space for Art, 819 Penn Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15222
Start Date: 9/28/2007
End Date: 10/19/2007

Funding Notes:  Exhibition funded by the August Wilson Center for African American Culture.
Other Notes: 

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.38.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies
Description: Front image: portraits of Claire, Stephanie, and Vivian.

Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition
Curator(s): Barbara O'Brien

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Trustman Art Gallery, 300 The Fenway, Simmons College, Boston, MA 02115
Start Date: 10/9/2007
End Date: 11/9/2007

Funding Notes: Part of Simmons College's Spinning Straw Into Gold, The Ethics of Production Fall 2007 Exhibition Series.  Funded in part by the LEF Foundation and Catherine Hannah Behrend.

Other Notes: Designed by Simmons College. Two Girls Working were artists in residence at Simmon College for a week.  This postcard detailed our exhibition and panel presentation. We also conducted interview sessions during the residency.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.39.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard
Description: Postcard promoting book publication.  Includes portraits of Linda, Susan, Towana, Erika, and Stephanie.

Event / Exhibition Type: Publication of book by Rutgers University Press.
Curator(s): N/A

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: N/A, N/A, N/A 
Start Date: Book available 10/2007
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Designed by Two Girls Working before the final cover of the book was selected.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.40.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Galley
Description: Pre-publication gallery of book.  Partial ARC, uncorrected, not for resale.

Event / Exhibition Type: 
Curator(s): N/A

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Rutgers University Press, 100 Joyce Kilmer Avenue, Piscataway, NJ 08854
Start Date: Book available 10/2007
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Includes quote by Lucy R. Lippard on the front cover.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.41.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Catalog
Description: Rutgers University Press' fall winter 2007 2008 catalogue promoting new publications

Event / Exhibition Type: Publication of book by Rutgers University Press.
Curator(s): N/A

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Rutgers University Press, 100 Joyce Kilmer Avenue, Piscataway, NJ 08854
Start Date: Book available 10/2007
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Trappings featured on pages 2-3.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.42.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Book,  signed
Description: ISBN:978-0-8135-4184-6

Event / Exhibition Type: Publication by Rutgers University Press.
Curator(s): N/A

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Rutgers University Press, 100 Joyce Kilmer Avenue, Piscataway, NJ 08854
Start Date: 10/2007
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.1.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies
Description: Postcard promoting book publication.  Includes image of the book cover.

Event / Exhibition Type: Publication of book by Rutgers University Press.
Curator(s): N/A

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: 

Place: N/A, Pittsburgh, PA 
Start Date: 11/2007
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: We designed this as our official book postcard once the cover was finalized.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.2.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard
Description: Postcard promoting book publication and signings.  Includes image of the book cover.

Event / Exhibition Type: New Jersey and New York book signings: 11/6/07, 11/7/07, 11/8/07, 11/10/07,11/11/07
Curator(s): N/A

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: Trappings Book Tour

Place: N/A, Pittsburgh, PA 
Start Date: 11/13/2007
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.3.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard
Description: Postcard promoting book publication and signings.  Includes image of the book cover.

Event / Exhibition Type: Pittsburgh book signings: 11/13/07, 11/15/07, 11/17/07.
Curator(s): N/A

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: Trappings Book Tour

Place: N/A, Pittsburgh, PA 
Start Date: 11/13/2007
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.4.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Print out of back of postcard, print of poster
Description: Postcard promoting exhibition and poster included in exhibition window.  The poster includes a photo of the collective Art364B.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group Exhibition
Curator(s): Jennifer S. Musawwir and Jovana Stokic

Title: Art346B: The Collective
Informal Meta Title: 

Place: NYU Windows on the corner of LaGuardia Place and West Third Street, New York, NY 10012
Start Date: 11/7/2007
End Date: 1/16/2008

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Tiffany Ludwig is part of the collective ART364B.  She presented a Two Girls Working photographs and audio works titled "Crystal", "Elizabeth", "Louise", and "Anita" as part of her installation in this group show.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.5.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Quad-fold installation brochure, four copies
Description: Front image: photographs of installation at Midwife Center with installation title "Trappings: Midwife Center".

Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation.
Curator(s): None. Content curated by Two Girls Working.

Title: Trappings: Midwife Center
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Midwife Center

Place: Midwife Center for Birth and Women's Health, 2825 Penn Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15222
Start Date: 11/16/2007
End Date: 11/2011

Funding Notes: The Heinz Endowments and PA Partners in the Arts
Other Notes: The ceiling tiles are still installed at the Midwife Center as of June 2012. The entire project received national recognition from Americans for the Arts' Public Art Network 2008 Year in Review, which noted innovative and exciting public art projects.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.6.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies.
Description:  Front image: artists' rendering of photographic ceiling tile with Marguerite Watson's photo.  The postcard promotes the opening reception for the installation.

Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation.
Curator(s): None. Content curated by Two Girls Working.

Title: Trappings: Midwife Center
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Midwife Center

Place: Midwife Center for Birth and Women's Health, 2825 Penn Avenue, Pittsburgh, PA 15222
Start Date: 11/16/2007
End Date: 11/2011

Funding Notes: The Heinz Endowments and PA Partners in the Arts
Other Notes: The ceiling tiles are still installed at the Midwife Center as of June 2012. The entire project received national recognition from Americans for the Arts' Public Art Network 2008 Year in Review, which noted innovative and exciting public art projects.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.7.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, one copy
Description: Front image: photograph of All City Waitress Marching Band

Event / Exhibition Type: Panel discussion
Curator(s): Carey Lovelace

Title: Making it Together: Women's Collaborative Art + Community
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: The Bronx Museum of the Arts, 1040 Grand Concourse, Bronx, NY 10456
Start Date: 3/2/2008
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Other participants included Wendy Babcox (6+), Uzuma S. Rizvi (Rasa Theater, Visible Collective), Emily Roysdon (LTTR), Faith Wilding (SubRosa), and Carey Lovelace.  Moderated by Amy Mackie, New Museum of Contemporary Art. Carey Lovelace is a Trappings participant.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.8.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Bi-fold, 8x10
Description: Cover is white with exhibition title and artist credit.  Has a sticker on the back with this exhibition's dates and details.

Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition
Curator(s): Jill Foote-Hutton

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: East Central Gallery, East Central College, 1964 Prairie Dell Road, Union, MO 63084
Start Date: 3/12/2008
End Date: 4/4/2008

Funding Notes: East Central College Foundation
Other Notes: This bi-fold promotes the traveling exhibition at East Central College.   The gallery was run by Jill Foote-Hutton, Trappings participant.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.9.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, two copies
Description: Front image: photograph of "Trappings: Participants" installed, with viewers.

Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition
Curator(s): Gail Goldman and Jose Ruiz

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Bronx River Art Center, 1087 East Tremont Avenue, Bronx, NY 10460
Start Date: 3/7/2008
End Date: 4/12/2008

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.10.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Interactive public art clothing label, two copies
Description: A card that hangs on clothing hooks.  Participants fill out label and return to museum.

Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition and Commissioned interactive public art clothing label project.
Curator(s): Lisa Haatchadoorian.

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Nicolaysen Art Museum, 400 East Collins Street, Casper, WY 82601
Start Date: 5/16/08
End Date: 7/27/08

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Clothing label folded in half to fit in this folder.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.11.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Bi-Fold postcard, three copies.
Description: Front image: image of "Trappings: Participants" installed.

Event / Exhibition Type: National Traveling Exhibition and Commissioned interactive public art clothing label project.
Curator(s): Lisa Haatchadoorian

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Nicolaysen Art Museum, 400 East Collins Street, Casper, WY 82601
Start Date: 5/16/08
End Date: 7/27/08

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.12.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Postcard, three copies.
Description: Front image: portraits of La'Tasha D. Mayes, Tweety Paisano-Suazo, Clara Lee Arnold, Cynthia Cook. Back image: Erika Soveranes

Event / Exhibition Type: Multi-part project: national traveling exhibition, and public art project on D-ride buses, billboards, and banners on Central Avenue (Route 66)
Curator(s): Suzanne Sbarge

Title: Trappings: Albuquerque
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Albuquerque

Place: 516 ARTS, D-ride buses, banners on Central Avenue.  516 Arts, 516 Central Avenue, Albuquerque, NM 87102
Start Date: 6/13/2008
End Date: 8/16/2008

Funding Notes: Bernalillo County, City of Albuquerque, Clear Channel Outdoor, The FUNd at Albuquerque Community Foundation, McCune Charitable Foundation, New Mexico Humanities Council.

Other Notes: Two Girls Working were in residence in New Mexico in February 2008, and opened this exhibition in June.  During the residency we produced several interview sessions.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.13.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Tri-fold brochure, two copies.
Description: Front image: image of "Trappings: Participants" installed.

Event / Exhibition Type: Multi-part project: national traveling exhibition, and public art project on D-ride buses and on banners on Central Avenue.
Curator(s): Suzanne Sbarge

Title: Trappings: Albuquerque
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Albuquerque

Place: 516 ARTS, D-ride buses, banners on Central Avenue.  516 Arts, 516 Central Avenue, Albuquerque, NM 87102
Start Date: 6/13/2008
End Date: 8/16/2008

Funding Notes: Bernalillo County, City of Albuquerque, Clear Channel Outdoor, The FUNd at Albuquerque Community Foundation, McCune Charitable Foundation, New Mexico Humanities Council.

Other Notes: These were made specifically to be placed in the D-ride buses to advertise the exhibition and public art installations.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.14.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Program guide, two copies.
Description: 516 Arts Downtown Albuquerque Program Guide, summer 2008

Event / Exhibition Type: Multi-part project: national traveling exhibition, and public art project on D-ride buses and on banners on Central Avenue.
Curator(s): Suzanne Sbarge

Title: Trappings: Albuquerque
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Albuquerque

Place: 516 ARTS, D-ride buses, banners on Central Avenue.  516 Arts, 516 Central Avenue, Albuquerque, NM 87102
Start Date: 6/13/2008
End Date: 8/16/2008

Funding Notes: Bernalillo County, City of Albuquerque, Clear Channel Outdoor, The FUNd at Albuquerque Community Foundation, McCune Charitable Foundation, New Mexico Humanities Council.

Other Notes: Two Girls Working appears on pages 13-15.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.15.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Exhibition brochure, four copies.
Description: Front image: portraits of Latasha, Tweety, Rocio, Stephanie, Cynthia, Susan, Clara Lee, and Erika

Event / Exhibition Type: A new version of the national, traveling exhibition brochure.  Included the republication of the essay "the Power of Two" by Patricia C. Phillips, and a new essay "Trappings: Finding Our Stories, Finding Ourselves" by Dr. Kathy Freise, a Trappings partici
Curator(s): Suzanne Sbarge

Title: Trappings: Albuquerque
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Albuquerque

Place: 516 Arts, 516 Central Avenue, Albuquerque, NM 87102
Start Date: 6/13/2008
End Date: 8/16/2008

Funding Notes: Bernalillo County, City of Albuquerque, Clear Channel Outdoor, The FUNd at Albuquerque Community Foundation, McCune Charitable Foundation, New Mexico Humanities Council.

Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.16.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Copies of exhibition catalogue.
Description: Front image: graphic design of the words "Fe", "in the making", and all of the exhibiting artists names.

Event / Exhibition Type: Group exhibition organized by Jill Larsen at Fe Gallery to celebrate Pittsburgh's 250th anniversary and the breadth of visual art being created in Pittsburgh. We exhibited the video "A Discourse On Power (in Eight Parts) and an installation view of the Mi
Curator(s): Jurors included: Vicky A. Clark, Joey Kennedy, Janet L. McCall, Katherine Talcott, and Michael Olijnyk.

Title: Fe:in the making
Informal Meta Title: 

Place: Fe Gallery, 4102 Butler Street, Pittsburgh, PA 15201
Start Date: 9/12/2008
End Date: 1/10/2009

Funding Notes: Pittsburgh 250 Community Connections and The Sprout Fund funded the exhibition.
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.17.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Photocopy of 3 pages from exhibition catalog.
Description: Title page, overview, artist project page

Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation.
Curator(s): Biljana Ciric

Title: Trappings: Shanghai
Informal Meta Title: Intrude: Art and Life 366 
at Zendai Museum of Modern Art in Shanghai, China

Place: Gynecological exam room at the Meinian Health Center, Shanghai, China,  
Start Date: 10/4/2008
End Date: 12/2008

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Commissioned by the Zendai Museum of Modern Art for their Intrude: Art and Life 366 project.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.18.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Poster
Description: Promotes book-signing, with image of book cover.

Event / Exhibition Type: Lecture and book signing.
Curator(s): N/A

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Carol Woods Assembly Hall, 750 Weaver Dairy Road, Chapel Hill, NC 27514
Start Date: 4/3/2009
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Organized by Jean Parrish, a Trappings participant.
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.19.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Print of gallery label.
Description: A copy of the educational label that was displayed with the artwork.

Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation.
Curator(s): None

Title: Trappings
Informal Meta Title: 

Place: Glen Ridge NJ Transit Train Station, Glen Ridge, NJ 07028
Start Date: 5/6/2009
End Date: 9/4/2009

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: Exhibition organized by an artist group called GRAPA, Glen Ridge Art Patrons Association.

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.20.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: No ephemera for this exhibition.
Description: 

Event / Exhibition Type: National, traveling exhibition.
Curator(s): Hu Monvan and Ashley Atkins

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: None

Place: Johnson  Johnson, One Johnson  Johnson Plaza, New Brunswick, NJ 08933
Start Date: 9/3/2009
End Date: 12/5/2009

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.21.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Exhibition catalog, three copies.
Description: Accordion book

Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation.
Curator(s): Yolanda Sanchez

Title: Trappings: Miami
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Miami

Place: Miami International Airport, MIA Gallery, Central Terminal Gallery, Concourse E, Miami, FL 33126
Start Date: 10/2010
End Date: 2/2011

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 

</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.22.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Print from Two Girls Working website
Description: Description of the exhibition published on our website.

Event / Exhibition Type: Public art installation.
Curator(s): Greta Blalock

Title: Trappings: Stories of Women, Power and Clothing
Informal Meta Title: Trappings: Portland

Place: Portland International Airport, Portland, OR 97208
Start Date: 4/2011
End Date: 10/2011

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: 
</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.23.</unitid><unittitle>Contents: Print of article from website.
Description: A print of the article "Telling stories in the public realm: what has been removed" which appeared on the website nanomajority.

Event / Exhibition Type: Essay.
Curator(s): None.

Title: "Telling stories in the public realm: what has been taken away"
Informal Meta Title: 

Place: www.nanomajority.com/projects/tiffany-ludwig, ,  
Start Date:  4/2011
End Date: 

Funding Notes: 
Other Notes: In April 2011, Art364B, the collective that includes Tiffany Ludwig, had an online exhibition at nanomajority.

</unittitle></did></c></dsc><controlaccess><head>Additional catalog entries</head><p>The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection.  
An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic 
databases.  THIS IS NOT AN INDEX.</p><controlaccess><list><head>Authors</head><item><persname>Ludwig, Tiffany</persname></item><item><persname>Piechocki, Renee</persname></item></list></controlaccess><controlaccess><list><head>Subjects</head><item><subject>Art--Exhibitions</subject></item><item><subject>Artists, American</subject></item><item><subject>Feminism in art--United States</subject></item><item><subject>Group work in art--United States</subject></item><item><genreform>Interviews</genreform></item><item><genreform>Oral histories</genreform></item><item><subject>Power (Social sciences)--United States</subject></item><item><subject>Women--Interviews--United States</subject></item><item><subject>Women--Social conditions--United States</subject></item><item><subject>Women artists--United States</subject></item><item><subject>Women's clothing--United States</subject></item></list></controlaccess></controlaccess></archdesc></ead>
