<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924"><eadid identifier="009451731">sch00389</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard. Records, 1975-2003: A Finding Aid</titleproper></titlestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">07/12/04</date>Jane S. Knowles</creation></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20060517">June 8, 2006</date><item>rca00006 converted from EAD 1.0 to 2002 by v1to02.xsl (sy2006-06-08).</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><frontmatter><titlepage><num>SC 147 
</num><titleproper>Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard. Records, 1975-2003: A Finding Aid</titleproper><author>Radcliffe College Archives, Arthur and Elizabeth Schlesinger Library on the History of Women in America </author><p><extptr xlink:href="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:HUL.OIS:radcliffe_shield" xlink:type="simple" /></p><sponsor>The collection was processed with help from the donors.</sponsor><publisher>Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study, Harvard University</publisher><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">July 2007</date><p>© 2007 President and Fellows of Harvard College</p></titlepage></frontmatter><archdesc level="collection"><did><unitid>SC 147</unitid><repository><extref xlink:href="http://www.radcliffe.edu/schles/" xlink:type="simple">Radcliffe College Archives, Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institute</extref></repository><origination><corpname>Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard</corpname></origination><unittitle>Records, <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1975-2003</unitdate></unittitle><physdesc><extent>5 file boxes</extent></physdesc><abstract>Project files, clippings, minutes, and correspondence of a committee of Radcliffe alumnae dedicated to ending sex discrimination at Harvard</abstract></did><processinfo><p>Processed: <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> 
July 2004</date></p><p>By: <persname role="processor"> 
Jane S. Knowles</persname></p></processinfo><acqinfo><p>Accession number: <num>R2003-7</num></p><p> The records of the Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard were given to the Radcliffe Archives by Alice (Acey) Carbonaro Welch, co-chair, in July 2003. <note><p>The collection was processed with help from the donors.</p></note></p></acqinfo><accessrestrict><head>TERMS OF USE 
</head><p>Access. Unrestricted. </p></accessrestrict><userestrict><p>Copyright. Copyright is held by the President and Fellows of Harvard College for the Radcliffe Archives. Copyright in other papers in the collection may be held by their authors, or the authors' heirs or assigns. Researchers must obtain the written permission of the holder(s) of copyright and the director of the Schlesinger Library before publishing quotations from materials in the collection.</p><p>Copying. Papers may be copied in accordance with the library's usual procedures. </p></userestrict><prefercite><p>Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard  Records, 1975-2003; item description, dates. SC 147,  folder #. Radcliffe College Archives, Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe Institute, 
Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass.</p></prefercite><bioghist><head>HISTORY</head><p>Meeting at their respective reunions, alumnae of the Radcliffe Classes of 1953 and 1958 recalled the discrimination they experienced as students and resolved to advance women's equality at Harvard. First, members of the Radcliffe Class of 1953 formed an Ad Hoc Committee to analyze the status of women at Harvard (1988) and in 1993, joined by members of the Class of 1958, they incorporated as the Committee for Equality of Women at Harvard, with the goals of increasing the number of women tenured faculty and working for equity of all women at the university. Included among the board members were Gabriella P. Schlesinger '58, Alice (Acey) Carbonaro Welch '53, co-chairs, Elizabeth Hatfield '58, Cornelia Dimmitt '58, Margaretta (Peggy) B. Schmertzler '53, Ann R. Shapiro '58, <persname>Eleanor W. Williams '58,</persname><persname>Sunny Yando,</persname><persname>Jane Marx '41, </persname>Nancy Tobin '49, Lilli Hornig, Ph.D '50, Millie Marnin '58, Jane O'Reilly '58, <persname>Deborah Socolar '75,</persname> and <persname>Phoebe Telser '58.</persname> Their organization came to have 2000 Harvard and Radcliffe alumni friends and supporters.</p><p>The Committee members issued annual reports charting the status of women at Harvard and other major research universities and publishing comparative data on numbers of senior women faculty, salary levels of women, supply of women Ph.Ds, and proportion of Harvard women undergraduates. They entered into dialogue with the administration, and lobbied women faculty, nominees for the Harvard Board of Overseers, Harvard and Radcliffe undergraduates, and alumni, and succeeded in gaining broad media coverage for their findings. They instituted the Harvard Woman Junior Fellowship at the Bunting Institute (1993) to help advance the careers of women junior faculty and established an escrow account, the Harvard Women's Faculty Fund (1995), as a means for donors to protest gender inequity while giving to the Harvard campaign.</p><p>They sponsored several student/faculty panels, developed a newsletter, brochures, and publicity material. In 1998 they convened the first national conference that addressed the issues of institutional change required for the full integration of women scholars and students into major research universities. It was sponsored by the <corpname>Ford Foundation</corpname> and the <corpname>Sloan Foundation,</corpname> with additional support from<persname> Albert Gordon '59.</persname> In 1999 and 2000 they petitioned for, but failed to obtain, a self-study similar to the <corpname>Massachusetts Institute of Technology's</corpname> study of gender inequity in the Sciences, and in 2001 they sponsored their own survey of women faculty at Harvard University.</p><p>In June 2000 they released the money in their escrow account to the Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study (the successor to Radcliffe College) and, with <persname>Ellen LaFollette '54</persname> who had raised money from alumnae groups in California, launched a campaign for a joint professorship at the Radcliffe Institute and Harvard's Faculty of Arts and Sciences. With a matching grant from Harvard, they endowed the professorship (2002) and helped endow a new junior faculty fellowship.</p><p>The appointment of <persname>Drew Gilpin Faust</persname> as Dean of the Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study (2001) and installation of a new administration at Harvard (2002) led to more cordial relations with both administrations. The report of the Committee (2003) noted improvement in the status of women faculty and a new focus on sexual assault policy, the development of women's studies, and other issues relating to undergraduate women.</p></bioghist><scopecontent><head>SCOPE AND CONTENT</head><p>Records of the Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard document the advocacy of members of the Radcliffe classes of 1953 and 1958 for improvement in the status of women at Harvard. Reports chart their findings and recommendations, while clippings attest to the breadth of media coverage, including articles in the <title xlink:type="simple">Boston Globe</title>,
<title xlink:type="simple">New York Times</title>, and <title xlink:type="simple">Chronicle of Higher Education</title>. Correspondence illustrates their quest for dialogue with the Harvard administration, and the support received from alumni and friends. Minutes, 1990-2002, and e-mail, 1999-2002, give details of both strategy and on-going projects. Also included are brochures, ads, programs, and photographs of panel discussions, and a proposal, correspondence, and reports relating to the conference, "Women in Research Universities: the Next Quarter Century" (1998), and its proceedings, <title xlink:type="simple">Equal Rites, Unequal Outcomes</title> (2003) edited by Lilli S. Hornig.</p><arrangement><p>The records of the Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard are arranged in two series:</p><list><item> I. Programs</item><item>II. Correspondence</item></list></arrangement><p>Series I, Programs (#1.1-3.6), consists of goals, yearly reports on gender disparity, programs for panels, photographs, conference files and CDs, petitions, and results of faculty survey. Also included are clippings, brochures, ads, and minutes, 1990-2002.</p><p>Series II, Correspondence (#3.7-5.9), of Margaretta (Peggy) Schmertzler, Alice (Acey) Carbonaro Welch, Ann R. Shapiro et al. with Harvard and Radcliffe administration, faculty, alumni, and other friends. Also included are statements of nominees for Harvard's Board of Overseers on the status of women, and e-mail among committee members planning strategy and coordinating future action.</p></scopecontent><dsc type="in-depth"><head>INVENTORY</head><c level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I. PROGRAMS </unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.1.</unitid><unittitle>"Report on the Work of the Ad Hoc Committee on the Status of Women at Harvard/Radcliffe '53, 1989-1993" by the Action Committee, led by members of the Radcliffe College Class of 1953, including <persname>Penny Pendleton Beye,</persname><persname>Holly Thomas Doyle,</persname><persname>Marjorie Hill Moore,</persname> Margaretta (Peggy) Bridgman Schmertzler, Alice (Acey) Carbonara Welch, and <persname>Anne Sears Wilson</persname></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.2.</unitid><unittitle>Brochures, n.d.	</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.3.</unitid><unittitle>Stationery</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.4.</unitid><unittitle>Clippings about the Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard, 1990, 1993-1994</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.5.</unitid><unittitle>Clippings about the Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard, 1995-1996</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.6.</unitid><unittitle>Clippings about the Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard, 1997</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.7.</unitid><unittitle>Clippings about the Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard, 1998-2002</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.8.</unitid><unittitle>Letter from Nancy Tobin to Aida Press, 1975; Ann R. Shapiro's "Remember the Ladies," ca. 1991.</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.9.</unitid><unittitle>Resolution and report (proposed at annual luncheon), re: inequality of women at Harvard, 1993</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.10.</unitid><unittitle>Goals of the Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard, 1993-2001</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.11.</unitid><unittitle>"Update," newsletters, 1994-2002, and sample mailings to alumnae, 1993-2002</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.12.</unitid><unittitle>Reports, letters to alumnae, and petitions with cover letters to President Neil Rudenstine, 1994-2003, including Lilli S. Hornig's "Veritas," 1996</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.13.</unitid><unittitle>Draft proclamation, 1994; Ann R. Shapiro's update on women at Harvard, 1995.</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.14.</unitid><unittitle>Panel discussions on Harvard's hiring practices, 1994-1996, including notes by Nancy Tobin</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.15.</unitid><unittitle>Bunting Harvard Junior Faculty Fellowship, 1994-1996</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.16.</unitid><unittitle>Proposal to establish a Harvard-Radcliffe forum on women's issues, and notes for presentation to Radcliffe College Alumnae Association annual meeting, 1995, by Peggy Schmertzler</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.17.</unitid><unittitle>Articles by Lilli S. Hornig, 1995-1999, n.d., including "Has Equal Opportunity Come of Age?," "Plus Ça Change" by Lilli S. Hornig and Nancy Tobin, "Women Faculty Then and Now: Twenty-five Years of Change," "Thoughts for a New Millenium," and Osep Planning Group, Subcommittee on Graduate Study, draft report, n.d.</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.18.</unitid><unittitle>Ads and press releases, 1995-1999</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.19.</unitid><unittitle>Articles and statements, 1996-1997, including "No More Nice Girls" and "Women and Tenure at Harvard" by members of the Committee for the Equality of Women at Harvard and "Effie" by Alexis Antiphanes</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.20.</unitid><unittitle>Telethon script and tally, 1996</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.21.</unitid><unittitle>Radcliffe College Alumnae Association Council: "Breaking the Barriers: Women's Revolutions and Evolutions," 1996</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.22.</unitid><unittitle>"Choosing to Lead: The Quest for Equality of Women at Harvard," 1996: invitation, program, speakers' biographies, notes, publicity. Also statement by members of the committee, "Choosing to Lead: Resource Development for the Equality of women at Harvard." Includes <genreform>PHOTOGRAPHS.</genreform></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.23.</unitid><unittitle>Radcliffe College Alumnae Association management meeting, Harvard Law School petition re: child care, flyer for sex discrimination meeting at Columbia University, 1997</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.24.</unitid><unittitle>"A Celebration of Women at Harvard," pamphlet, 1997</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.25.</unitid><unittitle>"Women in Research Universities: the Next Quarter Century," correspondence with <persname>Paula Kaplan,</persname> 1996-1997</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.26.</unitid><unittitle>"Women in Research Universities: the Next Quarter Century," correspondence with <persname>Elizabeth Doherty,</persname> 1997</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.27.</unitid><unittitle>"Women in Research Universities: the Next Quarter Century," correspondence with the<corpname> Ford Foundation,</corpname> 1997-1998</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.28.</unitid><unittitle>"Women in Research Universities: the Next Quarter Century," conference programs, forms</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.29.</unitid><unittitle>"Women in Research Universities: the Next Quarter Century," reports on break-out groups</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>1.30.</unitid><unittitle>"Women in Research Universities: the Next Quarter Century," summary and recommendations, 1998</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.1.</unitid><unittitle>"Women in Research Universities: the Next Quarter Century," conference packet</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.2.</unitid><unittitle>"Women in Research Universities: the Next Quarter Century," conference proceedings, 10 CDs. </unittitle></did><note><p>REQUEST AS R-32.</p></note></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.3v.</unitid><unittitle>"Women in Research Universities: the Next Quarter Century," conference book, <title xlink:type="simple">Equal Rites, Unequal Outcomes</title> (Kluwer, 2003)</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.4.</unitid><unittitle>Reunion meetings, flyers, 1999-2002</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.5-2.7.</unitid><unittitle>Petition to President Rudenstine asking for self-study on the status of women at Harvard, 2000 </unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.8.</unitid><unittitle>Radcliffe Alumnae Professorship, 2000-2001, including terms of endowment fund, disbursement of escrow funds, and deed of gift signed by Dean <persname>Drew Gilpin Faust</persname></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.9.</unitid><unittitle>"Reinventing the Wheel," 2001, and history of Women's Center, n.d.</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.10.</unitid><unittitle>Faculty survey, 2001, by Cornelia Dimmitt includes 47 anonymous replies out of 340 faculty surveyed and statement by<persname> Dorothy Zinberg;</persname> also draft follow-up letter, 2002.</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.11.</unitid><unittitle>Reports and studies about sexual assault policy, 2002</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>2.12.</unitid><unittitle>Minutes of meetings, 1990-1993</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>3.1.</unitid><unittitle>Minutes of meetings, 1994</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>3.2.</unitid><unittitle>Minutes of meetings, 1995-1996</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>3.3.</unitid><unittitle>Minutes of meetings, 1997-1998</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>3.4.</unitid><unittitle>Minutes of meetings, 1999</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>3.5.</unitid><unittitle>Minutes of meetings, 2000</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>3.6.</unitid><unittitle>Minutes of meetings, 2001-2002, n.d.</unittitle></did></c></c><c level="series"><did><unittitle>Series II: CORRESPONDENCE</unittitle></did><c level="item"><did><unitid>3.7.</unitid><unittitle>1988-1994, with <persname>Linda S. Wilson,</persname><persname>Jeremy Knowles,</persname><persname>Ruth Perry,</persname><persname>Joan Del Pozzo;</persname> also includes Peggy Schmertzler's "Towards a More Humane Society: Let Us Bring Anne Radcliffe Out of the Tower" (1988) and Ann R. Shapiro's questions for <persname>Linda S. Wilson.</persname></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>3.8.</unitid><unittitle>1995, with <persname>Daphne Abeel,</persname><persname>Dudley Herschbach,</persname><persname>Jerry Green,</persname><persname>Joseph J. McCarthy,</persname><persname>Sarah E. Wald, </persname>and <persname>Robert Waggoner</persname></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>3.9.</unitid><unittitle>Jan–Mar 1996, with <persname>John Kenneth Galbraith</persname> and <persname>Claire Lipsman</persname></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>3.10.</unitid><unittitle>Apr–Dec 1996, with <persname>John Kenneth Galbraith,</persname><persname>Carolyn Shaw-Bell,</persname><persname>Maurine Rothschild,</persname><persname>Joanne Tozzer Cave,</persname> Neil Rudenstine, <persname>Florence Ladd,</persname><persname>Alice H. Eagley,</persname> and <persname>Mary Dunn</persname></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>4.1.</unitid><unittitle>Jan-Apr 1997, with <persname>Carolyn Heilbrun,</persname> Neil Rudenstine, <persname>Renée Landers,</persname><persname>Maurine Rothschild,</persname><persname>Lucien Wulsin '66,</persname><persname>Joanne Martin,</persname><persname>Jane O'Reilly,</persname><persname>Jennifer Widner</persname></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>4.2.</unitid><unittitle>May-Dec 1997, with <persname>Jeremy Knowles</persname> in response to "Harvard Women in the University Campaign," Neil Rudenstine with <persname>Edwin J. Jacob,</persname> et al. in response to <title xlink:type="simple">New York Times </title>article about the Committee, and Neil Rudenstine with Elizabeth Hatfield and <persname>Hartly Fleischmann,</persname> re: <persname>Bonnie Honig</persname> case. Also includes <persname>Jane Mansbridge,</persname><persname>Ethan Bolker '60</persname> re: discrimination experienced as a student, and <persname>Joan Del Pozzo.</persname></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>4.3.</unitid><unittitle>1998-1999, includes <persname>Albert F. Gordon '59</persname> with Neil Rudenstine; also <persname>Jeremy Knowles,</persname><persname>Susan Pedersen,</persname><persname>Harry Lewis,</persname><persname>Harvey F. Fineberg,</persname><persname>Karen T. Romer,</persname><persname>Peggy McIntosh</persname> re: resignation from the Radcliffe College Alumnae Association, <persname>Susan Lyman,</persname> and Cornelia Dimmitt '58.</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>4.4.</unitid><unittitle>2000-2002, includes Neil Rudenstine's response to request for a study on the status of women at Harvard, and Neil Rudenstine with <persname>Ellen LaFollette;</persname> also <persname>Sharon Gagnon,</persname><persname>Drew Gilpin Faust,</persname><persname>A'Lelia Bundles,</persname><persname>Al Gordon,</persname><persname>Ann R. Shapiro</persname> to <persname>Lawrence H. Summers,</persname> and <persname>Linda S. Wilson.</persname></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>4.5.</unitid><unittitle>Correspondence with nominees for the Board of Harvard Overseers on status of women: <persname>John Baldwin, </persname><persname>Peter Bynoe,</persname><persname>Sharon Gagnon, </persname><persname>John Harrison,</persname><persname>Terrence Murray,</persname> 1995; and <persname>Robert Reischauer,</persname><persname>Sandra O. Moose,</persname><persname>Jeff Sagansky,</persname><persname>Richard Oldenburg,</persname> 1996. </unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>4.6.</unitid><unittitle>Correspondence with nominees for the Board of Harvard Overseers on status of women: <persname>Robert C. Waggoner,</persname><persname>Walter B. Hewlett,</persname><persname>Mildred S. Dresselhaus,</persname> 1997; <persname>John Rockwell,</persname><persname>Regina Montoya,</persname><persname>Mark F. Bergman,</persname><persname>Jamie S. Gorelick,</persname> 1998; and <persname>Sheila James Kuehl,</persname><persname>Karen Gordon Mills,</persname><persname>Margaret A. Hamburg,</persname><persname>Thomas E. Everhart,</persname> 1999.</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>4.7.</unitid><unittitle>Correspondence with nominees for the Board of Harvard Overseers on status of women: <persname>Lee Pelton,</persname><persname>Steven A. Schroeder,</persname><persname>Patti B. Saris,</persname><persname>Barbara Robinson,</persname> 2000; <persname>Harold H. Koh,</persname><persname>Roxane H. Gudeman,</persname><persname>Sidney R. Knafel,</persname><persname>Bruce Alberts,</persname>.<persname>Paul Buttenweiser,</persname> 2001; and <persname>Penny Pritzger,</persname><persname>William F. Lee,</persname><persname>Richard N. Zare</persname><persname>Rozlyn L. Anderson,</persname><persname>Richard I. Melvoin,</persname><persname>Frances D. Fergusson,</persname> 2000.</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>4.8.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, Feb-Mar 1999, re: on-going activities and strategizing among steering group </unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>4.9.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, Apr-Sept 1999, includes <persname>Yarden Weidenfield '89</persname> with <persname>Tasha M. Vincent '89</persname> on why to support/not to support Committee on Equality of Women at Harvard, response to the merger between Radcliffe and Harvard, and ad in <title xlink:type="simple">Harvard Magazine</title></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>4.10.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, Oct-Dec 1999, includes <persname>Margaret Geller's</persname> tenure in astronomy, report on the status of women at the <corpname>Massachusetts Institute of Technology</corpname></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>5.1.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, Jan–Feb 2000, includes concern about Radcliffe Institute's commitment to Women, Gender, and Society; <persname>Alexandra Seru</persname> and <persname>Julia Butler</persname> re: Seneca (the women's finals club at Harvard); <persname>Christiane Joost-Gaugier, </persname><persname>Cynthia Lichtenstein, </persname><persname>Mimi Thieme,</persname><persname>Pauline Kra,</persname><persname>Ann Arlen,</persname><persname>Claire Douglas,</persname> et al., re: continuing sex discrimination.</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>5.2.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, Mar-Apr 2000, includes correspondence with members of Seneca and appointment of <persname>Drew Gilpin Faust</persname> as dean of the Radcliffe Institute</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>5.3.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, May-Jun 2000, includes changes to Radcliffe College Alumnae Association, structure of Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study, joint tenured professorships at Radcliffe and Faculty of Arts and Sciences</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>5.4.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, Jul-Aug 2000, includes fundraising for Radcliffe Alumnae Professorship, name of chair, terms of gift, and Harvard presidential search</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>5.5.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, Sep-Dec 2000, includes discussion of terms of gift of Radcliffe Alumnae Professorship</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>5.6.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, Jan-Jun 2001, includes discussion of Radcliffe's fundraising strategies for Radcliffe Alumnae chair</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>5.7.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, July-Dec 2001, with Craig Smith re: publication of conference book, <title xlink:type="simple">Unequal Rites, Unequal Outcomes</title> and continuing fundraising efforts for Radcliffe Alumnae chair</unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>5.8.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, Jan-Jun 2002 includes <persname>Penny Pritzger</persname> re: <persname>President Lawrence H. Summers;</persname><persname>Jane Mansbridge</persname> and <persname>Cathy A. Trower</persname> re: faculty survey; and <persname>Katharine Park,</persname><persname>Shauna Shames,</persname><persname>Meredith Osborn,</persname> et al., in response to Harvard's changed sexual assault policy; also favorable comments on new administration at Harvard especially <persname>Dean William Kirby</persname> and <persname>Provost Steven Hyman.</persname></unittitle></did></c><c level="item"><did><unitid>5.9.</unitid><unittitle>E-mail, Jul-Dec 2002, includes comments on <title xlink:type="simple">Yards and Gates</title>, the Futures Committee of the Radcliffe Association, publication of <title xlink:type="simple">Equal Rites, Unequal Outcomes</title></unittitle></did></c></c></dsc><controlaccess><head> 
Additional catalog entries 
</head><p>The following catalog entries represent persons, organizations, and topics documented in this collection. An entry for each appears in the Harvard On Line Library Information System (HOLLIS) and other automated bibliographic databases. THIS IS NOT AN INDEX.</p><p>Authors</p><persname>Dimmitt, Cornelia, 1938-</persname><persname>Hatfield, Elisabeth</persname><persname>Hornig, Lilli S.</persname><persname>Marnin, Millie</persname><persname>O'Reilly, Jane</persname><persname>Rudenstine, Neil L.</persname><persname>Schlesinger, Gabriella P.</persname><persname>Schmertzler, Margaretta Bridgman</persname><persname>Shapiro, Ann R., 1937-</persname><persname>Tobin, Nancy</persname><persname>Welch, Alice Carbonaro</persname><corpname>Harvard University-Alumni and alumnae</corpname><corpname>Harvard University. Faculty of Arts and Sciences</corpname><corpname>Harvard University-Faculty-Selection and appointment</corpname><corpname>Harvard University--Students</corpname><corpname>Radcliffe College. Alumnae Association</corpname><corpname>Radcliffe College-Alumni and alumnae </corpname><corpname>Radcliffe College. Class of 1953</corpname><corpname>Radcliffe College. Class of 1958</corpname><corpname>Radcliffe College. Mary Ingraham Bunting Institute</corpname><corpname>Radcliffe Institute for Advanced Study</corpname><p>Subjects</p><subject>College Students-Sexual behavior</subject><subject>Rape-United States</subject><subject>Sex discrimination in higher education-United States</subject><subject>Women college students—United States</subject><subject>Women college teachers</subject><subject>Women-Education (Higher)-United States</subject><subject>Women in higher education—United States</subject><subject>Women's rights-United States</subject><geogname>Cambridge (Mass.)-Social conditions</geogname></controlaccess></archdesc></ead>
